<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Pages on Hyruo Blog</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/page/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Pages on Hyruo Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>by Hyruo, All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hyruo.com/en/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-author&#34;&gt;About the author
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;public-service-lawyer&#34;&gt;Public Service Lawyer
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After passing the national judicial examination in 2013, I became a public service lawyer in Foshan city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;law-society-cadre&#34;&gt;Law Society Cadre
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After joining the Chinese Law Society in 2016, I work part-time at the Foshan Law Society since 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;legal-advisor&#34;&gt;Legal Advisor
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2020 , I have served as a legal advisor to a government department in Foshan City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;experience&#34;&gt;Experience
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;experience-in-it-and-internet-work&#34;&gt;Experience in IT and internet work
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before engaging in legal work, I worked in several IT and internet companies, accumulating about a year of experience. I was primarily involved in tasks such as network equipment and information system maintenance, website operation and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;experience-in-judicial-work&#34;&gt;Experience in judicial work
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have three work experiences at courts: a one-month internship during their sophomore year, a three-month internship during their senior year, and an 18-month position starting before college graduation, all involving judgment execution and judicial supervision work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;experience-in-judicial-administration&#34;&gt;Experience in judicial administration
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In late 2012, I had began working at a Judicial Bureau in another city in Guangdong Province. Their primary roles included judicial administration, legal education and promotion, conflict and dispute mediation, conducted administrative reviews,handled administrative disputes,and supervising community correctional offenders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;experience-in-legal-supervision&#34;&gt;Experience in legal supervision
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In August 2014, I have began working in legal supervision.Overseeing local courts, procuratorates, public security bureaus, and judicial bureaus. The role involved ensuring these entities upheld the law and the constitution in their legal and judicial activities, prompting them to improve work reforms, efficiency, and quality to meet public expectations in the new era of the rule of law. Additionally,I had to facilitated coordination between these entities and local governments, other departments, and organizations, assisting in resolving issues that the entities could not handle independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;Services
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;legal-aid&#34;&gt;Legal Aid
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any legal issues, you can seek help from me,Including but not limited to various civil, criminal, and administrative issues. Even if I am unable to provide you with litigation representation services according to the law, I can still offer you professional legal guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;legal-research&#34;&gt;Legal Research
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you face thorny legal theoretical or practical issues, you can turn to me for help.As a legal professional, I enjoy the challenge of tackling various difficult questions. Although this research may not be authoritative, it might perhaps offer new research perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;government-affairs-guidance&#34;&gt;Government Affairs Guidance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you encounter difficulties in communicating with government departments or in handling governmental matters, you can seek assistance from me. Having worked in government for many years and been involved in various aspects of the work,I might be able to provide you with  a special solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-this-site&#34;&gt;About this Site
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This website&amp;rsquo;s content is translated from WordPress XML file to Markdown files by an automated plugin, but there are significant differences in formatting compared to WordPress. If you encounter difficulties in browsing, you can also click on the image below to access the source website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hyruo.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/about/4643828179_109de7ed3e_o.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;375&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/about/4643828179_109de7ed3e_o_hu78b5979965def093b298dcd5d36c8c9c_20235_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/about/4643828179_109de7ed3e_o_hu78b5979965def093b298dcd5d36c8c9c_20235_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;hyruo.png&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-blog-history&#34;&gt;The Blog History
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The startup period&lt;/strong&gt; began in 2008 when, at the recommendation of a friend, I moved my blog from Niuboo to the WordPress platform, thus starting my journey as an independent blogger. During this time, I mainly posted reflections on college life and learning experiences. However, due to my more left-leaning thoughts during my student days, much of it is now unreadable, so during one move, most of the content was deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The neglect period&lt;/strong&gt; started when I first entered the workforce. Due to reasons like youthful energy and the &amp;ldquo;capable ones should work more&amp;rdquo; mindset, I rarely updated my blog. I was mainly occupied with trying out different hosting services and platforms. I changed domains and hosts numerous times, and even used &amp;ldquo;Train Head&amp;rdquo; to collect many mindless articles. The number of articles increased, the database grew larger, but the content I wrote myself became less and less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The transformation period&lt;/strong&gt; began in 2014 when domestic internet regulation intensified suddenly. Faced with constant notifications of violating links from Alibaba Cloud, I found it unbearable. Many common words and phrases were deemed inappropriate, leaving me at a loss. Combined with the unstable access to Wordpress.org, I decided to migrate my blog to Typecho and make it entirely English. However, since domestic internet bandwidth was still limited at the time, and I often saw friends&amp;rsquo; domains turning &amp;ldquo;yellow,&amp;rdquo; I decided to keep the hosting on Alibaba Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The relocation period&lt;/strong&gt; was around 2016. After transitioning to an English blog, my English proficiency was still limited, so I just casually posted images and wrote a few sentences as updates, without caring about the number of visitors. After all, Google PR ranking was canceled in 2016, the mobile internet was on the rise, and few people continued to visit web pages. I considered maintaining a 1ip blog just as a keepsake, so I started experimenting with free foreign hosting spaces. To adapt to the small database limits of the free space, I deleted another batch of previous fragmented content and some irrelevant stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The reconstruction period&lt;/strong&gt; followed the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020. With more personal leisure time, and introduced by a friend, I joined the MJJ ranks and became more and more involved in blogging. At its peak, I had a bunch of various low-cost VPS. I would just randomly pick a VPS to host the blog without much management. During this period, I also tried multiple solutions like Hexo Hugo, but I ended up just tinkering with the website framework itself and neglecting writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The finalization period&lt;/strong&gt; came in 2023, when I was approaching 35 years old, an age when people in many industries start thinking about retirement. I restructured the blog, thinking that this would be the final form to play with, and I was too lazy to tinker with the website itself anymore. Currently, it&amp;rsquo;s divided into two parts: one is an English blog as the main publication platform, using my daughter&amp;rsquo;s name as the domain, hoping to bring some inspiration to her future life and learning experiences; the other in github page, using my university&amp;rsquo;s name as the domain, where I synchronize and publish some Chinese pages, sort of carrying the idea of more than 10 years of tinkering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legal&#34;&gt;LEGAL
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All textual works on this website are protected by copyright, and the authors reserve all rights. The photos used on this website, unless specifically stated, are subject to the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/?ref=chooser-v1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CC BY-NC-ND 4.0&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuration&#34;&gt;Configuration
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This website is running on Github Pages, uses the Hugo program, and employs the Stack theme. Here, I extend my gratitude to all the open-source contributors who power this with their passion!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is configured to use Cloudflare’s CDN service by default. It is normal to experience occasional slow access speeds in certain regions, including mainland China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, you can contact me by email.&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:mail@fosu.cc&#34; &gt;mail@fosu.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Links</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/links/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/links/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to exchange friendly links with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;english-links&#34;&gt;English Links
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;title: Hyruo Blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;description: A legal practitioners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;links: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hyruo.com/en/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://hyruo.com/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;image：https://hyruo.com/links/avatar.jpg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
