<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Hyruo Blog</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Hyruo Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>by Hyruo, All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hyruo.com/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The risks associated with using case-based methods in legal popularization efforts</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/the-risks-with-case-based-methods-in-legal-popularization-efforts/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/the-risks-with-case-based-methods-in-legal-popularization-efforts/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/the-risks-with-case-based-methods-in-legal-popularization-efforts/law.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The risks associated with using case-based methods in legal popularization efforts" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article only supply an Chinese Edition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to Update a Hugo Blog on an Android Phone</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/hugo.png" alt="Featured image of post How to Update a Hugo Blog on an Android Phone" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is well-known that the process of publishing a blog has always been cumbersome due to the absence of backend solutions in static blog programs like HUGO, HEXO, and Jekyll. Previously, I used various methods to update my blog, but all of them required a PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pc-method&#34;&gt;PC Method
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;vscodegithub&#34;&gt;VSCODE+Github
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My initial approach was to edit in VSCODE, generate static files in the Public directory locally using the Hugo command, and then submit them to Github Pages for direct publication. Later, I found the Hugo generation process too cumbersome, so I switched to editing and directly submitting to Github, then using Github Actions to generate blog files and publish them to Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since all images on this site are hosted on Github, and due to the well-known issues with the speed of accessing Github Pages, I eventually abandoned the Github Actions + Github Pages solution in favor of automatic deployment through Vercel or Cloudflare Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;obsidiangithub&#34;&gt;Obsidian+Github
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obsidian is an excellent note-taking software with a very large plugin library. With Obsidian + quickadd plugin + Git plugin, it&amp;rsquo;s very convenient to directly submit blog posts to Github from Obsidian. However, the issue is that Obsidian can only publish article content and cannot modify other site settings. Managing the Posts directory of Hugo directly with Obsidian feels odd, and unless a dedicated blog repository is created, there&amp;rsquo;s a constant risk of confusing note content with blog content during the management process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;joplingithub&#34;&gt;Joplin+Github
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joplin is also a very good open-source note-taking software. Although Joplin has fewer plugins, there is one that can directly publish to Github Pages, called Pages Publisher &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ylc395/joplin-plugin-pages-publisher&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pages Publisher&lt;/a&gt;. However, this plugin is used by fewer people and currently only offers a very basic blog theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, all these methods inevitably require the use of a PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mobile-method&#34;&gt;Mobile Method
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-code&#34;&gt;Github Code
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Github repositories allow for direct creation and modification of files. However, the inconvenience with this method is that direct access to Github from within China is not always reliable. The worst scenario is editing halfway through, only to have the page reset due to network issues. Github Codespaces faces the same issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/codespaces.png&#34;
	width=&#34;996&#34;
	height=&#34;526&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/codespaces_hu144d15b126d2fcb227a1c39faae435ff_128523_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/codespaces_hu144d15b126d2fcb227a1c39faae435ff_128523_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;codespaces&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;189&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;454px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stackedit&#34;&gt;StackEdit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stackedit is an excellent online Markdown editor that can be privately deployed and linked to Github repositories, with information stored in browser Cookies. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried editing simple information on my phone through Stackedit and submitting updates to Github. The main drawback of this method is that it cannot submit images, making it suitable only for situations where no images are needed or when using a third-party image library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/stackedit.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1968&#34;
	height=&#34;1092&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/stackedit_hu609bdde264d0cf5a7e75097180327694_303514_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/stackedit_hu609bdde264d0cf5a7e75097180327694_303514_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;stackedit&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;180&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;432px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having suffered significant setbacks with image libraries since 2008, and upon cleaning up my Wordpress blog in 2018, I found that nearly 500 out of 900 images on the site had been lost due to issues with external image libraries. Even self-built image libraries have left me lacking confidence. Managing them separately always feels prone to problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;weblog-app&#34;&gt;Weblog App
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Weblog is an Android app that supports managing Hugo and HEXO blogs on mobile devices. It includes built-in Hugo and Hexo environments and Git, allowing for convenient blog setup, static file generation, and webpage previews on the phone. It can easily publish to Github via Git. However, due to Hexo&amp;rsquo;s lower efficiency, it is recommended to use it with Hugo. The main issue with this solution is that it only supports creating MD files and does not allow uploading photos within the app. To upload photos, one must use the Android&amp;rsquo;s native file manager or a third-party file management tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/weblog2.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1078&#34;
	height=&#34;1004&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/weblog2_hu24148091c7a99a48fc1aa833c9e4a1b4_197990_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/weblog2_hu24148091c7a99a48fc1aa833c9e4a1b4_197990_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;weblog&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;107&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;257px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-server&#34;&gt;Code-server
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code-server is a VSCode-like program that can be deployed online, allowing for direct cloning of Github repositories to create blog files through a browser and submit them via Git. This solution essentially serves as a substitute for Github Codespaces. For use within Mainland China, it is recommended to set it up on a VPS in Japan, South Korea, Hong Kong, or Taiwan. Operating through a mobile browser is generally problem-free. Thanks to online deployment, it&amp;rsquo;s convenient to continue writing on multiple devices. The difference lies only in server performance and connection speed. This blog post was written collaboratively on an Android phone and tablet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/codeserver.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2800&#34;
	height=&#34;1660&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/codeserver_hu5fd35d24b090d4d7758a0adfc7ba69dd_951414_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/codeserver_hu5fd35d24b090d4d7758a0adfc7ba69dd_951414_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;code-server&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;168&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;404px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mgit-app&#34;&gt;Mgit App
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mgit is an Android Git application that easily pulls Github repositories to the local device, allowing for blog writing with a third-party Markdown editor. Many people use Obsidian as their blog editor and sync between their phone and computer using Mgit. The downside is that Mgit seems to have not been updated for a long time, and I encountered an issue on my Vivo X100 phone where I couldn&amp;rsquo;t edit files directly within Mgit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/weblog.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1080&#34;
	height=&#34;692&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/weblog_hu8f9c6f3f5b46204ad9783dc33f3597f7_80596_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-update-a-hugo-blog-on-an-android-phone/weblog_hu8f9c6f3f5b46204ad9783dc33f3597f7_80596_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mgit&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;156&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;374px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;termux&#34;&gt;Termux
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have not personally tried this method, but I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many recommendations for setting up a Linux environment within the Android system. However, if the sole purpose is to update a blog, this approach might be overkill.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Listening to the teachings of a university professor again after 16 years</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/university.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Listening to the teachings of a university professor again after 16 years" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;On May 13th, the Ministry of Education issued a public notice, indicating its intention to agree to the proposal by Foshan University of Science and Technology to change its name to Foshan University. This is the fifth renaming application by Foshan University of Science and Technology, and it seems that the matter has finally been settled. Initially, at the end of 2019, during the third renaming application to “Guangdong University of Science and Technology,” it seemed almost certain, as the Guangdong Provincial Department of Education had already publicized it and submitted it to the Ministry of Education for approval. However, due to the impact of the pandemic, the renaming inspection originally planned for the spring of 2020 did not proceed as scheduled, and this delay lasted for three years. By 2023, the Ministry of Education had introduced new naming rules for universities, making it almost impossible for Foshan University of Science and Technology to be approved for renaming as Guangdong University of Science and Technology. Consequently, when resubmitting the application, the school proposed the name “Foshan University,” which was actually one of the school’s previous names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/foshanuniversity.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2507&#34;
	height=&#34;1706&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/foshanuniversity_hu5438825b9b6d1014226d20d231e650c2_651580_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/foshanuniversity_hu5438825b9b6d1014226d20d231e650c2_651580_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FoshanUniversity&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;146&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;352px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-sudden-arrangement-for-a-class-reunion&#34;&gt;A sudden arrangement for a class reunion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like a stone stirring up a thousand ripples, the familiar Foshan University was finally returning, reviving the long-silent class and alumni groups. Consequently, a classmate proposed a weekend dinner gathering to celebrate this wonderful event. Due to the sudden nature of the event, only eight classmates nearby Foshan were able to attend, and one person couldn’t make it to the dinner due to a last-minute matter. However, to everyone’s surprise, what started as a joke in the class group ended up with the classmate who organized the event actually inviting the former dean of the college. This respected dean had also taught our “Jurisprudence” course during the 2007-2008 academic year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5191.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1612&#34;
	height=&#34;1208&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5191_hu052b76b500c3b9cae2fc291af821093c_1218854_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5191_hu052b76b500c3b9cae2fc291af821093c_1218854_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;listening-to-the-teacher-lecture-again&#34;&gt;Listening to the teacher lecture again
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For almost the first three hours of the dinner, it was mostly the teacher talking, or us students asking questions and the teacher answering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-teacher-himself&#34;&gt;About the teacher himself
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher started with his experiences of traveling abroad after retiring in January this year and talked about his personal journey from starting to teach at Foshan University in 1992, through its renaming to Foshan University of Science and Technology, and the multiple attempts to revert to a university status. Especially after 2017, he shared his own health challenges and how, as a scholar, he conducted interdisciplinary research on his condition, overcame it, and took care of his health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1744&#34;
	height=&#34;892&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;195&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;469px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-childrens-education&#34;&gt;About children’s education
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the dinner, the teacher spent a long time talking about his own experiences and those of other teachers at the college in educating their children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;he-emphasized-the-current-importance-of-the-high-school-entrance-exam-zhongkao&#34;&gt;He emphasized the current importance of the high school entrance exam (Zhongkao)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which he believes is now more significant than the college entrance exam (Gaokao). Since the late 1970s, the Gaokao has been considered the most important exam in China, with countless people relying on it to change their destinies. However, in recent years, due to the saturation of college enrollment, the university admission rate has approached 90%, and for most students attending ordinary high schools, even if they “lie flat,” they basically have no worries about not being able to attend university. Overall, the importance of the Gaokao is decreasing. But at the same time, due to the “general vocational分流” policy, during the process of entering high school, more than 55% of junior high school students in many places can only attend secondary vocational technical schools after graduation, and it is basically impossible for these schools to progress to ordinary universities. In this situation, if a child’s academic performance is not ideal in primary and junior high school, they may lose the opportunity to attend an ordinary university and can only take the vocational technical university route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;he-talked-about-his-methods-of-educating-his-children&#34;&gt;He talked about his methods of educating his children
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both he and his wife are highly educated, but they also faced difficulties in educating their children. He summed it up with the phrase &lt;strong&gt;“parents are not good at teaching their children (academics).”&lt;/strong&gt; Parents can still play a decisive role in their children’s growth in life and other aspects, but their role in learning is very limited. He emphasized the importance of teachers and schools in improving children’s academic performance and cited a series of examples from his surroundings. He hoped that we would create a relaxed family atmosphere for our children, send them to the best schools within our means, and handle relationships with teachers well. He advised that we should mainly rely on schools and classrooms to enhance our children’s learning ability, rather than relying on family or off-campus tutoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;he-discussed-the-issue-of-childrens-educational-planning&#34;&gt;He discussed the issue of children’s educational planning.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a law major himself and with his wife studying medicine, he pointed out that fields like law, especially medicine, and computer science are highly competitive and require continuous learning and updating of knowledge to keep up with the times. Even in computer science, it’s quite possible to be unable to compete with younger people in their thirties and forties due to the physical and familial demands that come with age, making it easy to fall behind in the race for new technology. He stressed the importance of guiding children to develop hobbies and interests based on their personalities and interests, rather than just following trends. The teacher has only one daughter, who is almost our age. After graduating with a bachelor’s degree from a top art academy in China, she pursued a master’s degree at a well-ranked university in the United States, and later, a Ph.D. After completing her doctorate, she became a teacher at a domestic art academy and quickly grew to become one of the youngest professors there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1001914.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;2250&#34;
	height=&#34;1500&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1001914_hua8053f0bd34c4ab00b1b9d33025e98fd_197404_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1001914_hua8053f0bd34c4ab00b1b9d33025e98fd_197404_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Education&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-development-of-the-university&#34;&gt;About the development of the university
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As one of the earliest faculty members with a doctoral degree in law at our alma mater, the teacher has long served as the university’s legal advisor and is aware of many secrets behind the school’s development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-development-of-a-university-is-inseparable-from-the-help-of-influential-people&#34;&gt;The development of a university is inseparable from the help of influential people.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the course of the development of Foshan University and later Foshan University of Science and Technology, the support of key figures was indispensable. In the early stages, two mayors of Foshan City, Yu Fei and Lu Ruihua, played significant roles. Without the attention and support of these two mayors, Foshan University would not have been established in 1986. &lt;em&gt;(Yu Fei: Served as the Vice-Governor of Guangdong Province but was expelled from the Communist Party in 1998 due to his children’s seeking private interests; Lu Ruihua: Served as the Governor of Guangdong Province. )&lt;/em&gt;
In the last 10 years, Foshan University of Science and Technology has skyrocketed from outside the top 500 national university rankings to 219th nationwide, thanks in large part to the assistance of the former Secretary of the Guangdong Provincial Party Committee, Hu Chunhua. As a member of the Central Political Bureau, Hu Chunhua visited the school three times after 2015, proposed the goal of building Foshan University of Science and Technology into a high-level science and technology university in Guangdong, and the Guangdong provincial government allocated 500 million yuan specifically for support. Since then, the school’s development has entered the fast lane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5194.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2106&#34;
	height=&#34;842&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5194_hueda0fd19d53824080503c29a507fa0d3_139141_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5194_hueda0fd19d53824080503c29a507fa0d3_139141_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;250&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;600px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-development-of-a-university-cannot-be-separated-from-government-support&#34;&gt;The development of a university cannot be separated from government support.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since public universities dominate in China, the development of universities is driven by administrative resources, and the richness of these resources determines the height of university development. Decisive factors include the level of education and the allocation of funds, both of which are decided by administrative organs. As a university founded by the Foshan municipal government, Foshan University has inherent shortcomings because, compared to the financial strength of national or provincial governments, a prefecture-level city like Foshan falls far short. Moreover, although Foshan’s economic output ranks among the top 20 in the country, as an ordinary prefecture-level city in the Pearl River Delta, under the three-tier fiscal structure (about 50% of income goes to the central government, and of the remaining 50% tax, another 50% goes to the province, leaving about 25% actually retained), the financial resources that the Foshan municipal government can dispose of are far less than those of first-tier cities like Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou, and Shenzhen, as well as other sub-provincial cities and general provincial capitals. For example, the fiscal budget expenditure for Foshan University of Science and Technology in 2024 is 1.8 billion yuan, while the fiscal budget expenditure for the Foshan municipal government during the same period is 24 billion yuan, accounting for 7.5% of the total. Nearby universities such as Shenzhen University and Southern University of Science and Technology have fiscal expenditures of over 6 billion yuan, which is an amount that the Foshan city government, with a fiscal budget of 24 billion at the city level, cannot afford. Fortunately, Foshan University of Science and Technology is currently not large in scale, and if calculated by the per-student expenditure on funds, it ranks among the top in Guangdong’s higher education institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-development-of-a-university-needs-to-go-with-the-flow&#34;&gt;The development of a university needs to go with the flow.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In discussing the school’s development, the teacher specifically mentioned the construction of doctoral programs, which is one of the two biggest projects the school has undertaken in recent years, the other being the “renaming to a university” project. Currently, there are about 400 universities in China with doctoral programs. Although Foshan University of Science and Technology has seen its ranking climb continuously, the lack of a doctoral program has always been a major concern, and this has even led to the university’s president position being vacant for three years. The main reason is that the Foshan municipal government hopes to find an expert at the “Academician” level to serve as the president, and it is almost impossible to find an Academician willing to be the president of a school without a doctoral program. In this round of applying for a doctoral program, the school has put in a great deal of effort, especially the party committee secretary who has used all his skills to advance the discipline construction, focusing on mechanical engineering, a field he is highly proficient in. As of now, the application for a doctoral program has reached the most critical stage. In the list of Guangdong universities applying for doctoral program construction published by the Guangdong Provincial Department of Education, Foshan University of Science and Technology’s mechanical engineering doctoral program ranked first among 234 disciplines in 32 universities across the province, and veterinary and animal husbandry programs also ranked among the top five. It can be said that this is the closest the school has been to securing a doctoral program since it became a doctoral degree-granting institution in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5195.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1888&#34;
	height=&#34;732&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5195_hu935cfa788b6b52a3c4d88f8d40a84db9_345000_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5195_hu935cfa788b6b52a3c4d88f8d40a84db9_345000_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;257&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;619px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-personal-growth&#34;&gt;About personal growth
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With his 32 years of work experience, the teacher shared several key aspects that we should focus on during our professional development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;avoid-speaking-ill-of-others-when-they-are-not-present&#34;&gt;Avoid speaking ill of others when they are not present.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher emphasized that Chinese society is heavily influenced by personal relationships, and we should never speak ill of others, regardless of how much we may dislike them or have had conflicts with them. Even a decade ago, we might not have fully appreciated the importance of this advice, but today, we deeply agree with it. Numerous examples around us confirm this point. However, as human beings, we have our limitations, and sometimes we inadvertently express our true feelings, leading to unforeseen consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dont-be-too-rigid&#34;&gt;Don’t be too rigid.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher cited several examples from his own experience, advising us to be flexible in handling work relationships and not to be overly pedantic or inflexible. Wearing the necessary masks and disguises is essential for self-protection, which is the foundation of growth. Throughout our development, we will encounter various setbacks and unavoidable conflicts of interest, but we should still approach them with a relaxed and optimistic attitude. Harmonious workplace relationships are crucial for our own well-being. We should not view potential competitors as adversaries but rather as companions, as work is only an eight-hour-a-day matter, while life is a lifelong journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;learn-to-be-content-and-embrace-ordinariness&#34;&gt;Learn to be content and embrace ordinariness.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher used examples of students and leaders he has helped and supported over the years to advise us that as we enter middle age, we should start to learn satisfaction and contentment, and not overly concern ourselves with personal gains and losses. After all, as we reach middle age, the harmony of the family, the growth of our children, and our health are often more important than personal advancement. Especially within the system, the time most people can shine in their careers typically does not exceed 15 years. In the marathon of life, there can still be two to three decades after retirement. Even if some have held high positions and had power for a time, facing decades of retirement, if there are problems with the family, children, or their own health, it would all have been in vain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1744&#34;
	height=&#34;892&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;195&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;469px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-legal-work-in-law&#34;&gt;About legal work in law
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a senior law professor, the teacher offered some sound advice and suggestions for the work and development of several of us students based on his own experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-judicial-work&#34;&gt;Regarding judicial work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Including myself, two of us present have worked in judicial authorities. Drawing on his long-term experience serving part-time in the National People’s Congress, the teacher offered two suggestions for those of us engaged in judicial work: First, the current workload in judicial authorities is generally high, with many cases and few people, a situation that is expected to persist for a long time, and the reward may not be proportional to the effort. For women, especially, who often have to invest more in family and childcare, choosing a career in the judiciary requires careful consideration. Second, within the judiciary, there is a significant level of internal competition, with a concentration of highly educated individuals, complex factions, and young and female leaders often having higher aspirations. It is important to know one’s limits, avoid confrontation, and advance steadily with modesty and caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-arbitration-work&#34;&gt;Regarding arbitration work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the students present works in an arbitration institution. Based on his experience as an arbitrator, the teacher advised that students working in arbitration institutions should strengthen communication with law firms, businesses, and other industry organizations, improve communication skills, and develop a network of contacts. Outside of work, they should continuously study relevant trade laws, international trade management, and arbitration rules to maintain advanced and in-depth professional knowledge. However, he suggested that it might not be necessary to pursue a doctoral degree, as we have all been working for over a decade and have missed the optimal time to advance our careers with a doctoral degree. Moreover, at our age, with the pressures of work and life, the benefits of obtaining a PhD may not be significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-notary-work&#34;&gt;Regarding notary work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two students present work in notary institutions. The teacher, based on his experience, put forward several points: First, the notary industry is relatively closed, with a smaller number of notaries among legal professions, and the overall development space is narrow. Second, in recent years, the notary industry has been continuously promoting restructuring, with some notary institutions transitioning from traditional public institutions to social welfare organizations similar to law firms. In this process, the personal networks and channels established become extremely important, as work income will be directly related to the volume of business. Third, the notary industry is closely related to the legal profession, and it is important to pay attention to interactions with lawyers, guiding clients to resolve many common disputes through notarization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/notary.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1200&#34;
	height=&#34;800&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/notary_hu7d6fd75e6699370713a188194a904a94_107780_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/notary_hu7d6fd75e6699370713a188194a904a94_107780_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Notary&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-lawyer-practice&#34;&gt;Regarding lawyer practice.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;One student is a practicing lawyer, and the teacher himself has also served as a part-time lawyer, and I also work part-time as a public service lawyer. Because of concerns that continuing to practice law after retirement might affect retirement benefits, the teacher canceled his part-time lawyer’s license upon retirement and did not apply to convert it to a general lawyer’s practice certificate. The teacher offered several suggestions for legal practice, including the importance of maintaining client relationships, how to expand one’s network and case sources, and the need for lifelong learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-corporate-work&#34;&gt;Regarding corporate work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two students work in central enterprises and large private enterprises in the IT and internet industry. As they are both female and have personal or family health issues, the teacher suggested that they should pay attention to their own and their family’s health while maintaining a positive attitude towards life and a proactive learning mindset. They should keep abreast of industry trends and maintain their level of expertise in law, seeking development opportunities through their comparative advantages in non-legal work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-work-within-the-system&#34;&gt;Regarding work within the system.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Including myself, out of the 7 students present, 5 of us are effectively working in “governmental, institutional, and enterprise units” within the system. The teacher offered a lot of opinions and suggestions on working within the system, also sharing many of his observations from working in the local system in Foshan. As some of the content is sensitive, it has not been written out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5192.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1612&#34;
	height=&#34;1208&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5192_hu82f2d5ee5588d27505d5c94102ba66cc_1060195_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5192_hu82f2d5ee5588d27505d5c94102ba66cc_1060195_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This gathering was indeed a rare opportunity. We arrived at 4 pm in the afternoon, and while waiting for the teacher and other classmates to arrive, we played the card game “Guan Dang” (Gentlemen’s Agreement) as we chatted, with one of our classmates working at a central enterprise saying, “It’s like not eating at all if you don’t play ‘Guan Dang’.” During the meal, we listened to the teacher “lecture” almost throughout, and the teacher even specifically commented on the phenomenon of “Guan Dang.” After the teacher left early due to time constraints, we chatted informally until almost 11 pm before dispersing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-is-no-template-for-choosing-the-path-of-life&#34;&gt;There is no template for choosing the path of life
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The eight classmates who attended the reunion had all graduated from the same class but later embarked on completely different paths in life. If we extend this group to the entire class of over 40 students, their paths become even more diverse and complex. In general, however, we all stood at the same starting point at the same time, seeking different lives. The vast differences that followed may have been more related to each family’s and personal choices. Even among those who pursued the same profession, different classmates took different paths. For example, in our class, four students became ordinary lawyers, one of whom has been practicing law in Foshan for 13 years and has had a smooth career development; another student who did not attend the dinner began practicing law only 10 years after graduation and is still in the early stages; one student who practices law in Shenzhen opened their own law firm early on and has recently opened branches in other places; and another student who practices law in Chengdu pursued a master’s degree after graduation and initially chose to practice in Shenzhen before moving to Chengdu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-advantage-brought-by-information-gaps-is-gradually-decreasing&#34;&gt;The advantage brought by information gaps is gradually decreasing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we graduated, information gaps were still a significant factor contributing to differences in life paths. Back then, in our class of over 40 students, only a few chose to take the civil service exam or participate in campus recruitment by enterprises and institutions, and only a few decided to become lawyers. It was only after entering the workforce that more people gradually realized the importance of their undergraduate degree in law. Including myself, many of us entered judicial and administrative organs through the civil service exam in the following years. It was not until 2017, when short video platforms began to thrive, that the advantages of employment in systems such as government agencies and state-owned enterprises were fully exposed, and this was only gradually recognized by the public. At this point, the difficulty of entering these professions compared to when we graduated from university had become unimaginable. For example, when I applied for a civil service position in the Pearl River Delta, there were only 13 applicants for the same position, with only 8 actually taking the exam. With no preparation at all, I even didn’t complete a complete practice test, and yet I managed to score 110 points (out of a total of 200 for two subjects) to become the first-ranked candidate, and was successfully employed. Every time I think back, I feel extremely lucky, with more luck than actual ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-are-no-shortcuts-in-the-marathon-of-life&#34;&gt;There are no shortcuts in the marathon of life
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher used his rich personal experiences and insights to illustrate how individuals navigate this era. In the 1980s, when university students were still a “rare species,” the teacher, with his strong character and self-discipline, successfully enrolled in university and pursued a master’s degree. He then went south to Foshan University to pioneer, gradually advancing from lecturer to associate professor and then to professor, and serving as the dean of the college. Along the way, he pursued a doctoral degree and engaged in postdoctoral research at top universities in the industry, providing himself and his family with ample material and spiritual wealth. In the second century of struggle, in this era widely considered highly competitive, I believe that this era still offers opportunities for many to change their destinies. However, success can only be achieved through even greater effort, a more positive attitude, and unwavering perseverance. After all, the negative emotions of this era are already enough, with voices of “lying flat” and “tittytainment” products ubiquitous. Only by adhering to one’s original aspiration can one live up to oneself, one’s family, and this era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1164572.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2250&#34;
	height=&#34;1500&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1164572_hu004c9b28559f5fa727659b387248f524_688245_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1164572_hu004c9b28559f5fa727659b387248f524_688245_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Visit a highschool female classmate</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin1.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Visit a highschool female classmate" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last night, at the invitation of a high school female classmate, my wife and I visited her company. The main purpose was to taste the cured meat, local eggs, and other delicacies she brought from her hometown. During the meal, we also took the opportunity to tour the company. Although I often visit companies in my work, most of the time it&amp;rsquo;s for serious business activities. Even when there are dining and touring components, they tend to be quite restrained, rarely allowing for a relaxed mindset like this visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a company engaged in the trade of stainless steel products, backed by Hongwang Holding Group Co., Ltd., one of the top 500 Chinese enterprises. It is a typical family-owned business. My classmate is the general manager of one of the trading companies under this enterprise, mainly responsible for domestic sales. In addition, the company&amp;rsquo;s stainless steel products, such as furniture and decorative building materials made of stainless steel materials, are also sold to countries like Japan, South Korea, and Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin5.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1636&#34;
	height=&#34;920&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin5_hub919c6f26601da0acf699e30dd4ec188_406937_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin5_hub919c6f26601da0acf699e30dd4ec188_406937_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hongwang-holding-group&#34;&gt;Hongwang Holding Group
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had heard of the Hongwang Group&amp;rsquo;s reputation many years ago. It is a successful example of Hunanese people going south to Guangdong for work and entrepreneurship after the reform and opening-up. The founder hails from Shuangfeng County, my hometown. In addition to establishing roots in Guangdong, the company has also given back to its hometown by investing in the construction of a large-scale manufacturing enterprise in the Shuangfeng County Development Zone, solving the local employment issues for many Shuangfeng residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a corporate group specializing in the production of cold-rolled stainless steel, silicon steel, and supporting fine processing products, Hongwang Group ranks 459th among the 2023 China Top 500 Enterprises and 241st among the China Top 500 Manufacturing Enterprises. It enjoys a good reputation in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meiling.png&#34;
	width=&#34;942&#34;
	height=&#34;695&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meiling_huc6fa779a5d79da6a42b887a053e7c386_751022_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meiling_huc6fa779a5d79da6a42b887a053e7c386_751022_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;135&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;325px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mellow-group&#34;&gt;Mellow Group
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This company is located on the top floor of the Foshan New City Xinbao Building, occupying two floors of office space. During the company tour, the clean, tidy, and modern atmosphere left a deep impression on me. Especially the small garden built on the rooftop of a high-rise office building, which indeed had a unique charm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin4.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1636&#34;
	height=&#34;920&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin4_hub970e22b605a2f8651b7adaff798151e_568943_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin4_hub970e22b605a2f8651b7adaff798151e_568943_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, in our conversation, I learned that although the company appears to lean towards a modern management model in many aspects, it still retains the humanized characteristics of traditional manufacturing enterprises. For example, the company provides free accommodation and meal subsidies for all employees, and the boss has specially purchased dozens of fully furnished apartments for employees to live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin7.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1287&#34;
	height=&#34;870&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin7_hu64c21e0e6f0505edfb89e971eb6047a7_1038332_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin7_hu64c21e0e6f0505edfb89e971eb6047a7_1038332_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;147&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;355px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;classmate&#34;&gt;Classmate
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This classmate is someone my wife and I both knew from high school, in the same class. Although she was a girl, during our school days, she exuded an extraordinary aura that commanded the scene, with a cheerful and outgoing personality. Her only shortcoming was her slightly weaker academic performance. After graduation, although we all worked in the same city, we only had sporadic contact with her twice. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until this visit to her company that we gained a deeper understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin3.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1612&#34;
	height=&#34;904&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin3_hu6d404f4b4399fd2bec863d4bbcbb7767_598323_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin3_hu6d404f4b4399fd2bec863d4bbcbb7767_598323_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;427px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;industry-contrast&#34;&gt;Industry Contrast
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the stainless steel and metal materials industry, most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t associate it with women. Yet, this female classmate of mine happens to be in such an industry and has even become a well-known figure in the Foshan stainless steel market, which is quite impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;position-contrast&#34;&gt;Position Contrast
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last time I met this classmate at a reunion years ago, she was still an ordinary salesperson. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until this visit that I learned she had grown into a general manager managing several companies years ago, which was quite shocking to me. Most of our other classmates from the same class are still in ordinary staff positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gender-contrast&#34;&gt;Gender Contrast
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to when we were in the same classroom, this female classmate was just a naive little girl. In just over a decade, she has grown into a powerful elite in the workplace. Balancing family and children while handling the complex affairs of the company and achieving rapid promotion is indeed no easy feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/class.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3284&#34;
	height=&#34;1600&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/class_hu76eda07030458ed05572fba6005da0c3_1518683_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/class_hu76eda07030458ed05572fba6005da0c3_1518683_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;205&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;492px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A Common Misconception about Chinese Village Structure That I Held for Thirty Years</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/20240506152638.png" alt="Featured image of post A Common Misconception about Chinese Village Structure That I Held for Thirty Years" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The ‘One Village One Surname’ phenomenon is prevalent in the majority of Chinese villages. However, due to my familiarity primarily with the regions of Hunan and Guangdong where I have lived, I mistakenly believed until the age of 35 that only traditional Han border areas such as Guangdong and Fujian retained this pattern of population distribution. It was only during recent discussions with colleagues and other friends from Hunan that I realized I had been laboring under a significant misunderstanding about this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-village-one-surname-system&#34;&gt;One Village One Surname System 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In rural China, many villages are characterized by the presence of only one surname, a situation closely tied to China’s ancient clan system and traditional cultural practices of communal living by clans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clan System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Agriculture-based ancient Chinese society saw families and clans playing a pivotal role in the social structure. The clan system emphasized the importance of blood ties, with people of the same surname typically believed to share a common ancestor. Consequently, they lived together, jointly upholding familial honor and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Land System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In feudal times, land was a crucial communal asset of the family. Members of the same surname worked the land together, fostering close economic cooperation. This economic collaboration also led to their residential aggregation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marriage Customs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Traditionally, intermarriage between men and women of the same village was discouraged, leading to the concentration of surnames within villages. Marriages often took place between individuals from different villages, further reinforcing the One Village One Surname phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Stability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Residential proximity of members of the same clan helped form a stable social structure. In ancient times, such structures were beneficial for withstanding external threats and facilitated effective social management and order maintenance within the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural and Religious Activities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 The clan system also involved the worship of common ancestors, with clan members participating in rituals together. These activities deepened the bonds among members and fostered the One Village One Surname residential pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Historical Migrations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Throughout history, due to war, disasters, and other causes, some clans migrated collectively to new areas. They often established villages there, naming them after their family surname, thereby creating the One Village One Surname layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;causes-of-the-misconception&#34;&gt;Causes of the Misconception
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factor of Birthplace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The reason why I held this misconception for 35 years, failing to recognize the common situation in rural China, is mainly related to my birthplace. I was born in a remote mountainous area in central Hunan, where within a few hundred meters of my home, according to the organizational structure of Chinese villages, belonged to the same village group. This village group had about 20 families, totaling around 70 people. However, these 20 families had 8 different surnames, with the most populous surname represented by only a few families. These surnames include Zeng, Peng, Qin, Zhou, He, Xie, Yu, and Wang, among others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/xianee.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1933&#34;
	height=&#34;1045&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/xianee_hue3428b0466b4b83d5c6c0ab494d12e2c_470106_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/xianee_hue3428b0466b4b83d5c6c0ab494d12e2c_470106_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;184&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;443px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Situation in Hometown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If the map is expanded to cover our entire village, about 2 square kilometers (approximately 600 people), the distribution of surnames is even more extensive. Even though I have been away from my hometown for nearly 18 years, I still remember many family surnames in the village. In addition to the 8 surnames mentioned above, there were at least the following surnames in our village: Sun, Hu, Jiang, Song, Ge, Qu, Chen, Xiong, Liao, Liu, Li, Long, Zhu, Su, Lei, Zuo, and Chen, among others. If one were to consult the household registration records, there should actually be more than 30 surnames.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/xintian.png&#34;
	width=&#34;2572&#34;
	height=&#34;775&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/xintian_hucaa0ac3b3958a976bdb6d35661db394c_5003182_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/xintian_hucaa0ac3b3958a976bdb6d35661db394c_5003182_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;331&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;796px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Historical Reasons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
According to my family genealogy, our He ancestors migrated from Taihe County, Jiangxi, to Xiangxiang County, Hunan, in 924 AD, and then spread out in Hunan, forming the largest settlement area of the He surname in all of China. According to the 2021 China Name Report released by the Public Security Ministry’s Household Registration Management Research Center, Hunan has become the province with the largest distribution of the He surname, accounting for about 15.3% of the total He population in China. Since I have lived in Hunan and Guangdong for a long time, it was natural for me to compare the two and assume that the history of surname formation in Hunan, like that of our He surname, spanned over a thousand years, while most village families in Guangdong were formed by immigrants in the mid to late 15th century during the Ming Dynasty. This naturally led to a situation where one area had villages with mixed surnames, while the other had villages with uniform surnames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Reasons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 In general public opinion and media impression, Guangdong and Fujian are considered to be the places where the “clan power” is most preserved in China. When it comes to the “clan” issue, I immediately think of the “One Village One Surname” phenomenon and believe that the strong clan atmosphere in Guangdong and Fujian is caused by this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-truman-show&#34;&gt;The Truman Show
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Show It was only after learning from many friends from Hunan and other provinces that I realized the “One Village One Surname” phenomenon is indeed the reality in most rural areas across China, including in Hunan. This came as a surprise, giving me a sense of “I was the clown all along.” If “One Village One Surname” is the norm, then my hometown seems to be an exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Administrative Division Issue&lt;/strong&gt;: I was born in Shuangfeng County, Hunan, but this county is relatively new, established only in 1953, with a history of just 70 years. For nearly 2,000 years, from 3 BC to 1953, Shuangfeng County was part of Xiangxiang County. I have consulted the “Annals of Shuangfeng County” multiple times but never found any content indicating a special situation regarding surname distribution. It was only when comparing the “Annals of Shuangfeng County” with the sections on surnames in the “Annals of Nanhai County,” “Annals of Zhongshan County,” and “Annals of Panyu County” in Guangdong that I discovered Shuangfeng County indeed has significantly more surnames than these counties in Guangdong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analysis-of-causes&#34;&gt;Analysis of Causes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After confirming the uniqueness of surname distribution in my hometown, I was initially skeptical of this conclusion. Shuangfeng is an ordinary county in Hunan, geographically located in the central part of the province, and there is nothing special about it among the more than 100 county-level administrative regions in Hunan. The only thing that struck me as different is that Shuangfeng was the birthplace of the most important historical figure in modern Hunan history: Zeng Guofan. Therefore, in researching this issue, I focused most of my efforts on matters related to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, since Zeng Guofan’s residence is less than two kilometers from my home, I grew up listening to stories about him. When the clues pointed to something related to him, I already guessed the conclusion: the aftermath of war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/pdyft-1024x600.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;600&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/pdyft-1024x600_hub6403425d9adfa717d920fb323d070f3_231751_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/pdyft-1024x600_hub6403425d9adfa717d920fb323d070f3_231751_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;170&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;409px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Qing Government’s Local Disbandment Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After the Opium War broke out, Western powers successively invaded China. To counter imperialism, the Qing government organized a large number of soldiers in Hunan to participate in the war. However, after the Opium War ended, as the conflict subsided, the Qing government adopted a policy of disbanding locally the soldiers recruited from southern provinces, including Hunan, leading to a large number of demobilized soldiers and deserters scattering far from their homes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Taiping Rebellion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In June 1852, the Taiping Army entered Hunan from Guangxi, under the banner of Christianity, calling on the poor and oppressed to join the Taiping forces and share in the peace of the realm. Many people from Hunan joined the Taiping Army. Within less than a year, the Taiping Army entered and left Hunan four times, affecting more than 60 counties. Starting with less than 10,000 troops when they first entered Hunan, they had grown to a 150,000-strong army by the time they left. Most of the Hunanese who joined the Taiping Army, except for those who defected to the Xiang Army, met with a doomed fate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After the Taiping Army entered Hunan, it inflicted devastating damage on the clan system in the province&lt;/strong&gt; (from “A Study of Hunan’s Clan System in Modern Times” by Tan Jianguo)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They opposed the worship of ancestors, demanding that people believe in the only true God, the “Heavenly Father,” and recklessly burned and destroyed ancestral halls and the spirit tablets of ancestors. As Zeng Guofan said, wherever the Taiping Army went, “no temple was left unburned, no image untouched.” For instance, after Jiahe County was captured by the Taiping Army, “the city was left in ruins, and the school, examination pavilions, and village ancestral halls, as well as nunneries, were all destroyed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They severely cracked down on and suppressed clan militias that opposed the Taiping Army. Many clans in Hunan organized militias and built fortifications to protect themselves and resist the Taiping Army after it entered the province. Some clans even led their members to encircle and annihilate the Taiping Army. Numerous clan militias suffered heavy casualties in battles with the Taiping Army, severely damaging their vitality, and some were even completely wiped out. For example, the landlord Cao Kuilong led his able-bodied clansmen to annihilate the Taiping Army but was subsequently destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clan members were either abducted, brutally killed, or forced to flee and scatter. Records of such events can be found frequently in local chronicles. For instance, in Jiahe County, “over a hundred members from two clans were abducted, and thousands were abducted in the entire county. Although some have gradually returned, a quarter of them have not.” After Dong’an City fell, the Taiping Army “slaughtered over a thousand men and women in the city.” In Chenzhou, the Taiping Army “occupied the area, massacring mercilessly. Many abducted residents did not return, and entire villages were reduced to ashes, with nearly every household deserted.” As such, the clan system and clan power suffered a severe blow in this tumultuous revolutionary movement, beginning their decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establishment of the Xiang Army&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Zeng Guofan was born in Xingle Township, Hetang, Xiangxiang County, Changsha Prefecture, Hunan, which is now part of Shuangfeng County’s Heye Town. In the process of establishing the Xiang Army, he recruited a large number of locals as soldiers. For example, when setting up the Xiang Army’s naval force, Zeng Guofan required that “the sailors must number four thousand, all from Xiangxiang County, without the use of soldiers from other counties.” His brother, Zeng Guoquan, recruited people exclusively from Xiangxiang County, and even more specifically, from the area within ten miles of their home. From 1853 to 1869, nearly 100,000 people from Xiangxiang County joined the Xiang Army, with the number of officers reaching 7,886. Given that the entire population of Xiangxiang County was less than 500,000 at the time, almost every household had members who enlisted, and Heye Town, where my family is from (then part of Xiangxiang County’s Hetang 24th District), had the highest enlistment rate in the county. For instance, four out of Zeng Guofan’s five brothers joined the military.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the “Xiangxiang County Annals” of the Tongzhi era, from the third year of the Xianfeng reign to the eighth year of the Tongzhi reign (1853–1869), there were a total of 7,886 generals from Xiangxiang County. These generals were divided into two categories: civil officials with military achievements, including governors, lieutenant governors, provincial administrators, provincial inspectors, circuit intendants, prefects, salt commissioners, directors of medical services, associate prefects, prefects, associate magistrates, magistrates, and assistant magistrates, totaling 358 people; and military officials with military achievements, including military governors, commanding generals, lieutenant generals, colonels, brigadiers, regimental commanders, battalion commanders, company commanders, and platoon leaders, totaling 7,528 people. Among them, there were 8 governors and lieutenant governors, 39 provincial administrators, inspectors, and circuit intendants, 283 prefects, magistrates, and assistant magistrates, 183 military governors, 417 commanding generals, and 1,132 lieutenant generals and colonels. The Tongzhi annals also recorded 21,335 volunteer soldiers who died in battle or from illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/1_20220205200534a4423-1024x722.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;722&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/1_20220205200534a4423-1024x722_hu13b72b109c4c8fefad2a8cdc127651ee_256739_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/1_20220205200534a4423-1024x722_hu13b72b109c4c8fefad2a8cdc127651ee_256739_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;141&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;340px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conquest of Eighteen Provinces&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As the most legendary traditional army in modern Chinese history, the Xiang Army played a pivotal role in the development of Chinese history, with half of modern Chinese history having some connection to the Xiang Army, especially for Hunan. The emergence of the Xiang Army brought Hunan, a place that had been obscure for thousands of years, to the forefront, creating countless heroic stories. For example, Mao Zedong’s father joined the Xiang Army founded by Zeng Guofan. &lt;br&gt;
In the second half of the 19th century, the mark of the Xiang Army was left across China, with Xiangxiang County even boasting the achievement of “one county’s soldiers conquering eighteen provinces.” It was during the years of continuous warfare that my hometown began to see a large number of empty-nest families, inevitably leading to increased internal migration to fill the population gap caused by war. Additionally, some soldiers and officers of the Xiang Army who followed Zeng Guofan’s brothers settled here, further complicating the local distribution of surnames.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quelling the Taiping Rebellion&lt;/strong&gt;: In 1852, to resist the Taiping Rebellion, Zeng Guofan began to organize the Xiang Army. Over the course of 12 years until the rebellion was quelled in 1864, the Xiang Army mostly suffered defeats and was known as “frequently defeated in battle, yet repeatedly returning to fight.” Countless Xiang Army soldiers died or were wounded during this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quelling the Nian Rebellion&lt;/strong&gt; ：After the failure of the Taiping Rebellion, some of the Xiang Army was disbanded and returned to their hometowns, but a portion continued to serve. For instance, in 1867 (the sixth year of the Tongzhi reign), the Xiang Army suffered a surprise attack by the Nian Army in Qishui County, Hubei, resulting in the death of 5,281 soldiers, including the maternal grandfather of Cai Hesen (one of the founders of the Communist Party of China).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lüqiao Incident&lt;/strong&gt;：In 1874 (the 13th year of the Tongzhi reign), a Ryukyu fishing boat was stranded in Taiwan due to a typhoon and conflicts arose with the local Gaoshan people, resulting in the death of 54 Ryukyu fishermen. Japan used this incident as a pretext to send 3,000 soldiers to invade southern Taiwan in May 1874, starting the Japanese invasion of Taiwan. The Xiang Army was ordered to station in Xiamen, ultimately forcing Japan to withdraw from Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reconquest of Xinjiang&lt;/strong&gt;：In 1876 (the second year of the Guangxu reign), Xiang Army generals Zuo Zongtang and Liu Jintang led troops into Xinjiang, successfully reclaiming the region by January 2, 1878 (the third year of the Guangxu reign). With the Xiang Army as a backdrop, Zeng Guofan’s son, Zeng Jize, successfully negotiated the “Ili Treaty” with Tsarist Russia in 1881 (the seventh year of the Guangxu reign), successfully recovering Ili from Russian control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Battle of Tamsui&lt;/strong&gt; ：In October 1884 (the 10th year of the Qing Guangxu reign), during the Sino-French War, the Xiang Army resisted French invasion at Tamsui (now part of New Taipei City), achieving a significant victory for the Qing army in the later stages of the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Victory at Zhennan Pass&lt;/strong&gt;：In November 1883, with the Yuenan-French situation critical, to strengthen the defense of the Guangxi border, Zuo Zongtang recommended the Xiang Army general Wang Debang to be stationed at the border. Wang Debang recruited Xiang Army soldiers in Hunan to assist Feng Zicai in the Battle of Zhennan Pass, where they defeated the French invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Battle of Niuzhuang&lt;/strong&gt;： In 1894, the First Sino-Japanese War broke out. The Huai Army, led by Li Hongzhang, suffered successive defeats from the Battle of Pyongyang, leading to a catastrophic retreat. After experiencing the campaigns against the Taiping, the Nian, as well as the pacification of Xinjiang, the Xiang Army, once again, was brought to the forefront. In the Battle of Niuzhuang, 1,880 Xiang Army soldiers heroically sacrificed themselves, writing the final chapter of the Xiang Army’s history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/20240506152638.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1000&#34;
	height=&#34;750&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/20240506152638_hude6d581674c58540088d774479e67e89_1172145_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/20240506152638_hude6d581674c58540088d774479e67e89_1172145_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-additional-questions-needing-clarification&#34;&gt;Two Additional Questions Needing Clarification
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.How to View the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement is an unavoidable topic in modern Chinese history. Different eras have different views on the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement, and some of these views are incompatible, almost without any intersection points. If we set aside the issue of “Li Xiucheng,” I believe that most people would still evaluate the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement in a more rational manner. A careful study of Hong Xiuquan and the history of the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement reveals that it was just another failed case of a peasant uprising, with no substantial difference from the Nian Rebellion. The Christian doctrines employed by the movement, including some sporadic expressions of anti-imperialist nature, were just the inevitable backdrop of that era. However, when it comes to evaluating the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement, things become much more complex once the issue of “Li Xiucheng” is involved. For a long time after Qiao Benyu published “Evaluation of Li Xiucheng’s Autobiography” in 1962, criticizing Li Xiucheng for being “loyal but not loyal,” the issue of Li Xiucheng became a hot topic in the study of modern Chinese history, and it even became the most studied figure in modern history for a time. The research on Li Xiucheng ultimately boils down to a question of political stance. If one takes a liberal stance, Li Xiucheng did indeed guide the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement towards becoming a capitalist country, enough to be revered as a pioneer by liberals; if one takes a classist stance, Li Xiucheng’s betrayal of the peasant revolution is indeed the greatest stain on his life. Especially after he was captured, his attempt to persuade Zeng Guofan to rebel against the Qing dynasty and declare himself emperor can be seen as evidence that the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement still had not escaped the shackles of the old-style peasant uprising, including the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom itself, which was just another failed feudal kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Black on white, the evidence is ironclad; Li Xiucheng’s loyalty did not endure, not a lesson to be learned.”  – Mao Zedong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Heavenly Kingdom relied on the rise of a new talent, Li Xiucheng, to support it, but the rest of its political and military efforts could not match his.” – A Comprehensive History of China&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li Xiucheng was born into a poor peasant family, grew up fighting hunger and cold, joined the God Worshipping Society, participated in the Jintian Uprising, and his entire family joined the ranks. Through the crucible of revolution, he rose from a soldier to the highest commander of the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Army. He lived a life of “iron-hearted loyalty,” leaving heroic deeds that moved people to sing and cry. Unfortunately, his country was destroyed, and he was captured. His attempt to use a false surrender tactic, like Jiang Wei, was detrimental to the spirit of revolutionary education. The history is ruthless, and criticism is inevitable, but it is also a pity! – A History of the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement is a very dark chapter in Chinese history, and I have always wanted to remain silent about it. Yet, the charm and hardships of the early days of the movement also inspire awe. This movement originated from noble, exaggerated yet distorted ideals, advanced rapidly with strategic movements, threatening the Qing government’s rule. It swept away everything, refusing to rebuild, trying to overthrow the Qing dynasty but unable to rule the country. The Taiping Army committed arson, murder, and looting, causing widespread suffering, and was eventually suppressed by the Qing army and foreign forces. This movement foreshadowed that China needed a true political transformation, to change its closed-door policy, and usher in a new era, becoming a truly civilized and humane nation. – Mou Yat-sen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/t013aee7524198f6bc5.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;970&#34;
	height=&#34;537&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/t013aee7524198f6bc5_hu471ff0638cfdadadea8fe47c589fe98e_107570_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/about-chinese-village-structure-that-i-held-for-thirty-years/images/t013aee7524198f6bc5_hu471ff0638cfdadadea8fe47c589fe98e_107570_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;180&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;433px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.How to View the Xiang Army’s Massacre Problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Xiang Army’s massacre problem has always been the biggest stain on the Xiang Army. Indeed, according to contemporary ethics, it is. However, in ancient times, war was indeed that bloody, including the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom, without exception. It is only because the historical moment of the Xiang Army’s massacre has reached the 1860s, which is relatively close to the contemporary period, that it seems especially out of the ordinary. Moreover, the location was in Nanjing, and 73 years later, the Japanese invaders committed a horrific massacre there, making it easy to compare the two events. Here, I also don’t want to “wash the dirt,” but it needs to be pointed out that some people vilify the Xiang Army on one hand and glorify the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom on the other, which is either stupidity or malice. Regarding the dark history of the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom, I will not quote it here, but I will simply quote the views of scholars on this event, along with a few bloody incidents from the same period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In examining the issue of massive population loss during the Nanjing-Jiangnan war during the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement, the indiscriminate killing, and sometimes even severe killing by both the Taiping Army and the Qing Army were undoubtedly the most important reasons. However, as time passed, regimes changed, and various political factors were considered, the indiscriminate killing committed by both armies had different interpretations in different historical periods. For a long time, due to the legitimacy of the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement as a peasant uprising, the indiscriminate killing by the Taiping Army during the Jiangnan war was, to some extent, diluted by its supposed revolutionary nature. At the same time, with the recent academic reinterpretation of the entire late Qing Dynasty history, the serious crimes of indiscriminate killing committed by the Qing Army during the Jiangnan war were, to some extent, intentionally or unintentionally diluted, and the indiscriminate killing during the war was more often attributed to the Taiping Army, while giving full affirmation, even exaggeration, to Zeng Guofan and his Xiang Army in suppressing the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom. It can be said that regardless of the focus of research and the positions held, deliberately exaggerating or avoiding the indiscriminate killing and crimes against humanity of one side is not an objective attitude of historical research. Only by seriously considering the advantages of the victorious Qing government in terms of discourse power and the attitudes of Jiangnan gentry towards the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom, and further supplementing new historical materials or even new evidence from archaeological excavations to the study of the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom, can we better restore the historical truth of the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement and this brutal war. — Shao Jian: “Discussion on Indiscriminate Killing During the Jiangnan War of the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Movement”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Tongzhi Shaanxi-Gansu Hui Uprising — Estimated Death Toll of 20 Million:&lt;/strong&gt; The Tongzhi Hui Rebellion began in 1862 and ended in 1873, lasting for more than a decade before being suppressed by the Qing government. According to the data analysis from “The History of the Population of China, Volume 5: Qing Dynasty” by Fudan University, after the disaster, the population of Shaanxi, originally over 13 million, decreased by 4.66 million, with a loss of 45.8% in the Guanzhong area. The population of Gansu, originally about 19.45 million (which included today’s Gansu, Qinghai, and Ningxia), decreased by 14.55 million. Among them, the Pingliang Prefecture, with an original population of about 2.8 million, suffered a loss of 2.49 million, and the Qingyang Prefecture, with an original population of about 1.41 million, suffered a loss of 1.287 million. Many villages and towns, originally with tens of thousands of people, were almost deserted after the disaster, with no one living within a radius of ten miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Taiping Heavenly Kingdom Uprising &lt;strong&gt;— Estimated Death Toll of 70 Million:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; ：The Taiping Heavenly Kingdom&amp;rsquo;s armed forces expanded into Guangxi, Hunan, Hubei, Jiangxi, Anhui, Jiangsu, Henan, Shanxi, Zhili, Shandong, Fujian, Zhejiang, Guizhou, Sichuan, Yunnan, Shaanxi, Gansu, and Guangdong provinces, capturing over 600 cities. This sustained, massive uprising movement, which lasted for more than a decade, directly caused an excessive death toll of at least 54 million in Jiangsu, Anhui, Jiangxi, Zhejiang, and Hubei provinces. If we also consider the population losses in other battlefields such as Hunan, Guangxi, Fujian, Sichuan, and other provinces, the population loss caused by the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom War in China would be at least over 100 million, with an excessive death toll directly caused by the war reaching 70 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Guangdong Tujia-Hakka Clashes&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;strong&gt;Estimated Death Toll of 1 Million:&lt;/strong&gt; The Guangdong Tujia-Hakka (Cantonese and Hakka) Clashes during the Xianfeng and Tongzhi reigns (1854-1867) is a major historical event that has been largely forgotten or ignored. This conflict originated in the western part of Guangdong, specifically in Heishan, and spread to several counties such as Kaiping, Enping, Gaoming, Xinxing, Xinning, and Yangchun, lasting for over a decade. The clashes resulted in the massacre of over a million people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Can female employees choose their retirement age at will?</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/1.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Can female employees choose their retirement age at will?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a labor dispute case arising from a worker’s desire to delay retirement. The plaintiff in the case is a company management company in Guangdong (Company A), and the defendant is Ms. Ou. The case is a labor contract dispute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/5.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;683&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/5_hucbca7e50e2572eac8d10ee39a99727d6_446108_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/5_hucbca7e50e2572eac8d10ee39a99727d6_446108_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;149&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;359px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1basic-case-summary&#34;&gt;1.Basic Case Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ms. Ou is a financial employee of Company A. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 2018, Ms. Ou was employed by Company A as a middle-level economist, but there was no agreement in their labor contract that Ms. Ou was in a management position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; On April 9, 2019, Company A sent Ms. Ou a “Notice of Retirement,” informing her that she would reach the legal retirement age on April 10, 2019, and notifying her to handle retirement procedures and complete work handover within the specified period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; On April 10, 2019, Ms. Ou turned 50 years old. She believed that during her working period, she had obtained the professional qualifications of a junior accountant and a middle-level economist, and enjoyed the treatment of professional title subsidy, so she should be classified as a female cadre. Therefore, she applied to Company A to choose to retire at 55 years old. After inquiring with relevant departments, Company A believed that she had reached the legal retirement age and sent her another “Notice of Retirement.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From April 1, 2019, to July 1, 2022, Ms. Ou repeatedly filed applications through labor arbitration, social security fund management, human resources and social security authorities, etc., to clarify her retirement age, but was rejected multiple times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 11, 2022, the Human Resources and Social Security Authority issued a “Notice of Retirement Age Clarification,” confirming that Ms. Ou is a female employee engaged in a professional and technical position and can retire at the cadre age of 55. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After negotiations between Company A and Ms. Ou, she returned to her position on September 1, 2022. After returning to her position, Ms. Ou applied for labor arbitration with Company A as the respondent, requesting confirmation that the labor relationship between the two parties still existed from May 2019 to August 2022, and requesting the payment of 310,000 yuan in wages from May 2019 to August 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 6, 2022, the Labor Arbitration Commission made a ruling in accordance with the law; Ms. Ou was dissatisfied with the arbitration ruling regarding the payment of wages and appealed to the court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/2.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;681&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/2_hu04f9d5f58cdba1da1af818aa8b0fdcaf_244592_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/2_hu04f9d5f58cdba1da1af818aa8b0fdcaf_244592_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2handling-results&#34;&gt;2.Handling Results
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On November 6, 2022, the Labor Arbitration Commission made a ruling: confirming that the labor relationship between the two parties still existed from May 2019 to August 2022, and reimbursing the wages for that period amounting to 70,000 yuan due to the fact that no labor was provided during that time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms. Ou appealed to the court because she was not satisfied with the determination of the amount of wages to be reimbursed in the ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 2, 2023, the court made a judgment: confirming that the labor relationship between the two parties still existed from May 2019 to August 2022, and reimbursing the wages for that period amounting to 70,000 yuan due to the fact that no labor was provided during that time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court’s judgment was consistent with the arbitration commission’s ruling: given that Ms. Ou did not provide any labor from May 2019 to August 2022, it was determined that her wages for that period should be calculated based on the minimum wage standard of Foshan City. Company A reduced the amount of wages to be reimbursed by 240,000 yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/3.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;680&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/3_hue85021deb4fcbb903a9a6d22d68cf869_221148_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/3_hue85021deb4fcbb903a9a6d22d68cf869_221148_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;361px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3case-insights&#34;&gt;3.Case Insights
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this case, Company A actively and legally responded to the handling of the case. After the dispute arose, Company A sent several letters to relevant departments to determine Ms. Ou’s retirement age but was unable to confirm her retirement age only because it did not receive a clear response; at the same time, given its active and legal response, it provided some factual basis for the arbitration commission and the court to discretionarily order Company A to calculate Ms. Ou’s wages from May 2019 to August 2022 based on the minimum wage standard of Foshan City. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in the process of handling the issue of workers’ retirement age, in addition to clearly stipulating in the labor contract that the worker’s position belongs to a “management position,” it is also necessary to comprehensively determine whether the worker’s position belongs to a “professional technical position.” In cases similar to Company A in this case, it is advisable to follow procedures to notify workers of retirement, consult with relevant departments, and retain relevant evidence to prove that the employer actively handles related issues during the worker’s status being undetermined, in order to obtain discretionary handling by the court and actively communicate with workers after receiving a response, properly handle the relationship between the employer and the worker, and standardize management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4research-insights&#34;&gt;4.Research insights
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the aging of our population deepens, labor disputes arising from employee retirement are increasing. This case suggests that before handling employee retirement matters, enterprises should communicate and negotiate fully with employees, respect their right to choose their retirement age, ensure that both parties have a clear understanding and consensus on retirement matters, and avoid unilateral decision-making. Additionally, in the daily personnel management process, enterprises can conduct legal risk assessments in advance regarding the issue of employee retirement age, take corresponding legal measures to prevent and resolve legal issues related to retirement age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/4.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1300&#34;
	height=&#34;731&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/4_hu7a70fff8e4ea805f6ae843f06bea6614_378288_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/can-female-employees-choose-their-retirement-age-at-will/images/4_hu7a70fff8e4ea805f6ae843f06bea6614_378288_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5relevant-laws-and-regulations&#34;&gt;5.Relevant laws and regulations
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice of the Ministry of Labor and Social Security on Preventing and Rectifying the Problem of Early Retirement of Enterprise Employees in Violation of National Regulations (Labor and Social Security Department Issue (1999) No. 8) The national legal retirement age for enterprise employees is 60 for men, 50 for female workers, and 55 for female cadres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opinions on Deepening the Reform of Internal Personnel, Labor, and Distribution Systems in State-owned Enterprises (National Economic and Trade Commission, Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security, Ministry of Labor and Social Security (2001) No. 230) Cancel the administrative level of enterprises. Enterprises will no longer apply the administrative levels of national organs, and managers will no longer enjoy the administrative level treatment of national organ cadres. Break down the traditional boundaries between “cadres” and “workers,” shifting from identity management to post management. Those working in management positions are managers. After a change of position, their income and other benefits should be adjusted accordingly to the new position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guangdong Provincial Department of Labor and Guangdong Provincial Social Insurance Management Bureau Forwarding the Original Notice of the Ministry of Labor and Social Security on Preventing and Rectifying the Problem of Early Retirement of Enterprise Employees in Violation of National Regulations (Guangdong Labor Wage (1999) No. 114) The determination of the current position of female employees should be based on the labor contract signed between the employer and the employee. That is, regardless of whether the original identity is a worker or cadre, their current position should be based on the position determined in the labor contract. Anyone who has worked in the current position for more than one year should be identified by the current position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to Legally Terminate an Employment Contract in China</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/how-to-legally-terminate-an-employment-contract-in-china/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/how-to-legally-terminate-an-employment-contract-in-china/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-legally-terminate-an-employment-contract-in-china/images/legal.webp" alt="Featured image of post How to Legally Terminate an Employment Contract in China" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a typical case of legally terminating an employment contract, where the plaintiff is Company A from Foshan City, and the defendant is Mr. Deng. The case revolves around a labor contract dispute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic facts of the case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 2018, Company A (engaged in concrete business) appointed Mr. Deng as the technical director. In 2020, Mr. Deng purchased concrete from Company A for his own housing construction, but the company’s system showed that the parameters of the concrete supplied to Mr. Deng (which were for high-grade concrete) were higher than the standards of the concrete he purchased (Mr. Deng bought low-grade concrete). In November 2021, Mr. Deng fell while descending a staircase at Company A and was injured while on a phone call with a colleague discussing work tasks, fracturing his right foot. In January 2022, Mr. Deng’s injury was recognized as a work-related injury. In April 2022, Mr. Deng printed out his salary records and discussed them with others, violating the confidentiality clause in the Employee Handbook, and Company A gave Mr. Deng a Class B work negligence penalty. In April 2022, an outsider reported Mr. Deng’s abnormal concrete purchase data to Company A, and the company informed Mr. Deng of the report and had several discussions with him, but Mr. Deng failed to provide a reasonable explanation for the data anomaly. In May 2022, a local housing construction authority inspection team conducted a special inspection at Company A and found some serious issues, placing the company under key monitoring. Among these issues, such as incomplete inspection materials, test results not meeting standard requirements, and raw materials lacking calibration records, fell under the responsibility of the technical department led by Mr. Deng. Company A again gave Mr. Deng a Class B work negligence penalty. On May 31, 2022, after notifying the company’s labor union, Company A issued Mr. Deng a “Notice of Termination of Employment Contract,” stating that according to the Employee Handbook, the company could terminate the employment contract immediately if an employee received two Class B penalties within a year. Mr. Deng later filed for labor arbitration, requesting that Company A pay for work injury insurance benefits and compensation for the illegal termination of the employment contract. Company A appealed the arbitration decision to the court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-legally-terminate-an-employment-contract-in-china/images/legal.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;683&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-legally-terminate-an-employment-contract-in-china/images/legal_hudcd69764c3de56315b24d7aa34a23e1b_378690_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-legally-terminate-an-employment-contract-in-china/images/legal_hudcd69764c3de56315b24d7aa34a23e1b_378690_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;149&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;359px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disposition of the Case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon review, the court determined that Company A should pay Mr. Deng work injury insurance benefits but was not required to pay compensation for the illegal termination of the employment contract. Mr. Deng, dissatisfied with the ruling, filed an appeal. The higher court rejected the appeal and upheld the original judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revelation of the case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lessons from the Case Constructing harmonious labor-capital relations is an important issue that must be addressed for the long-term and stable development of a company. This case is a typical labor dispute case, involving two common issues in labor disputes: one is the issue of work injury compensation, and the other is the issue of economic compensation for the termination of employment relations. The judgment in this case protects the legitimate rights and interests of employees with work injuries, clarifying the legal responsibility of the employer to pay work injury insurance benefits. On the other hand, in cases where a worker seriously violates company rules and regulations, the employer can terminate the employment relationship through legal procedures without paying economic compensation to the worker. It is important to note that when an employer formulates or modifies rules and regulations that directly affect the vital interests of workers, or when dealing with significant matters, it should discuss these with the employee representative congress or all employees and inform the workers of the rules and regulations. If the employer fails to inform the workers of the rules and regulations, these cannot be used as a basis for determining the rights and obligations of both parties. An employer with a trade union organization that unilaterally terminates an employment contract should notify the union of the reasons in advance. If the union is not notified in advance, and the worker requests economic compensation from the employer for illegally terminating the employment contract, the court should support the worker. In this case, the concrete company submitted evidence such as meeting notices, training confirmation records, public notice photos, and WeChat chat records, confirming that the Employee Handbook was agreed upon by the company’s union and acknowledged by the employees, and was publicly announced to all employees. Therefore, the court recognized that the Employee Handbook was binding on Mr. Deng. The concrete company also submitted a letter notifying the union of the termination of the employment contract, so the court confirmed that the procedures for terminating the employment contract by Company A were legal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This case has guiding, exemplary, and referential significance for promoting enterprises to hire workers in accordance with the law, reducing labor disputes, and maintaining legitimate employment autonomy. It promotes the core socialist values of respecting one’s position and loving one’s profession, gives a negative evaluation to the worker’s violation of professional ethics and damage to the company’s interests, and upholds the employer’s legitimate right to hire and fire, helping to create a first-class business environment and achieving a good judicial outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research Insights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In labor dispute cases, illegally terminating employment contracts is a perennial problem for many small and medium-sized enterprises. Some companies, when terminating employment contracts due to employees’ serious violations of company rules and regulations, often end up having to pay compensation for illegal termination because of their own inadequate personnel compliance systems. In this case, the fact that the company involved legally established a trade union and issued the “Employee Handbook” following legal procedures was the fundamental prerequisite for legally terminating the employee’s contract. This has typical exemplary significance for promoting the construction of enterprise personnel compliance systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to prevent sexual abuse of minors with intellectual disabilities</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/1.webp" alt="Featured image of post How to prevent sexual abuse of minors with intellectual disabilities" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the issue of the prevention of sexual assault of minors has received extensive attention, including the promulgation of a series of laws and regulations such as the Law on the Protection of Minors and the Regulations on the Protection of Minors in Schools, all of which emphasize the need to strengthen the prevention of sexual assault of minors. However, in general, most of the above-mentioned prevention work is concentrated in schools, and there is not much mention of the problem of sexual assault of minors at the social level, especially between families and neighbors, and a large proportion of sexual assault of minors with intellectual disabilities occurs between families and neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-shocking-cases&#34;&gt;1. Shocking cases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A simple search on the Internet is not difficult to find that cases of minors being sexually assaulted at home are not uncommon. Here are a few typical cases as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A case of a 9-year-old girl being sexually assaulted&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unfortunate incident of a 9-year-old girl in Guangzhou who was sexually assaulted by a neighbor for 3 years and whose parents did not know about it has recently attracted the attention of readers. At present, the suspect of sexually assaulting the girl is being detained on suspicion of child molestation, and the lawyer said that the suspect can be sentenced to more than 10 years in prison. It is reported that the reason why the girl was sexually assaulted by the monster neighbor for a long time was that the monster neighbor was an acquaintance and had intimidated the girl for a long time.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sexual assault of a 12-year-old girl with intellectual disabilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October this year, Xiaowen, a minor girl from Maoming, Guangdong Province, who has intellectual disability problems, became pregnant and was about to undergo abortion surgery. This was her second sexual assault and second pregnancy in eight months. The previous time, in March of this year, when the police were involved in the investigation, but a similar tragedy happened again in a short period of time.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A case of sexual assault of a mother and daughter (13 years old) with intellectual disabilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mentally handicapped mother and daughter in Lianghe Town, Linshui County, Guang&amp;rsquo;an City, Sichuan Province, fell prey to many elderly local men and were sexually assaulted many times. This cruel fact was uncovered because the 13-year-old daughter was found to be more than 5 months pregnant, and the local police took blood from adult males in the town for DNA testing, and found that the suspect was actually an 84-year-old man.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A 60-year-old man sexually assaulted a mentally handicapped woman from the same village and was sentenced to three years and seven months in prison&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang, a 60-year-old man in Bozhou, Anhui Province, knew that Zhang XX in the same village was mentally and intellectually disabled, but still had sexual relations with him, but he did not know that his actions constituted the crime of rape. Recently, the Qiaocheng District People&amp;rsquo;s Court of Bozhou City pronounced a verdict on the case, and the court sentenced the defendant Wang Moumou to three years and seven months in prison for rape in the first instance.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was further discovered that some media outlets had investigated these articles, and in addition to telling outrageous storylines, these articles were even more shocking in terms of the figures quoted in the articles. For example, DT Finance once wrote that among the 134 cases of sexual assault of minors it investigated, 54.2% of children under the age of 14 and 8.2% had intellectual disabilities. Among the perpetrators, there are not only strangers who committed random crimes, Didi drivers, netizens who have just met, but also acquaintances including friends, relatives, neighbors, etc. Among them, the proportion of family members committing crimes reached 15.5%, which is the highest proportion of acquaintances committing crimes. In addition, the proportion of repeated sexual assault in cases committed by family members is as high as 94%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 22 months from January 2018 to October 2019, prosecutors across the country prosecuted 32,500 people for sexual assault against minors, an average of 49 per day.&lt;br&gt;
——DT Finance&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/2.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;683&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/2_huf4bf6bf14cb13f7874a6fc84a3fab9e7_309920_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/2_huf4bf6bf14cb13f7874a6fc84a3fab9e7_309920_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;149&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;359px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-lack-of-legislation&#34;&gt;2. Lack of legislation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2020 revision of the Law on the Protection of Minors is the main legal basis for the prevention of sexual assault, and the issue of sexual assault is mentioned 11 times, including the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minors&amp;rsquo; parents and other guardians must not retain persons who have sexually violated minors to care for minors on their behalf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools and kindergartens shall establish systems for the prevention of sexual assault&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools and kindergartens must not conceal situations of sexual violations against minors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools and kindergartens shall carry out education on the prevention of sexual assault&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools and kindergartens shall employ protective measures for minors who have suffered sexual violations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexual assault of minors is prohibited&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Units with close contact with minors should review whether the applicant has a record of sexual assault when recruiting staff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The State is to establish a system for inquiring into information on persons convicted of sexual assault&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State organs are to carry out necessary protective measures for minor victims of sexual assault and their families&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judicial organs handling cases of sexual violations of minors are to follow the provisions of special procedures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be seen that in terms of the prevention of sexual abuse of minors, the Law on the Protection of Minors mainly limits the rules to schools. But there are still quite a few loopholes in other areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vulnerabilities at the household&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the family level, the Law on the Protection of Minors only stipulates that when a minor&amp;rsquo;s parents or other guardians are unable to fully perform their guardianship duties due to reasons such as going out to work, they may not entrust a person with a record of sexual assault to take care of a minor on their behalf. There is no regulation for situations such as parents or guardians sexually assaulting minors, and only the relevant catch-all clauses can be applied by reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vulnerabilities at the societal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for how to prevent minors from being sexually assaulted at the social level, in addition to restricting persons with sexual assault records from engaging in occupations that have close contact with minors, no other work measures have been formulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loopholes in the judicial process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the judicial process, there are also great difficulties in the protection of minors with intellectual disabilities. Because the victim is both a minor and a mentally handicapped child, does not have full capacity for conduct, has limited ability to judge violations, cannot understand the social consequences of such conduct, does not know how to protect the scene and evidence, and cannot effectively testify, it is difficult to collect evidence and solve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A girl under the age of 18 in Xikou Town, Xiuning County, Anhui Province, was sexually assaulted by three people in the same village from May last year to January this year, resulting in pregnancy. This online post has attracted the attention of many netizens. The bureau responded that on April 26 this year, the public security department immediately intervened in the investigation after receiving the report, and then took criminal coercive measures against the criminal suspect Wang in accordance with the law, and after the case was transferred to the Xiuning County Procuratorate for trial, the procuratorate made a decision not to approve the arrest in accordance with the law, and the criminal suspect has now been changed to residential surveillance. —— &lt;em&gt;It was revealed that a girl in Anhui was sexually assaulted and pregnant by 3 people, and the procuratorate made a decision not to approve the arrest&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/3.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;682&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/3_hu9651a340b917a363459adca1d6d17b5f_327670_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/3_hu9651a340b917a363459adca1d6d17b5f_327670_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-the-base-number-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities-who-have-been-sexually-assaulted&#34;&gt;3. The base number of minors with intellectual disabilities who have been sexually assaulted
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-number-of-people-who-are-difficult-to-count&#34;&gt;The number of people who are difficult to count
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estimates from media: 2.8 million&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The size of the population with intellectual disabilities in China has always been a mystery. According to estimates, some self-media say that the proportion of the country&amp;rsquo;s mentally handicapped population is 1%, that is, 14 million, of which 50% are minors, and the number of newborns with intellectual disabilities is about 1.1 million every year. The number of &amp;ldquo;marginal intellectual disabilities&amp;rdquo; who fall between the mentally retarded and the normal (generally with an IQ below 70 as the criterion) is even larger, numbering in the tens of millions.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;em&gt;According to the estimate of 17.95% of the population aged 0-14 in the communiqué of China&amp;rsquo;s Seventh Population Census, minors account for about 20% of the population, the same below.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample survey: 2 million&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the results of China&amp;rsquo;s first national sample survey of disabled persons in 1987, the current disability rate of intellectual disability is 12.7 per thousand (including intellectual disability in comprehensive disability). According to the Second National Sample Survey of Persons with Disabilities in 2006, there were about 9.88 million people with intellectual disabilities (including intellectual disabilities in comprehensive disabilities), accounting for about 0.75 per cent of the total population and 11.9 per cent of the disabled population.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of registrants: 430,000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2008, the China Disabled Persons&amp;rsquo; Federation (CDPF) launched the construction of a national basic database of persons with disabilities, collecting and managing the basic population information of persons with disabilities in conjunction with the issuance of second-generation certificates for persons with disabilities, and through identity authentication with the Ministry of Public Security&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;National Citizenship Information Service System&amp;rdquo;, it has established the only authoritative national basic information database for persons with disabilities in China. As of June 3, 2013, a total of 37,952,000 persons with disabilities had been collected in the National Basic Database of Persons with Disabilities, of which 2,157,000 were intellectually disabled.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of people served: 170,000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, according to the statistics of the China Disabled Persons&amp;rsquo; Federation, there are 656,000 intellectually disabled people in China in 2022&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;Receiving rehabilitation services decreased by 208,000 from 864,000 in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, it shows that it is indeed difficult to find out the base number of people with intellectual disabilities in China, and on the other hand, it also confirms that the state and society do not pay enough attention to this group. After all, in the folk, the abbreviation of intellectual disability is &amp;ldquo;intellectual disability&amp;rdquo;, which is a common insulting word. As a family, it is obviously impossible to take the initiative to report that their child is &amp;ldquo;mentally retarded&amp;rdquo;, and often can only be counted through hospital identification or other means. But just like the sensational &amp;ldquo;Xuzhou Iron Chain Girl&amp;rdquo;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:12&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;The practice of some families imprisoning people with intellectual disabilities for a long time objectively makes it difficult to keep these data in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In horizontal comparison, the prevalence of intellectual disability among children over the age of 5 is about 1% globally, of which about 0.6% is severe intellectual disability&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:13&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;。 The National Survey of Children&amp;rsquo;s Health found that in 2011~2012, the intellectual disability rate of children aged 2~17 was about 1.1%&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:14&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;。 Domestic academic research usually uses the 0.75% conclusion of the 2006 sample survey as the benchmark for studying this issue.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:15&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:15&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;That is, the number of minors with intellectual disabilities in China is about 2 million in proportion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, since the average life expectancy of people with intellectual disabilities is obviously much shorter than that of the general population, the actual proportion of minors in the total of about 10 million people with intellectual disabilities should be much higher, and it is more reasonable to have between 3 million and 4 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/4.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;700&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/4_hue129277cccb4e4c974878e5d6851e964_206040_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/4_hue129277cccb4e4c974878e5d6851e964_206040_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;146&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;351px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-number-of-victims-is-more-difficult-to-count&#34;&gt;The number of victims is more difficult to count
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the 90s of the last century, some foreign studies found that the group with intellectual disabilities had the highest proportion of sexual abuse among all vulnerable groups&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:16&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:16&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, 90 per cent of people with intellectual disabilities have experienced sexual assault, and 82 per cent of them have been sexually assaulted before the age of 18&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:17&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:17&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, about 49% of whom have been sexually assaulted more than 10 times&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:18&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:18&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;。 For a long time, China&amp;rsquo;s public security departments have not published data on the incidence rate of criminal cases and the rate of solving cases, so it is difficult to find out the data in this area in China.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:19&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:19&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang Songbo et al., a scholar from mainland China, conducted a survey of hospitalized patients with mental disorders during the recovery period and found that 29.9% of female patients reported having been sexually assaulted, and 75.9% of them reported experiencing physical violence at the same time as they reported having been sexually assaulted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2004 to November 2007, the Lu County People&amp;rsquo;s Court in Sichuan Province accepted and concluded a total of 45 rape cases, of which 21 (46.7 percent) were victims with intellectual disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2005 to October 2007, the Beijing Miyun People&amp;rsquo;s Court concluded a total of 86 rape cases, of which 23 (26.7 percent) were victims of intellectual disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2005 to May 2007, the Rugao Municipal People&amp;rsquo;s Court in Jiangsu Province concluded a total of 35 rape cases, of which 14 were victims of intellectual disabilities, accounting for 40 percent. Of these, 4 rape cases were concluded between January and April 2007, and 5 victims were all intellectually disabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the influence of traditional culture, women in China have always attached more importance to chastity and honor, and the reporting rate of sexual assault cases is low, and the judicial &amp;ldquo;black number&amp;rdquo; of sexual assault is the highest among all types of crimes. Therefore, in reality, there are a large number of cases of sexual assault of people with intellectual disabilities who are not reported and are dealt with by the judicial authorities. If the standard of 25% in foreign countries is extrapolated, then there should &lt;strong&gt;be no less than 600,000 victims of sexual assault by mentally disabled people in China.&lt;/strong&gt; A &lt;em&gt;Review of Research on Sexual Assault of People with Intellectual Disabilities&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:20&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:20&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the study found that men with intellectual disabilities are almost equally likely to be sexually assaulted than women, and that men with intellectual disabilities are also at high risk of sexual assault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/5.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;683&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/5_hudc6147bf7d76002cccbc3ca12a3e67c8_282352_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/5_hudc6147bf7d76002cccbc3ca12a3e67c8_282352_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;149&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;359px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-difficulties-in-preventing-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities&#34;&gt;4. Difficulties in preventing sexual abuse of minors with intellectual disabilities
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;difficult-to-research&#34;&gt;Difficult to research
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present, there is a lack of research on the prevention of sexual assault of minors with intellectual disabilities in China. For example, in terms of sexual assault prevention education, there are few studies on sexual assault prevention education, there are more quantitative studies and less qualitative studies, and most of the research content is research on the current situation and countermeasures of child sexual abuse prevention, but there is little attention paid to how the work is carried out, and how the teaching methods, strategies and effectiveness are.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:21&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:21&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;The reasons for this mainly include the following aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficult to study&lt;/strong&gt;: The study of minors with intellectual disabilities is inherently challenging, because sexual assault incidents may have a low reporting rate due to various reasons (e.g., victims are unable to communicate effectively, fear of retaliation, etc.), and the relevant population may have great difficulties in communication, understanding and expression skills, which greatly increases the difficulty of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low social attention&lt;/strong&gt;: At present, the whole society still pays little attention to people with intellectual disabilities, resulting in insufficient support and attention for related research. In terms of the scope of personal work, the attention to people with intellectual disabilities is far lower than the attention to special groups such as patients with severe mental disorders and the deaf-mute, after all, the latter cause accidents and accidents are very common and more harmful to society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of professionals&lt;/strong&gt;: The study of minors with intellectual disabilities requires expertise in special education, mental health, law, and social work, which may be relatively lacking. In the process of research, I found that there is a big gap between the countermeasures, suggestions or specific measures proposed by many papers in this field and the actual situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strong-concealment&#34;&gt;Strong concealment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a long time, due to social and cultural prejudices, people have generally been in a state of &amp;ldquo;talking about sexual perversion&amp;rdquo;, and they have avoided the issue of sexual assault. As for the sexual abuse of minors with intellectual disabilities, it is itself superimposed with multiple prejudices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marginalized groups&lt;/strong&gt; People with intellectual disabilities are marginalized groups, often not regarded as normal people, and are easily excluded and discriminated against by society. It is difficult for family members to maintain rational choices when dealing with people with intellectual disabilities, and many families are prone to choose inhumane ways to treat people with intellectual disabilities due to economic factors and various reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;way forward&lt;/strong&gt; Few families of origin can take care of people with intellectual disabilities for the rest of their lives, and most families will choose to seek another home for people with intellectual disabilities when they become adults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For women with intellectual disabilities, traditional Chinese rural families often take advantage of their normal fertility to marry off to groups such as &amp;ldquo;old singles&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;disabled people&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;absolute poor households&amp;rdquo; , so that the original family can get rid of the &amp;ldquo;burden&amp;rdquo;. Families with better family conditions are likely to spend extra money and find them a slightly better partner, as was the case with a cousin of mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For men with intellectual disabilities, it is even more miserable, often sent out by their families to do the hardest, most tiring or simple physical work, and suffer the most exploitation. I have two twin cousins who are currently in this state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this context, in order to achieve the purpose of &amp;ldquo;marriage&amp;rdquo;, the original family of the person with intellectual disabilities may still conceal the fact that the minor is sexually assaulted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relatives commit crimes&lt;/strong&gt; Due to the lack of awareness of people with intellectual disabilities and their high dependence on relatives, relatives have more opportunities to have intimate contact with them alone, which objectively increases the possibility of sexual abuse by relatives. And this kind of sexual assault is extremely difficult for the public power and the outside world to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/6.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;683&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/6_hud895a74634c1e29bccb9490c3327f6b2_326994_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/6_hud895a74634c1e29bccb9490c3327f6b2_326994_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;149&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;359px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-the-general-idea-of-preventing-sexual-abuse-of-minors&#34;&gt;5. The general idea of preventing sexual abuse of minors
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the provisions of the Law on the Protection of Minors on the prevention of sexual abuse of minors are not satisfactory, many measures and future plans are proposed in other laws and administrative regulations, but no special attention is paid to the issue of sexual abuse of minors with intellectual disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;legal-aspects&#34;&gt;Legal aspects
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Law on the Promotion of Family Education stipulates that the parents or other guardians of minors shall pay attention to the mental health of minors in light of the physical and mental development characteristics of minors of different ages, educate them on safety knowledge in areas such as sexual assault prevention, help them master safety knowledge and skills, and enhance their awareness and ability to protect themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Civil Code provides protective provisions on the statute of limitations for the right to claim compensation for sexual assault of minors, which shall be calculated from the date on which the victim reaches the age of 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;at-the-level-of-administrative-regulations&#34;&gt;At the level of administrative regulations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main norms of administrative regulations on the prevention of sexual abuse of minors are the Notice on the Development of Chinese Women and the Program for the Development of Chinese Children (2021-2030) issued by the State Council, which lists nearly 20 preventive measures, in addition to the same measures listed in the Law on the Protection of Minors, there are the following plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effectively control and severely punish illegal and criminal acts of rape, indecency, and humiliation of girls and women with intellectual or mental disabilities, and prevent and severely punish illegal and criminal acts of sexual violations against children in accordance with law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexual assault committed by persons with special responsibilities to children is severely punished in accordance with law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establish and improve mechanisms for caring for key populations and families, mechanisms for discovering and reporting infringement cases, mechanisms for joint prevention and coordination of multiple departments, and systems for supervising the promotion of infringement cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raise awareness and capacity among children, families, schools, and communities to identify, prevent, prevent, and report sexual abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explore the establishment of a system for disclosing information on persons who have committed crimes against children, and strictly implement a system for the filing of foreign teachers&amp;rsquo; certificates of no criminal record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strengthen case filing and case filing supervision, and improve case filing standards and conviction and sentencing standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explore the formulation of special evidentiary standards for cases of sexual violations against children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strictly punish illegal and criminal conduct that uses the internet to sexually lure or sexually violate children in accordance with law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;departmental-rules-and-local-regulations&#34;&gt;Departmental rules and local regulations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the level of departmental regulations, it is mainly the education, the Communist Youth League, the women&amp;rsquo;s federation and other institutions that make special provisions on the prevention of sexual assault on students. For example, in December 2018, the General Office of the Ministry of Education issued a notice on further strengthening the prevention of sexual assault of students in primary and secondary schools (kindergartens) , proposing five work measures. However, the content of the measures is generally the same as those enumerated in the Law on the Protection of Minors, with the main difference being that the preventive responsibilities of local government bodies and schools are emphasized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of local regulations and local government normative documents, it is mainly a refinement of the Law on the Protection of Minors and other laws and regulations at the national level, most of which are copied from the original text, and no new measures are proposed. For example, the regulations on the protection of minors in Beijing, Shandong and other places, the three-year action implementation plan for improving the quality of care services for left-behind children and children in difficult situations in urban and rural areas in Chongqing, and the construction plan for child-friendly cities in Huzhou (2023-2025).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/7.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;663&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/7_hu1448f4eb91b67c5a5c662fe81e04e6f8_320316_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/7_hu1448f4eb91b67c5a5c662fe81e04e6f8_320316_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;154&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;370px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-special-system-for-the-prevention-of-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities&#34;&gt;6. Special system for the prevention of sexual abuse of minors with intellectual disabilities
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, for minors with intellectual disabilities who are enrolled in school normally, the state has established a preliminary prevention system in the construction of a sexual assault prevention system. However, for minors with intellectual disabilities who have completed compulsory education (generally 15 years old), some minors with intellectual disabilities who are unable to attend school normally, and there is still a certain gap in how to prevent the sexual abuse of minors with intellectual disabilities at the family and social levels, I personally believe that a special system for preventing the sexual abuse of minors with intellectual disabilities can be established from the following aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproductive intervention&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Actively intervenes in family fertility services for people with intellectual disabilities to help them understand the reproductive process and possible consequences, so that families with intellectual disabilities can have equal opportunities and resources so that they can make reproductive decisions that are suitable for them. When necessary, in special circumstances such as where minors with intellectual disabilities are sexually assaulted and pregnant, medical services for the termination of pregnancy shall be actively intervened, to ensure that the reproductive rights of minors with intellectual disabilities are respected, and to avoid unnecessary new social tragedies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State Assessment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Carry out regular assessments for minors with intellectual disabilities, and establish a team of multidisciplinary professionals including doctors, nurses, psychological counselors, social workers, and other multidisciplinary professionals through cooperation with medical institutions, social welfare institutions, educational institutions, and other relevant institutions, to provide comprehensive status assessment services for minors with intellectual disabilities, assess possible problems in home and school supervision, and check whether there are sexual assaults and other violent victims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family Follow-up Surveys&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Establish a system of face-to-face home visits, with teachers, social workers, and other personnel regularly carrying out home visit services to the families of minors with intellectual disabilities, assessing the growth status of minors with intellectual disabilities in the family, and investigating possible sexual assault and other violent victimizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promote smart wearable devices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ma Dugong, a self-media person, has been strongly advocating that all minors should wear smart wearable devices to avoid possible accidents. Although this idea is obviously too extreme, if it is only carried out among minors with intellectual disabilities, it may be a very good practice, and the government can provide the equipment free of charge, and continue to monitor the use of the equipment, supporting the special protection of face-to-face interviews, evaluations and other systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement special legal rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Give full play to the preventive effects of criminal punishments, establish special detection rules for cases of sexual assault on minors with intellectual disabilities, and avoid emboldening potential criminals due to some unsolvable cases. For example, where minors with intellectual disabilities are unable to verbally express the circumstances of the violation, they may learn from the practices of foreign countries and the Taiwan region and use dolls with anatomical details of the human body to use body language instead, which is to be treated as the victim&amp;rsquo;s statement.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:22&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:22&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2001, Taiwan began to purchase a large number of domestic violence and sexual assault prevention and treatment centers in the jurisdiction. In order to assist in the investigation of sexual assault crimes against young children and children with intellectual disabilities, and to increase the rate of prosecution and conviction, the relevant departments of Taiwan have developed and produced male and female interrogation dolls of different genders as tools to assist case handlers in questioning specific child victims. Pop-up books, human body charts, and other related tools commonly used in daily life assist in questioning juvenile victims. &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Research on the issue of the acceptance of victims&amp;rsquo; statements in cases of sexual assault against minors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:22&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:22&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/8.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;730&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/8_hue94a0d572d52448440f7f68fb07c32e7_245314_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities/images/8_hue94a0d572d52448440f7f68fb07c32e7_245314_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;140&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;336px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://baike.baidu.com/item/%E5%B9%BF%E5%B7%9E9%E5%B2%81%E5%A5%B3%E7%AB%A5%E8%A2%AB%E9%82%BB%E5%B1%85%E6%80%A7%E4%BE%B5%E4%BA%8B%E4%BB%B6/15499432&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;A 9-year-old girl in Guangzhou was sexually assaulted by a neighbor&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.thepaper.cn/newsDetail_forward_4969911&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maoming police investigated &amp;ldquo;12-year-old mentally handicapped girl was sexually assaulted again&amp;rdquo; and underwent abortion surgery on the 16th&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.thepaper.cn/newsDetail_forward_8123360&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Sichuan mentally disabled mother and daughter were sexually assaulted, and the 13-year-old daughter was pregnant, and the suspect was an octogenarian&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chinacourt.org/article/detail/2016/02/id/1805666.shtml&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;A 60-year-old man was sentenced to three years and seven months in prison for sexually assaulting a mentally handicapped woman from the same village&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=Mzg5NDg2NjMyMg==&amp;amp;mid=2247645186&amp;amp;idx=1&amp;amp;sn=21d81746b2e48cd095e209dc9d649b90&amp;amp;source=41#wechat_redirect&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Behind the 112 cases of sexual assault of minors: who is committing the violence? Who is crying for help?&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.guancha.cn/society/2016_10_12_376986.shtml&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;It was revealed that the Anhui girl was sexually assaulted by 3 people and became pregnant, and the procuratorate made a decision not to approve the arrest&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://m.huxiu.com/article/233316.html?f=ydzx&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The flippancy of subjecting mentally handicapped children to general education is essentially abandonment&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.gov.cn/guoqing/2021-05/13/content_5606149.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Communiqué of the Seventh National Population Census&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0891422210001800&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Wu L, Qiu Z, Wong D, et al. The research on the status, rehabilitation, education, vocational development, social integration and support services related to intellectual disability in China [J]. Res Dev Disabil, 2010, 31: 1216-1222.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://kns.cnki.net/kcms2/article/abstract?v=yqeyU9EK6jThjnWu2Efe3BJgNWcBuU7yR4p6ul7RBWjnm7NtKbqC-87g-EM8EYtPsma5JqLDeX9A8hFJTVvh2FlGN5MxWAdDhTKnqfGNEaZnZOxSGux-DoM6iW5j6tDd&amp;amp;uniplatform=NZKPT&amp;amp;flag=copy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zhang Jun: Data analysis of the National Basic Database of Disabled Population, Statistical Survey, No. 3, 2013&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cdpf.org.cn/zwgk/zccx/ndsj/zhsjtj/2022zh/8a6c50f56bae42d9b4cad0440ce01931.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Progress of the main business of the cause of the disabled in China&lt;/a&gt; [︎ ↩]&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:12&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://baike.baidu.com/item/%E4%B8%B0%E5%8E%BF%E7%94%9F%E8%82%B2%E5%85%AB%E5%AD%A9%E5%A5%B3%E5%AD%90%E4%BA%8B%E4%BB%B6/60063632&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Feng County gave birth to an eight-child woman&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29034100/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hughes-Mccormack LA, Rydzewska E, Henderson A, et al. Prevalence of mental health conditions and relationship with general health in a whole-country population of people with intellectual disabilities compared with the general population [J]. BJPsych Open, 2017, 3(5): 243-248&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:14&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ppc.uiowa.edu/publications/outcomes-care-iowa-medicaid-managed-care-enrollees-state-fiscal-year-2007-final-report&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Momany E T, Damiano P C, Carter K D. Outcomes of care for Iowa medicaid enrollees: state fiscal year 2008. Final report to the Iowa Department of Human Services [R]. Iowa: University of Iowa, 2009.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:15&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://kns.cnki.net/kcms2/article/abstract?v=yqeyU9EK6jSf4WUn2SYPcGi3NZBOsWvxhhepoldnHTRMKbwpM4qPlPs427JY5J0GSupIG4fvSdH9Xi7hyWkv7LuSPcnlmKTOrN-zgcUtXg6JWD1oqY6WQlqfHJDJrlpzvcnrb9ybNxk=&amp;amp;uniplatform=NZKPT&amp;amp;flag=copy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Wang Miaomiao, Lu Guohua, Li Anqiao, Qiu Zhuoying: Research on the Health Status and Health Services of the Intellectually Handicapped, Chinese Rehabilitation Theory and Practice., 2019, 25(01)&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:15&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:16&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/1992-19972-001&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Sobsey D,Doe T. Patterns of sexual abuse and assault. Journal of Sexuality and Disability,1991,9(3):243-259.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:16&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:17&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/1994-30217-001&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stromsness, M. M. (1993). Sexually abused women with mental retardation: Hidden victims, absent resources. Women &amp;amp; Therapy, 14(3-4), 139–152.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:17&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:18&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S019074092030685X&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Glenn S Q.Sexuality education lesson plans for children with disabilities[M]. The second edition.2010,10(2):22-23.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:18&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:19&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://kns.cnki.net/kcms2/article/abstract?v=yqeyU9EK6jTppwD7FdUsMZlXYTaj0Ek4xbYlZYFoF1HZKk197IDA0jp8r_IfBxG2aw1-g_F97fMfYIkRbC08VznT4MbKBHTKXH_cnCTbReZCQBLkHLImcyV_3ejdHbFqd0KeUJubOFc=&amp;amp;uniplatform=NZKPT&amp;amp;language=CHS&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LIAO Huaigao,XIONG Shaobo,LI Qiaoyi.A review of the research on sexual assault of mentally handicapped people[J].Theory and Reform,2011(4):156-160&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/How-to-prevent-sexual-abuse-of-minors-with-intellectual-disabilities#fnref19&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:19&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:20&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://kns.cnki.net/kcms2/article/abstract?v=yqeyU9EK6jRIcI9hXDesq8RSZcL2ExDxqHXASvnwXHRgRT9LFsx3LPCwHCrxUEmf84eK4kyq9HEMzqlAqLcUCfxnhVAdR7XjWlWXUeXQjN_Xn6qvgOGk8r67gH2_ftiJD5HtTvVA0SHXP3ribXbTpQ==&amp;amp;uniplatform=NZKPT&amp;amp;language=CHS&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Action Research on Sexual Assault Prevention Education for Adolescent Students with Intellectual Disabilities in Special Education Schools, Sichuan Normal University, 2021&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:20&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:21&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://kns.cnki.net/kcms2/article/abstract?v=yqeyU9EK6jQ-ROOesWxOnWfdFF3fVISP76bzDlgjo-UScgEml5SLYmVG8jWYGC82o1eQJTLkBMDXvoA6u8Gvf9f3taaQAaIAMTBZpRsglj4zdbfg16d2G_IgQwhdQ8kB8y14hCbNcmrP_8vPMBAiEQ==&amp;amp;uniplatform=NZKPT&amp;amp;language=CHS&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dai Zijun, A Comparative Study on the Interrogation Methods of Foreign Juvenile Victims and Its Enlightenment, Chinese Youth Social Sciences, No. 2, 2022&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:21&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:22&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://kns.cnki.net/kcms2/article/abstract?v=yqeyU9EK6jSNxKBGfKgyQtvFJZMr9Mc93ma5fE80OhnQ6IBrzSQ_mQvAkgKOYV5JxpZANYrFGAV6FAECb06P90dJ45XHTx-zMjp0_Wl_yIPeoNbNNz50kjZDhfUoDOdwwqkU9t4VkR7hytdM1X7blg==&amp;amp;uniplatform=NZKPT&amp;amp;language=CHS&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pan Xingwen.Research on the Acceptance of Victims&amp;rsquo; Statements in Sexual Assault Cases of Juveniles, East China University of Political Science and Law, 2023&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:22&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:22&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Korea’s Experience in Governing Traffic Accidents</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/1.webp" alt="Featured image of post Korea’s Experience in Governing Traffic Accidents" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-traffic-safety-situation-in-south-korea-has-changed-completely&#34;&gt;1. The traffic safety situation in South Korea has changed completely
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the latest statistics from the World Health Organization, South Korea&amp;rsquo;s traffic accident death rate per 100,000 people has dropped from 25.6 in 2000 to 8.6 in 2019, rising more than 100 places in the global ranking in 20 years, second only to Qatar, Latvia, the Bahamas and Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427155325.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1369&#34;
	height=&#34;1261&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427155325_hu9608166c9404674cd2f689e68c9650ba_132620_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427155325_hu9608166c9404674cd2f689e68c9650ba_132620_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;108&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;260px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further inquiries found that according to the data released by the South Korean government in recent years, the number of traffic accident deaths in South Korea has continued to decline for four consecutive years since 2020. In 2022, there were 2,735 deaths, and the mortality rate per 100,000 people has dropped to 5.3. By 2023, it will further drop to 2,551 people, and the traffic accident fatality rate per 100,000 people has dropped to 4.9, making it one of the world&amp;rsquo;s leading countries in traffic safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427161559.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1506&#34;
	height=&#34;934&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427161559_hu66b6cc19695db31301077ade73d1e7bf_66450_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427161559_hu66b6cc19695db31301077ade73d1e7bf_66450_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;161&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;386px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Road Safety Country Profiles Korea 2023 &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fn1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427162240.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1398&#34;
	height=&#34;903&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427162240_hu651f36e44dfb2cd54eeb11e7cc9813c4_78327_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427162240_hu651f36e44dfb2cd54eeb11e7cc9813c4_78327_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;154&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;371px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Road Safety Country Profiles Korea 2023 &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fn1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;[1:1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-traffic-safety-used-to-be-a-major-social-issue-in-south-korea&#34;&gt;2. Traffic safety used to be a major social issue in South Korea
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you search for &amp;ldquo;South Korea&amp;rsquo;s traffic safety&amp;rdquo;, it is not difficult to find that several years ago, South Korea had a high traffic fatality rate, ranking last among OECD countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeju, Nov. 16 (Yonhap) &amp;ndash; Seol Jae-hoon, director of the Traffic Safety Research Headquarters of the Korea Institute of Transportation, attended a seminar on &amp;ldquo;Policy Proposals for Improving Traffic Culture&amp;rdquo; held at the Jeju Provincial Government Building on Nov. 16 and said that the number of traffic accident fatalities per 100,000 people in Malaysia in 2010 was 11.3, the highest among the 29 OECD member countries.&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fn2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinanews.com, July 7 According to Yonhap News Agency, on the 7th, the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) revealed that based on 2011, South Korea ranked second among the 31 OECD member countries with 105 traffic accident fatalities, ranking second after Poland (109). The number of traffic fatalities in South Korea is 1.7 times higher than the OECD average of 63.&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fn3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, former South Korean President Lee Myung-bak said in a speech on national radio and the Internet that looking at the statistics related to disasters and disasters around the world, it is difficult to say that South Korea is close to joining the ranks of developed countries. In 2010, for example, more than 10,000 people died each year in work-related injuries, car accidents, and fires, and the economic loss amounted to 32 trillion won. In 2011, more than 340,000 people were injured in traffic accidents. With 15,000 suicides, the highest number of OECD countries, and the rapid growth of suicide rates among the elderly population, South Korea&amp;rsquo;s social security situation in all aspects is extremely serious. Lee Myung-bak pointed out that only when the people can live and work in peace and contentment and have a safe living environment can they be called truly developed countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-south-koreas-main-practices-for-improving-traffic-safety&#34;&gt;3. South Korea&amp;rsquo;s main practices for improving traffic safety
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the whole, South Korea&amp;rsquo;s management of traffic accidents in recent years has experienced a process of transformation from local regional pilot to national promotion, from key areas of prevention to universal prevention, from temporary movement to legislative system, from extensive policy to fine management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;congressional-resolution---traffic-accidents-are-reduced-to-zero-movement&#34;&gt;Congressional resolution - Traffic accidents are reduced to zero movement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2013, the National Assembly passed the Resolution on Reducing Road Traffic Accidents to Zero, which aims to radically improve road safety in South Korea. Although this goal may seem exaggerated, it does win broad public support, after all, slogans such as &amp;ldquo;promote zero emissions from vehicles&amp;rdquo; are common in many countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resolution mainly includes three aspects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actively formulate and revise relevant laws and systems such as the Traffic Safety Law&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Securing financial resources for traffic safety projects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishment of an organization dedicated to the supervision and management of traffic safety affairs (Traffic Safety Research Institute)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resolution consists of four basic principles &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fn4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human life and health take precedence over all transportation purposes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppliers and regulators of road transport systems are equally responsible as users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The road traffic system minimizes human error and, if it occurs, damage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Road traffic system suppliers, regulators, and citizens work together to achieve safety&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nationwide-call-for-ideas&#34;&gt;Nationwide call for ideas
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, the newly established Traffic Safety Research Institute has launched a nationwide open contest to call for ideas to help reduce road traffic accidents with 3 million won a year. Among them, the project that won the grand prize in 2014 was the designation of a low-speed zone in the village.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2011, South Korea began to designate low-speed zones around disability care centers, but due to the lack of awareness of pedestrian protection in South Korea for a long time, in fact, pedestrian safety in South Korea has not been guaranteed. In 2013, South Korea had the lowest pedestrian road traffic fatality rate in the OECD, and the situation was particularly bad for the elderly, with the death rate for pedestrians over 65 years old nearly five times higher than the OECD average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the adoption of the Resolution on Reducing Road Traffic Accidents to Zero, the Ministry of Land, Infrastructure, Transport and Tourism of the Republic of Korea will coordinate the funding of the traffic safety project, and local funds will no longer be required. As a result, after 2014, villages across South Korea have been competing to join the low-speed highway zone program. The plan consists of two elements, one is to reduce the speed limit in the village area by demarcating low-speed zones, and the other is to install electronic monitoring equipment in each low-speed zone to give priority to pedestrians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427171157-1024x602.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;602&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427171157-1024x602_hu61b88214b7f3ac7d91b9b0a1fc3ec5ad_291271_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427171157-1024x602_hu61b88214b7f3ac7d91b9b0a1fc3ec5ad_291271_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;170&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;408px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Republic of Korea’s Campaign to Bring Road Crashes to Zero &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fn4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to statistics, in the pilot village area, the total number of car accidents decreased by 37%, the number of fatalities decreased by 29%, and the number of injuries decreased by 43% in the first six months after the installation of low-speed zone facilities. Seeing the success of the pilot program, more districts are seeking to establish village areas to improve pedestrian safety. The following year, 20 sections were added in 8 districts, and by 2018, another 30 sections were installed in 10 districts. Local residents generally welcomed the establishment of village areas, and some local governments decided to install village areas at their own expense. For example, in 2018, the Gapyeong government installed two villages from its own budget at the request of local residents. As of 2018, 64 villages in 23 regions of South Korea have joined the program.&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fn5&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-safety-plan-is-published-annually&#34;&gt;The safety plan is published annually
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the adoption of the Resolution on Reducing Road Traffic Accidents to Zero, South Korea has developed a series of plans to improve traffic safety every year. For example, in 2016, 26 measures in five areas were introduced, and 46 safety projects were continuously promoted, with the goal of reducing the traffic fatality rate to 1.6 deaths per 10,000 vehicles by 2017, making the use of seat belts mandatory for all seats on all roads, strengthening penalties for traffic violations, improving traffic safety education, and strengthening the regulation of commercial vehicle safety.&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fn6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establish a pedestrian-first transportation culture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improving traffic laws: Continue to enforce &lt;strong&gt;the policy of mandatory seat belts for all seats&lt;/strong&gt; and increase penalties for the most frequently reported violations by whistleblowers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prohibition of reckless driving and revision of sanctions (implementation of monitoring facilities in locations with optimal control)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new regulations to control careless driving &lt;strong&gt;are punishable by up to one year in prison or a fine of up to $4,000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Differentiated revisions to the provisions on liability insurance payout ratios for uninsured vehicles and escape accidents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enforce control over illegal, unregistered vehicles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vehicles with properly installed safety devices are rewarded by offering premium discount promotions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhance road safety advertising by promoting collaboration among diverse road safety-related agencies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improve policies that encourage citizen engagement, including &amp;ldquo;Good Driver Miles&amp;rdquo;, experience-oriented &amp;ldquo;Advanced Education Centers&amp;rdquo;, etc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement a security-oriented infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous improvement of high-accident sites and hazardous road areas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement safety facilities including roundabouts and rest areas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhancement of incident management strategies in regional traffic information centers (CCTV surveillance)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expansion of residential and school areas,&lt;strong&gt;and legislation to establish a speed limit of 30 km/h for &amp;ldquo;community road areas&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promote Lane Departure Warning System (LDWS) and Automatic Emergency Braking System (ABES) standards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carry out the &amp;ldquo;pedestrian-oriented environmental development&amp;rdquo; project and &lt;strong&gt;increase the setting of areas for the elderly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up a customized transportation system for the transportation disadvantaged&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Itinerant education for senior drivers and &lt;strong&gt;complements training centers for senior drivers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traffic accident prevention programs in rural areas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Promote children&amp;rsquo;s vehicle safety awareness campaigns and centralize control of children&amp;rsquo;s school buses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange traffic volunteers at school hours to prevent road accidents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helmets and child safety seats are available in limited quantities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhance safety regulations for commercial vehicles and upgrade accident response systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conduct traffic safety assessments of commercial transport companies that cause traffic accidents and fatalities, and reward and incentivize companies that perform well&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital recording of dangerous driving behaviors&lt;/strong&gt; to enhance safety-oriented driving behaviors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driver training and providing experiential education&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strengthen national transport policies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strengthen the working-level meetings of the &amp;ldquo;Traffic Safety Policy Council&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Council for the Promotion of Transport&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strengthen the traffic safety capacity building of local government departments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assessment of local traffic culture indicators will improve the attention of local governments to road safety awareness&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;The above bold part is a rare measure in China&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427190142.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1440&#34;
	height=&#34;700&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427190142_hu629935663721fe173830d80f459a8d46_1079255_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427190142_hu629935663721fe173830d80f459a8d46_1079255_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;205&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;493px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Motorway Safety in Korea&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fn7&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Korea has installed barrier drums and rubber rollers in all high-speed turning areas, while standardizing the color and shape of road signs. The use of different colors to distinguish ground conductors at all highway intersections, two interchanges less than one kilometre apart from each other, overpasses with black dots, and overpasses with parking areas on sharp curves has reduced traffic safety risks to some extent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427191029.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1389&#34;
	height=&#34;1152&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427191029_hu33ce44ec425c01c889413adf8ca7bf0a_1313257_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427191029_hu33ce44ec425c01c889413adf8ca7bf0a_1313257_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;120&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;289px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-most-stringent-revision-of-the-road-safety-law-in-history&#34;&gt;The most stringent revision of the Road Safety Law in history
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In accordance with the requirements of the Resolution on Reducing Road Traffic Accidents to Zero, South Korea has revised the Road Safety Act several times and has continuously upgraded the measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significant reduction in driving speed&lt;br&gt;
 In April 2021, South Korea&amp;rsquo;s revised Road Traffic Act began to implement the &amp;ldquo;Safe Speed 5030 Policy&amp;rdquo;. Accordingly, the &lt;strong&gt;speed limit on urban arterial roads has been lowered to 50 km/h&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;speed limit on roads near homes and schools has been lowered to 30 km/h, and&lt;/strong&gt; the speed limit on intercity highways has remained unchanged. The new law strengthens penalties for speeding, with violators punishing a minimum fine of 30,000 won and demerit points, and in severe cases, they may face a suspended driver&amp;rsquo;s license and criminal penalties.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over below 20km/h ：30,000 won&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 20～40km/h：60,000 won + 15 points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 40～60km/h：90,000 won + 30 points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 60～80km/h：120,000 won + 60 points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 80~100km/h: 300,000 won or less, detention + 80 points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 100km/h: 1,000,000 won or less, detention + 100 points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 100 km/h three times: Imprisonment for up to 1 year or a fine of up to 5 million won + license revocation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are penalty points for each traffic violation, and if the cumulative penalty points for multiple violations exceed 40 points, the driver&amp;rsquo;s license will be suspended (suspended). If you accumulate 121 points or more in 1 year, 201 points or more in 2 years, or 271 points or more in 3 years, your driver&amp;rsquo;s license will be revoked (you cannot use it again).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the Korean survey, the new regulations will reduce the incidence of urban traffic accidents by 24.1%, the probability of serious injuries caused by traffic accidents by 21.5%, and the probability of death by 30%, while driving time will only be 2-3 minutes longer. - &lt;em&gt;Embassy of the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China in the Republic of Korea: Please note when driving in South Korea: South Korea implements the &amp;ldquo;Safe Speed 5030 Policy&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pedestrian protection significantly enhanced&lt;br&gt;
On July 12, 2022, South Korea&amp;rsquo;s revised Road Traffic Act significantly increased the obligation to protect pedestrians for right-turning vehicles. Put simply, when turning right, the vehicle must confirm whether there is a pedestrian crossing or preparing to cross the road, and the offender will be subject to penalties such as administrative fines or demerit points.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drivers must stop temporarily when a pedestrian hesitates or waves to a driver to cross the street, when a pedestrian waits in front of a crosswalk, when a pedestrian walks or runs quickly towards a crosswalk, or when a pedestrian turns to pay attention to a signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the children&amp;rsquo;s reserve area, regardless of whether there are traffic lights or not, it is mandatory to stop temporarily in front of the pedestrian crossing for observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violating the above regulations will result in penalties for violating the signal light, including a deduction of 10 points and a fine of 60,000 won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a traffic accident with a pedestrian occurs during the period, the offender will be sentenced to imprisonment for up to 5 years and a fine of up to 20 million won in accordance with the gross negligence offense under the Traffic Accident Handling Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South Korean police expect the implementation of the new law to significantly reduce pedestrian accidents and establish a more advanced pedestrian-centric road culture. - &lt;em&gt;Legal Daily: South Korea&amp;rsquo;s new version of the Road Traffic Act has greatly strengthened pedestrian protection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-south-koreas-traffic-safety-outlook&#34;&gt;4. South Korea&amp;rsquo;s Traffic Safety Outlook
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2022, South Korea formulated a new round of comprehensive five-year plan for traffic safety, which calls for a 50% reduction in traffic fatalities by 2027 from 2020 levels. South Korea&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Land, Infrastructure, Transport and Tourism has stated that it will redouble its efforts to prevent traffic-related deaths in order to achieve the UN&amp;rsquo;s recommended goal of preventing at least 50% of traffic deaths and injuries by 2030 as soon as possible. To achieve this goal, the South Korean government plans to advance the country&amp;rsquo;s transportation system upgrade by maximizing the use of information and communication technology, big data, and other cutting-edge technologies. At the same time, South Korea also plans to promote a conditional driver&amp;rsquo;s license system for the elderly, as the country is widely expected to become a super-aging society by 2025.&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fn8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427193704.png&#34;
	width=&#34;750&#34;
	height=&#34;378&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427193704_hub439713fde2dce18085f4ecb090260d4_213693_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/20240427193704_hub439713fde2dce18085f4ecb090260d4_213693_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;198&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;476px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the Ministry of Land, Infrastructure and Transport of the Republic of Korea has announced that it will spread the next-generation intelligent transportation C-ITS system by 2027 to achieve the goal of zero traffic accidents. The system includes location-based data collection, location-based traffic information, toll collection system, providing information on road dangerous road sections, road weather information, driving support for road construction sections, danger warning of traffic signal violations at intersections, right turn safe operation support, bus operation management, yellow bus operation guidance, school district speed control, pedestrian collision warning, vehicle collision avoidance support, emergency vehicle approach warning and vehicle emergency warning.&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fn9&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judging from the above measures, some of the measures do have reference points for China. For example, the mandatory wearing of seat belts is currently strictly implemented in only a few cities in China. Seat belts are rarely worn in the back of most vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-a-little-personal-impression&#34;&gt;5. A little personal impression
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the whole, South Korea has indeed achieved remarkable results in the management of traffic accidents in recent years, and it is indeed not easy to catch up with the old developed countries from its original backward position in the world. Judging from South Korea&amp;rsquo;s experience, I think there are several aspects that are worth affirming and learning from. But after checking the figures from the National Bureau of Statistics, I feel that I will talk about this matter later when I have time, and it seems that there is no need to write about it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/nationalstats-1024x836.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;836&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/nationalstats-1024x836_hu07c0426602828322957a5db8daa2b6a8_271736_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/nationalstats-1024x836_hu07c0426602828322957a5db8daa2b6a8_271736_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;122&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;293px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://data.stats.gov.cn/english/easyquery.htm?cn=C01&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;National Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/whotrafficdeaths-1024x457.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;457&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/whotrafficdeaths-1024x457_hu2915f390ee8a749ee12d7add56cf1643_86934_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/whotrafficdeaths-1024x457_hu2915f390ee8a749ee12d7add56cf1643_86934_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;224&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;537px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://data.who.int/indicators/i/D6176E2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;WHO data&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/worldbankdata-1024x370.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;370&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/worldbankdata-1024x370_hu8d3435b1e95a3cdebbf4482fef674edc_174585_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/koreas-experience-in-governing-traffic-accidents/images/worldbankdata-1024x370_hu8d3435b1e95a3cdebbf4482fef674edc_174585_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;276&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;664px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SH.STA.TRAF.P5?contextual=default&amp;amp;end=2019&amp;amp;locations=CN-KR-US-RU-VN&amp;amp;start=2000&amp;amp;view=chart&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;WorldBank data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;The World Health Organization (WHO) and the World Bank are both subordinate agencies of the United Nations, and China is one of the founding members of the United Nations and a permanent member of the Security Council.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.itf-oecd.org/sites/default/files/korea-road-safety.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Road Safety Country Profiles Korea 2023&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fnref1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fnref1:1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.yna.co.kr/view/ACK20121116002600881&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;韩联社.韩国交通事故死亡率居OECD之最&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fnref2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chinanews.com.cn/gj/2014/07-07/6357301.shtml&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;中新网.韩国交通事故死亡率居经合组织成员国第2位&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fnref3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.effectivecooperation.org/system/files/2021-06/gdi_delivery_note_on_improving_road_safety_for_pedestrians_in_korea.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;WorldBank, Republic of Korea’s Campaign to Bring Road Crashes to Zero&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fnref4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://m.blog.naver.com/edusns1/120212386428&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;교통사고 제로화 실천 추진방안과 원칙&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fnref5&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://irf.global/assets/pdf/Korea-MOLIT-2016-Traffic-Safety-Enforcement-Plan.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Comprehensive Measures to Reduce Traffic Accident Fatalities&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fnref6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.itf-oecd.org/sites/default/files/docs/motorway-safety-korea.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Motorway Safety in Korea&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fnref7&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.yna.co.kr/view/AEN20220609006600320&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;韩国的目标是到2027年通过先进的系统和更强的监控将交通死亡人数减半&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://itskorea.kr/downloadFile.do?fileId=FILE_000000000045623&amp;amp;fileSn=1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;제9차(2022~2026년) 국가교통안전기본계획&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fosu.cc/article/Korea%E2%80%99s-Experience-in-Governing-Traffic-Accidents#fnref8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hunan’s Oldest County: Which is it?</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/IMG_20240423_222634.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hunan’s Oldest County: Which is it?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I came across an article that claimed Chaling, Leiyang, and Liling as the three oldest counties in Hunan, with Chaling County established in 221 BC, Leiyang County in 202 BC, and Liling County during the Eastern Han Dynasty, which is 1900 years ago. However, I have serious doubts about this conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1chu-state-pioneer-in-establishing-counties-in-china&#34;&gt;1.Chu State: Pioneer in Establishing Counties in China
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although traditional Chinese historians believe that the system of counties in China began with Shang Yang’s reforms in the Qin state in 356 BC, according to archaeological evidence, the current consensus in the historical field is that the system of counties in China originated at least from the Spring and Autumn period (770-476 BC), and many scholars trace this origin back to the Western Zhou period (1046-771 BC). In any case, the Chu State (approximately 1042-223 BC) was the earliest to establish counties, and the Hunan region was developed and incorporated into the Chu State during the Warring States period (476-221 BC) until the Qin conquered the Chu. This raises a question: before 221 BC, was there a county-level region in Hunan that survived, whether it was a county of the Qin Dynasty (221-207 BC) or of the Chu State.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2changsha-jun-in-historical-texts&#34;&gt;2.Changsha Jun* in Historical Texts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;* &amp;#34;Jun&amp;#34; 郡 is a type of administrative division in ancient China, belonging directly to the state, with counties at the next level，similar to &amp;#34;prefecture&amp;#34;.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first saw this article, Changsha County immediately came to my mind. This is because, in my memory, the history of Qin Dynasty’s Hunan has almost been overturned since the discovery of the Liye Qin bamboo slips in Western Hunan. For a period of 2000 years, the history of Qin Dynasty’s Hunan was based on records such as “Records of the Grand Historian” and “Book of Han,” which were divided into Changsha Jun and Qianzhong Jun. The historical records used in Chaling County also have this background. However, the conclusion that Chaling County was established in 221 BC, directly drawn from the “Book of the Later Han Dynasty · Counties and States IV” about Changsha Jun, seems hasty, as the “Book of the Later Han Dynasty” does not confirm that Changsha Jun was established in 221 BC either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changsha Jun was established by the Qin. It is located 2,800 li ( ancient Chinese length unit) south of Luoyang. It consists of thirteen cities, with 255,854 households and 1,953,072 people. Including Linxiang, You, Chaling, Ancheng, Ling, Xiangnan, Liandao, Zhaoling, Yiyang, Xiajun, Luo, Liling, Rongling, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;——“Book of the Later Han Dynasty · Counties and States IV”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 26th year of Qin Ying Zheng (221 BC), Chaling County was established, governing the current Chaling and Yanling counties, belonging to Changsha Jun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;——“Annals of Chaling County”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423180307-1024x749.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;749&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423180307-1024x749_hu5c2846525eceeeed49dee85725932188_1124844_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423180307-1024x749_hu5c2846525eceeeed49dee85725932188_1124844_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;136&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;328px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Changsha Jun may be a later conjecture without solid evidence, according to Sima Qian’s “Records of the Grand Historian” (104 BC), in 202 BC, Emperor Liu Bang of the Han Dynasty enfeoffed Wu Rui, a founding general, as the King of Changsha, establishing the Changsha Kingdom, which lasted until 7 AD. This record from the dynastic history should be accurate. Then, the term “Changsha” must have a source. My conjecture is that if Changsha Jun did not exist, then Changsha County might have existed. After all, the Qin Dynasty had only fallen five years before the establishment of the Changsha Kingdom. So, I started searching for evidence with this conjecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3qin-dynastys-changsha-jun-debunked&#34;&gt;3.Qin Dynasty’s Changsha Jun Debunked
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, the record of Changsha Jun in the “Book of the Later Han Dynasty · Counties and States IV” has already been debunked in contemporary times; that is, there was no place called “Changsha Jun” in the Qin Dynasty. At the same time, there are also considerable doubts about the records of Qianzhong Jun, and it is highly likely that there was no place called “Qianzhong Jun” in the Qin Dynasty either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statement that the Qin set up Qianzhong and Changsha Juns is clearly wrong. The two prefectures that were actually set up were Dongting and Cangwu, and these two prefectures continued to exist throughout the Qin Dynasty but naturally disappeared during the Anti-Qin and Chu-Han Wars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423192420.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1371&#34;
	height=&#34;682&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423192420_hu294b28bbbb226b35ea4e952e64e59bc7_235109_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423192420_hu294b28bbbb226b35ea4e952e64e59bc7_235109_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;201&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;482px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Establishment Era and Political Region Evolution of Qin’s Dongting and Cangwu Jun” by Qin Zaiyuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4chu-state-established-changsha-county&#34;&gt;4.Chu State Established Changsha County
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although Changsha Jun did not exist in the Qin Dynasty, this does not mean that the history of Changsha can only be traced back to the Han Dynasty. For example, some scholars have found that as early as the Warring States period, the Chu State had already established Changsha County.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423193021.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1432&#34;
	height=&#34;1138&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423193021_hu7ac0992e0af535bd18c3fb733fa4e3e0_442323_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423193021_hu7ac0992e0af535bd18c3fb733fa4e3e0_442323_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;125&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;302px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5changsha-county-was-the-capital-of-cangwu-jun&#34;&gt;5.Changsha County was the Capital of Cangwu Jun
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;More recently, scholars have concluded through the study of Qin Dynasty bamboo slips such as Liye Qin Jian and other documents that Changsha County was the capital of Cangwu Jun during the Qin Dynasty, debunking the previously misunderstood two thousand years of Changsha Jun, which was actually Cangwu Jun.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liye Qin Jian, Huayuan Qin Du, and Yiyang Tuzishan Han Jian all mention the place name “Changsha,” indicating that the Qin Dynasty continued the Chu State’s establishment of Changsha County, which served as the capital of Cangwu Jun and continued until the early Han Dynasty. The ancient city of Qin Changsha County is located in the present Wuyi Square and surrounding areas in Changsha City, and the city site of Linxiang County in the early Han Dynasty may have been in Beijin City. It is suspected that the capital of the Wu’s Changsha Kingdom may have been moved from Beijin City to the “Linxiang Ancient City,” and after the move, the original Changsha County was renamed Linxiang County.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423195955.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1774&#34;
	height=&#34;1518&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423195955_hu3d876f467e2100202173b71ba03624e5_462241_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423195955_hu3d876f467e2100202173b71ba03624e5_462241_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;116&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;280px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6the-establishment-time-of-changsha-county&#34;&gt;6.The Establishment Time of Changsha County
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, according to the textual research on the establishment time of Changsha County cited in the article, it can be known that the time when the Chu State established Changsha County was roughly between 329 BC and 296 BC during the reign of King Huai of Chu.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, among the multiple place names examined in the paper, there is also the current Yiyang, which is still in use and belonged to the Chu State’s counties during the Warring States period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202953.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1020&#34;
	height=&#34;685&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202953_hu94d16647a4e43fb2ea2bda9238d53a36_143062_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202953_hu94d16647a4e43fb2ea2bda9238d53a36_143062_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;148&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;357px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7changsha-county-is-one-of-the-oldest-counties-in-hunan&#34;&gt;7.Changsha County is One of the Oldest Counties in Hunan
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion: Since both Changsha and Yiyang are located in northern Hunan, and the Chu State developed the Hunan region from north to south, during the Warring States period when the areas of YunMengZe and Dongting Lake were still vast&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, these two places adjacent to Dongting Lake should be the earliest counties established by the Chu State in the Hunan region.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423204539.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1237&#34;
	height=&#34;1278&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423204539_hu177b796cb6958ef5b9a7b8ba8fd3ecba_276946_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423204539_hu177b796cb6958ef5b9a7b8ba8fd3ecba_276946_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;96&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;232px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8other&#34;&gt;8.Other
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Counties Established by Chu State Regarding this, I also looked into the list of counties established by the Chu State during the Spring and Autumn period and the Warring States period that have been verified by current historical research. From the counties established by the Chu State in the Spring and Autumn period verified by scholars in the 1980s, it can be seen that the sphere of influence of the Chu State had not reached the Hunan region at that time&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and the same is true for the more than forty counties established by the Chu State in the Spring and Autumn period that have been verified in recent years.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423201354.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1122&#34;
	height=&#34;571&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423201354_hue325b079a4b9869b34e77833898f27c5_303956_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423201354_hue325b079a4b9869b34e77833898f27c5_303956_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;196&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;471px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, from the counties established by the Chu State in the Warring States period that have been verified by scholars, no place names that correspond to the current cities and counties in various parts of Hunan have been found either.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202824.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1363&#34;
	height=&#34;768&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202824_hucc6992c8235bb784a84b919926488efb_179358_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202824_hucc6992c8235bb784a84b919926488efb_179358_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;425px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li Fengxian: “Research on the Year, Boundary, and County Establishment of Qin Dynasty’s prefectures during the Warring States Period.” Ph.D. dissertation, Qinghai Normal University, 2023. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhao Yuxuan: “Examination of ‘Changsha’ County in Qin and Han Dynasty Bamboo and Silk Documents.” “Documents Unearthed.” First issue, 2024. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xu Shaohua: “Eight Comments on the Places Mentioned in the Baoshan Chu Slips.” “Journal of Chinese Historical Geography.” Vol. 4, 1996. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhou Hongwei: “Another Discussion on the Historical Process of Dongting Lake’s Changes.” “Journal of Chinese Historical Geography.” Vol. 20, No. 2, 2005. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang Kuan: “On the Nature of the County System of the Chu State during the Spring and Autumn Period.” “Research on Chinese History.” No. 4, 1981. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chen Jian: “The Origin and Transformation of the County System in the Pre-Qin Period.” Ph.D. dissertation, Jilin University, 2019. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zheng Yifan: “A Preliminary Study on the Counties of the Chu State during the Warring States Period.” Master’s thesis, Wuhan University, 2017. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
