<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Cloud on Hyruo Blog</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/tags/cloud/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Cloud on Hyruo Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>by Hyruo, All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hyruo.com/en/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Very lucky to registered an Oracle Cloud service account</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/successfully-registered-an-oracle-cloud-service-account/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/successfully-registered-an-oracle-cloud-service-account/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/successfully-registered-an-oracle-cloud-service-account/images/R-C-1.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Very lucky to registered an Oracle Cloud service account" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, I had been using Alibaba Cloud servers registered with a promotional offer, with a configuration of 2 CPU cores and 2GB of memory. However, since that product is about to expire and I cannot continue to renew it with the promotional offer, I don&amp;rsquo;t plan on using it anymore. So, during this time, I have been searching on the Nodeseek forum to find a cloud server with a suitable price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/successfully-registered-an-oracle-cloud-service-account/images/103-1P3221HU2P6-1024x576.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;576&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/successfully-registered-an-oracle-cloud-service-account/images/103-1P3221HU2P6-1024x576_hubc8eec448d5d2f3ff33ac72025455ba4_105328_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/successfully-registered-an-oracle-cloud-service-account/images/103-1P3221HU2P6-1024x576_hubc8eec448d5d2f3ff33ac72025455ba4_105328_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alibaba cloud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, I saw someone on the forum post a promotional offer for a cloud server operated by an individual seller. They were offering a cloud server with 1 CPU core and 1GB of memory for only 1 Chinese Yuan per month. However, many comments below mentioned that these types of cloud servers have extremely poor performance and may become unusable after a while. They suggested trying to register for an Oracle Cloud service account instead, as they offer free cloud servers as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I decided to give registering for an Oracle Cloud service account a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first registered, I entered my personal information and contact address in English and attempted to verify using my Visa credit card from China Construction Bank. As expected, the verification failed. Then, I searched online and found many discussions where people mentioned that registering for an Oracle Cloud service account is a mysterious problem because there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be any consistent pattern. Some even mentioned trying for one or two years without success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a &amp;ldquo;give it a try&amp;rdquo; attitude, on my second attempt, I decided to abandon any clever methods. I directly registered using Chinese information, provided the most common QQ email account in China, and chose a server location far from my place, in Hyderabad, India. For verification, I used my Mastercard from Guangfa Bank. Miraculously, it was successful this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when I shared this information on the forum, many people still didn&amp;rsquo;t believe it. Orz.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nodeseek.com/post-33594-5#45&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.nodeseek.com/post-33594-5#45&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/successfully-registered-an-oracle-cloud-service-account/images/Screenshot_20231031_195614.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;880&#34;
	height=&#34;288&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/successfully-registered-an-oracle-cloud-service-account/images/Screenshot_20231031_195614_hu8ad8839687008891afb5a84d2feaf527_35252_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/successfully-registered-an-oracle-cloud-service-account/images/Screenshot_20231031_195614_hu8ad8839687008891afb5a84d2feaf527_35252_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;305&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;733px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it seems 1 physical core and 1 virtual thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oracle Cloud service accounts provide two types of free servers by default: traditional x86 servers and ARM servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my blog website requires minimal resources, I chose to use a 1 CPU core and 1GB memory x86 server. I installed the Ubuntu system and BT panel and set up Litespeed, PHP, and MySQL. It looks promising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I have time, I&amp;rsquo;ll try using Oracle&amp;rsquo;s free 4 CPU core and 24GB memory ARM server to build a Mastodon application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
