<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Law on Hyruo Blog</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/tags/law/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Law on Hyruo Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>by Hyruo, All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hyruo.com/en/tags/law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Listening to the teachings of a university professor again after 16 years</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/university.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Listening to the teachings of a university professor again after 16 years" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;On May 13th, the Ministry of Education issued a public notice, indicating its intention to agree to the proposal by Foshan University of Science and Technology to change its name to Foshan University. This is the fifth renaming application by Foshan University of Science and Technology, and it seems that the matter has finally been settled. Initially, at the end of 2019, during the third renaming application to “Guangdong University of Science and Technology,” it seemed almost certain, as the Guangdong Provincial Department of Education had already publicized it and submitted it to the Ministry of Education for approval. However, due to the impact of the pandemic, the renaming inspection originally planned for the spring of 2020 did not proceed as scheduled, and this delay lasted for three years. By 2023, the Ministry of Education had introduced new naming rules for universities, making it almost impossible for Foshan University of Science and Technology to be approved for renaming as Guangdong University of Science and Technology. Consequently, when resubmitting the application, the school proposed the name “Foshan University,” which was actually one of the school’s previous names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/foshanuniversity.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2507&#34;
	height=&#34;1706&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/foshanuniversity_hu5438825b9b6d1014226d20d231e650c2_651580_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/foshanuniversity_hu5438825b9b6d1014226d20d231e650c2_651580_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FoshanUniversity&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;146&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;352px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-sudden-arrangement-for-a-class-reunion&#34;&gt;A sudden arrangement for a class reunion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like a stone stirring up a thousand ripples, the familiar Foshan University was finally returning, reviving the long-silent class and alumni groups. Consequently, a classmate proposed a weekend dinner gathering to celebrate this wonderful event. Due to the sudden nature of the event, only eight classmates nearby Foshan were able to attend, and one person couldn’t make it to the dinner due to a last-minute matter. However, to everyone’s surprise, what started as a joke in the class group ended up with the classmate who organized the event actually inviting the former dean of the college. This respected dean had also taught our “Jurisprudence” course during the 2007-2008 academic year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5191.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1612&#34;
	height=&#34;1208&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5191_hu052b76b500c3b9cae2fc291af821093c_1218854_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5191_hu052b76b500c3b9cae2fc291af821093c_1218854_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;listening-to-the-teacher-lecture-again&#34;&gt;Listening to the teacher lecture again
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For almost the first three hours of the dinner, it was mostly the teacher talking, or us students asking questions and the teacher answering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-teacher-himself&#34;&gt;About the teacher himself
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher started with his experiences of traveling abroad after retiring in January this year and talked about his personal journey from starting to teach at Foshan University in 1992, through its renaming to Foshan University of Science and Technology, and the multiple attempts to revert to a university status. Especially after 2017, he shared his own health challenges and how, as a scholar, he conducted interdisciplinary research on his condition, overcame it, and took care of his health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1744&#34;
	height=&#34;892&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;195&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;469px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-childrens-education&#34;&gt;About children’s education
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the dinner, the teacher spent a long time talking about his own experiences and those of other teachers at the college in educating their children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;he-emphasized-the-current-importance-of-the-high-school-entrance-exam-zhongkao&#34;&gt;He emphasized the current importance of the high school entrance exam (Zhongkao)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which he believes is now more significant than the college entrance exam (Gaokao). Since the late 1970s, the Gaokao has been considered the most important exam in China, with countless people relying on it to change their destinies. However, in recent years, due to the saturation of college enrollment, the university admission rate has approached 90%, and for most students attending ordinary high schools, even if they “lie flat,” they basically have no worries about not being able to attend university. Overall, the importance of the Gaokao is decreasing. But at the same time, due to the “general vocational分流” policy, during the process of entering high school, more than 55% of junior high school students in many places can only attend secondary vocational technical schools after graduation, and it is basically impossible for these schools to progress to ordinary universities. In this situation, if a child’s academic performance is not ideal in primary and junior high school, they may lose the opportunity to attend an ordinary university and can only take the vocational technical university route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;he-talked-about-his-methods-of-educating-his-children&#34;&gt;He talked about his methods of educating his children
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both he and his wife are highly educated, but they also faced difficulties in educating their children. He summed it up with the phrase &lt;strong&gt;“parents are not good at teaching their children (academics).”&lt;/strong&gt; Parents can still play a decisive role in their children’s growth in life and other aspects, but their role in learning is very limited. He emphasized the importance of teachers and schools in improving children’s academic performance and cited a series of examples from his surroundings. He hoped that we would create a relaxed family atmosphere for our children, send them to the best schools within our means, and handle relationships with teachers well. He advised that we should mainly rely on schools and classrooms to enhance our children’s learning ability, rather than relying on family or off-campus tutoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;he-discussed-the-issue-of-childrens-educational-planning&#34;&gt;He discussed the issue of children’s educational planning.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a law major himself and with his wife studying medicine, he pointed out that fields like law, especially medicine, and computer science are highly competitive and require continuous learning and updating of knowledge to keep up with the times. Even in computer science, it’s quite possible to be unable to compete with younger people in their thirties and forties due to the physical and familial demands that come with age, making it easy to fall behind in the race for new technology. He stressed the importance of guiding children to develop hobbies and interests based on their personalities and interests, rather than just following trends. The teacher has only one daughter, who is almost our age. After graduating with a bachelor’s degree from a top art academy in China, she pursued a master’s degree at a well-ranked university in the United States, and later, a Ph.D. After completing her doctorate, she became a teacher at a domestic art academy and quickly grew to become one of the youngest professors there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1001914.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;2250&#34;
	height=&#34;1500&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1001914_hua8053f0bd34c4ab00b1b9d33025e98fd_197404_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1001914_hua8053f0bd34c4ab00b1b9d33025e98fd_197404_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Education&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-development-of-the-university&#34;&gt;About the development of the university
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As one of the earliest faculty members with a doctoral degree in law at our alma mater, the teacher has long served as the university’s legal advisor and is aware of many secrets behind the school’s development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-development-of-a-university-is-inseparable-from-the-help-of-influential-people&#34;&gt;The development of a university is inseparable from the help of influential people.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the course of the development of Foshan University and later Foshan University of Science and Technology, the support of key figures was indispensable. In the early stages, two mayors of Foshan City, Yu Fei and Lu Ruihua, played significant roles. Without the attention and support of these two mayors, Foshan University would not have been established in 1986. &lt;em&gt;(Yu Fei: Served as the Vice-Governor of Guangdong Province but was expelled from the Communist Party in 1998 due to his children’s seeking private interests; Lu Ruihua: Served as the Governor of Guangdong Province. )&lt;/em&gt;
In the last 10 years, Foshan University of Science and Technology has skyrocketed from outside the top 500 national university rankings to 219th nationwide, thanks in large part to the assistance of the former Secretary of the Guangdong Provincial Party Committee, Hu Chunhua. As a member of the Central Political Bureau, Hu Chunhua visited the school three times after 2015, proposed the goal of building Foshan University of Science and Technology into a high-level science and technology university in Guangdong, and the Guangdong provincial government allocated 500 million yuan specifically for support. Since then, the school’s development has entered the fast lane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5194.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2106&#34;
	height=&#34;842&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5194_hueda0fd19d53824080503c29a507fa0d3_139141_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5194_hueda0fd19d53824080503c29a507fa0d3_139141_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;250&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;600px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-development-of-a-university-cannot-be-separated-from-government-support&#34;&gt;The development of a university cannot be separated from government support.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since public universities dominate in China, the development of universities is driven by administrative resources, and the richness of these resources determines the height of university development. Decisive factors include the level of education and the allocation of funds, both of which are decided by administrative organs. As a university founded by the Foshan municipal government, Foshan University has inherent shortcomings because, compared to the financial strength of national or provincial governments, a prefecture-level city like Foshan falls far short. Moreover, although Foshan’s economic output ranks among the top 20 in the country, as an ordinary prefecture-level city in the Pearl River Delta, under the three-tier fiscal structure (about 50% of income goes to the central government, and of the remaining 50% tax, another 50% goes to the province, leaving about 25% actually retained), the financial resources that the Foshan municipal government can dispose of are far less than those of first-tier cities like Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou, and Shenzhen, as well as other sub-provincial cities and general provincial capitals. For example, the fiscal budget expenditure for Foshan University of Science and Technology in 2024 is 1.8 billion yuan, while the fiscal budget expenditure for the Foshan municipal government during the same period is 24 billion yuan, accounting for 7.5% of the total. Nearby universities such as Shenzhen University and Southern University of Science and Technology have fiscal expenditures of over 6 billion yuan, which is an amount that the Foshan city government, with a fiscal budget of 24 billion at the city level, cannot afford. Fortunately, Foshan University of Science and Technology is currently not large in scale, and if calculated by the per-student expenditure on funds, it ranks among the top in Guangdong’s higher education institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-development-of-a-university-needs-to-go-with-the-flow&#34;&gt;The development of a university needs to go with the flow.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In discussing the school’s development, the teacher specifically mentioned the construction of doctoral programs, which is one of the two biggest projects the school has undertaken in recent years, the other being the “renaming to a university” project. Currently, there are about 400 universities in China with doctoral programs. Although Foshan University of Science and Technology has seen its ranking climb continuously, the lack of a doctoral program has always been a major concern, and this has even led to the university’s president position being vacant for three years. The main reason is that the Foshan municipal government hopes to find an expert at the “Academician” level to serve as the president, and it is almost impossible to find an Academician willing to be the president of a school without a doctoral program. In this round of applying for a doctoral program, the school has put in a great deal of effort, especially the party committee secretary who has used all his skills to advance the discipline construction, focusing on mechanical engineering, a field he is highly proficient in. As of now, the application for a doctoral program has reached the most critical stage. In the list of Guangdong universities applying for doctoral program construction published by the Guangdong Provincial Department of Education, Foshan University of Science and Technology’s mechanical engineering doctoral program ranked first among 234 disciplines in 32 universities across the province, and veterinary and animal husbandry programs also ranked among the top five. It can be said that this is the closest the school has been to securing a doctoral program since it became a doctoral degree-granting institution in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5195.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1888&#34;
	height=&#34;732&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5195_hu935cfa788b6b52a3c4d88f8d40a84db9_345000_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5195_hu935cfa788b6b52a3c4d88f8d40a84db9_345000_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;257&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;619px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-personal-growth&#34;&gt;About personal growth
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With his 32 years of work experience, the teacher shared several key aspects that we should focus on during our professional development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;avoid-speaking-ill-of-others-when-they-are-not-present&#34;&gt;Avoid speaking ill of others when they are not present.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher emphasized that Chinese society is heavily influenced by personal relationships, and we should never speak ill of others, regardless of how much we may dislike them or have had conflicts with them. Even a decade ago, we might not have fully appreciated the importance of this advice, but today, we deeply agree with it. Numerous examples around us confirm this point. However, as human beings, we have our limitations, and sometimes we inadvertently express our true feelings, leading to unforeseen consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dont-be-too-rigid&#34;&gt;Don’t be too rigid.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher cited several examples from his own experience, advising us to be flexible in handling work relationships and not to be overly pedantic or inflexible. Wearing the necessary masks and disguises is essential for self-protection, which is the foundation of growth. Throughout our development, we will encounter various setbacks and unavoidable conflicts of interest, but we should still approach them with a relaxed and optimistic attitude. Harmonious workplace relationships are crucial for our own well-being. We should not view potential competitors as adversaries but rather as companions, as work is only an eight-hour-a-day matter, while life is a lifelong journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;learn-to-be-content-and-embrace-ordinariness&#34;&gt;Learn to be content and embrace ordinariness.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher used examples of students and leaders he has helped and supported over the years to advise us that as we enter middle age, we should start to learn satisfaction and contentment, and not overly concern ourselves with personal gains and losses. After all, as we reach middle age, the harmony of the family, the growth of our children, and our health are often more important than personal advancement. Especially within the system, the time most people can shine in their careers typically does not exceed 15 years. In the marathon of life, there can still be two to three decades after retirement. Even if some have held high positions and had power for a time, facing decades of retirement, if there are problems with the family, children, or their own health, it would all have been in vain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1744&#34;
	height=&#34;892&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;195&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;469px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-legal-work-in-law&#34;&gt;About legal work in law
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a senior law professor, the teacher offered some sound advice and suggestions for the work and development of several of us students based on his own experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-judicial-work&#34;&gt;Regarding judicial work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Including myself, two of us present have worked in judicial authorities. Drawing on his long-term experience serving part-time in the National People’s Congress, the teacher offered two suggestions for those of us engaged in judicial work: First, the current workload in judicial authorities is generally high, with many cases and few people, a situation that is expected to persist for a long time, and the reward may not be proportional to the effort. For women, especially, who often have to invest more in family and childcare, choosing a career in the judiciary requires careful consideration. Second, within the judiciary, there is a significant level of internal competition, with a concentration of highly educated individuals, complex factions, and young and female leaders often having higher aspirations. It is important to know one’s limits, avoid confrontation, and advance steadily with modesty and caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-arbitration-work&#34;&gt;Regarding arbitration work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the students present works in an arbitration institution. Based on his experience as an arbitrator, the teacher advised that students working in arbitration institutions should strengthen communication with law firms, businesses, and other industry organizations, improve communication skills, and develop a network of contacts. Outside of work, they should continuously study relevant trade laws, international trade management, and arbitration rules to maintain advanced and in-depth professional knowledge. However, he suggested that it might not be necessary to pursue a doctoral degree, as we have all been working for over a decade and have missed the optimal time to advance our careers with a doctoral degree. Moreover, at our age, with the pressures of work and life, the benefits of obtaining a PhD may not be significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-notary-work&#34;&gt;Regarding notary work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two students present work in notary institutions. The teacher, based on his experience, put forward several points: First, the notary industry is relatively closed, with a smaller number of notaries among legal professions, and the overall development space is narrow. Second, in recent years, the notary industry has been continuously promoting restructuring, with some notary institutions transitioning from traditional public institutions to social welfare organizations similar to law firms. In this process, the personal networks and channels established become extremely important, as work income will be directly related to the volume of business. Third, the notary industry is closely related to the legal profession, and it is important to pay attention to interactions with lawyers, guiding clients to resolve many common disputes through notarization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/notary.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1200&#34;
	height=&#34;800&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/notary_hu7d6fd75e6699370713a188194a904a94_107780_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/notary_hu7d6fd75e6699370713a188194a904a94_107780_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Notary&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-lawyer-practice&#34;&gt;Regarding lawyer practice.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;One student is a practicing lawyer, and the teacher himself has also served as a part-time lawyer, and I also work part-time as a public service lawyer. Because of concerns that continuing to practice law after retirement might affect retirement benefits, the teacher canceled his part-time lawyer’s license upon retirement and did not apply to convert it to a general lawyer’s practice certificate. The teacher offered several suggestions for legal practice, including the importance of maintaining client relationships, how to expand one’s network and case sources, and the need for lifelong learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-corporate-work&#34;&gt;Regarding corporate work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two students work in central enterprises and large private enterprises in the IT and internet industry. As they are both female and have personal or family health issues, the teacher suggested that they should pay attention to their own and their family’s health while maintaining a positive attitude towards life and a proactive learning mindset. They should keep abreast of industry trends and maintain their level of expertise in law, seeking development opportunities through their comparative advantages in non-legal work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-work-within-the-system&#34;&gt;Regarding work within the system.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Including myself, out of the 7 students present, 5 of us are effectively working in “governmental, institutional, and enterprise units” within the system. The teacher offered a lot of opinions and suggestions on working within the system, also sharing many of his observations from working in the local system in Foshan. As some of the content is sensitive, it has not been written out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5192.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1612&#34;
	height=&#34;1208&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5192_hu82f2d5ee5588d27505d5c94102ba66cc_1060195_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5192_hu82f2d5ee5588d27505d5c94102ba66cc_1060195_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This gathering was indeed a rare opportunity. We arrived at 4 pm in the afternoon, and while waiting for the teacher and other classmates to arrive, we played the card game “Guan Dang” (Gentlemen’s Agreement) as we chatted, with one of our classmates working at a central enterprise saying, “It’s like not eating at all if you don’t play ‘Guan Dang’.” During the meal, we listened to the teacher “lecture” almost throughout, and the teacher even specifically commented on the phenomenon of “Guan Dang.” After the teacher left early due to time constraints, we chatted informally until almost 11 pm before dispersing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-is-no-template-for-choosing-the-path-of-life&#34;&gt;There is no template for choosing the path of life
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The eight classmates who attended the reunion had all graduated from the same class but later embarked on completely different paths in life. If we extend this group to the entire class of over 40 students, their paths become even more diverse and complex. In general, however, we all stood at the same starting point at the same time, seeking different lives. The vast differences that followed may have been more related to each family’s and personal choices. Even among those who pursued the same profession, different classmates took different paths. For example, in our class, four students became ordinary lawyers, one of whom has been practicing law in Foshan for 13 years and has had a smooth career development; another student who did not attend the dinner began practicing law only 10 years after graduation and is still in the early stages; one student who practices law in Shenzhen opened their own law firm early on and has recently opened branches in other places; and another student who practices law in Chengdu pursued a master’s degree after graduation and initially chose to practice in Shenzhen before moving to Chengdu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-advantage-brought-by-information-gaps-is-gradually-decreasing&#34;&gt;The advantage brought by information gaps is gradually decreasing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we graduated, information gaps were still a significant factor contributing to differences in life paths. Back then, in our class of over 40 students, only a few chose to take the civil service exam or participate in campus recruitment by enterprises and institutions, and only a few decided to become lawyers. It was only after entering the workforce that more people gradually realized the importance of their undergraduate degree in law. Including myself, many of us entered judicial and administrative organs through the civil service exam in the following years. It was not until 2017, when short video platforms began to thrive, that the advantages of employment in systems such as government agencies and state-owned enterprises were fully exposed, and this was only gradually recognized by the public. At this point, the difficulty of entering these professions compared to when we graduated from university had become unimaginable. For example, when I applied for a civil service position in the Pearl River Delta, there were only 13 applicants for the same position, with only 8 actually taking the exam. With no preparation at all, I even didn’t complete a complete practice test, and yet I managed to score 110 points (out of a total of 200 for two subjects) to become the first-ranked candidate, and was successfully employed. Every time I think back, I feel extremely lucky, with more luck than actual ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-are-no-shortcuts-in-the-marathon-of-life&#34;&gt;There are no shortcuts in the marathon of life
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher used his rich personal experiences and insights to illustrate how individuals navigate this era. In the 1980s, when university students were still a “rare species,” the teacher, with his strong character and self-discipline, successfully enrolled in university and pursued a master’s degree. He then went south to Foshan University to pioneer, gradually advancing from lecturer to associate professor and then to professor, and serving as the dean of the college. Along the way, he pursued a doctoral degree and engaged in postdoctoral research at top universities in the industry, providing himself and his family with ample material and spiritual wealth. In the second century of struggle, in this era widely considered highly competitive, I believe that this era still offers opportunities for many to change their destinies. However, success can only be achieved through even greater effort, a more positive attitude, and unwavering perseverance. After all, the negative emotions of this era are already enough, with voices of “lying flat” and “tittytainment” products ubiquitous. Only by adhering to one’s original aspiration can one live up to oneself, one’s family, and this era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1164572.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2250&#34;
	height=&#34;1500&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1164572_hu004c9b28559f5fa727659b387248f524_688245_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1164572_hu004c9b28559f5fa727659b387248f524_688245_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Visited two college classmates who are lawyers</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_220820.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Visited two college classmates who are lawyers" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much contact with many friends from out of town in recent years. Taking advantage of the weekend, I visited two college classmates who are lawyers in Shenzhen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204849-1024x767.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;767&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204849-1024x767_hu196bde671f564b6f8b6a444bc567a7eb_136394_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204849-1024x767_hu196bde671f564b6f8b6a444bc567a7eb_136394_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of lawyer&amp;rsquo;s office&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In China, graduates with a major in law have several main employment channels, including courts, procuratorates, administrative law enforcement agencies, and law firms. Among them, law firms are usually the most popular choice of employment because they do not require participation in the highly challenging civil service examination. In our class, out of 40 classmates, seven of them joined law firms after graduation. However, two of them later switched to government legal departments, and now there are five remaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_205050-767x1024.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;767&#34;
	height=&#34;1024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_205050-767x1024_hu8c88828db650cf97c213f9b3e56112fe_98327_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_205050-767x1024_hu8c88828db650cf97c213f9b3e56112fe_98327_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;74&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;179px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a lawyer is a rapidly growing profession that demands high individual capabilities. Of my two classmates who are lawyers in Shenzhen, one became a partner in a small law firm due to obtaining the lawyer&amp;rsquo;s practicing certificate early. Currently, the law firm has around ten lawyers. The other classmate joined a very large law firm, which was recognized as an excellent law firm nationwide in 2021. It has approximately 100 lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204939-702x1024.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;702&#34;
	height=&#34;1024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204939-702x1024_hub60023c9ac623c56f9e5ebbefe5a33fb_86549_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204939-702x1024_hub60023c9ac623c56f9e5ebbefe5a33fb_86549_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;68&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;164px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a larger firm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the communication with my two classmates, I had three main thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the current year of 2023, the legal profession still generally relies on personal family background. If individuals have good social connections and a certain amount of capital accumulation, pursuing a career in law can be relatively smooth. However, if personal family conditions are difficult, it is very challenging to establish oneself as a lawyer in a major city. It requires several times more effort than others to have a chance of achieving some degree of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legal industry in China is undergoing a significant transformation. The traditional model where individual lawyers take on cases as independent agents (essentially being their own bosses) is being squeezed by the &amp;ldquo;salary system&amp;rdquo; employed by large law firms. In this model, lawyers work as employees of the law firm and receive relatively fixed compensation. Currently, the largest law firm in China has 15,000 lawyers, and even smaller law firms are actively expanding and moving towards corporate operation models. Most young lawyers work for senior lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legal profession in large cities has become highly competitive. For example, in the city of Shenzhen where these two classmates are located, there are already over 20,000 lawyers, with a ratio of 1 lawyer per 1,000 residents, similar to the situation in the UK. Due to the relatively low litigation costs in China, a large portion of civil litigation cases do not require the involvement of lawyers. In criminal cases, if the defendant cannot afford a lawyer, the government will provide a designated lawyer for free defense. This significantly suppresses the demand for legal services. As a result, the income of lawyers in China cannot be compared to countries like the UK and the US. With more people in the profession, the share of the income pie for each individual becomes smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A wonderful experience working in the procuratorate</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/a-wonderful-experience-working-in-the-procuratorate/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/a-wonderful-experience-working-in-the-procuratorate/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/a-wonderful-experience-working-in-the-procuratorate/images/IMG_20230909_184227.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A wonderful experience working in the procuratorate" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was very honored to go to the procuratorate of a city as the leader of a working group to carry out a special work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our working group consists of 15 people, including senior judges, prosecutors and legal professionals. The main task of the working group is to conduct a comprehensive inspection and evaluation of criminal justice cases handled by courts, procuratorates and public security bureaus throughout the city last year, as well as administrative law enforcement cases handled by government administrative departments such as the Natural Resources Bureau, the Ecology and Environment Bureau, and the Health Bureau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first time working in the procuratorate, and I am deeply impressed by the good working atmosphere and advanced office facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/a-wonderful-experience-working-in-the-procuratorate/images/IMG_20230909_184227-1024x856.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;856&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/a-wonderful-experience-working-in-the-procuratorate/images/IMG_20230909_184227-1024x856_huea44a0ac4efc01c9bcbb5e6e91897297_197278_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/a-wonderful-experience-working-in-the-procuratorate/images/IMG_20230909_184227-1024x856_huea44a0ac4efc01c9bcbb5e6e91897297_197278_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;119&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;287px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Procuratorate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the Constitution of the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China, the main duties of the procuratorate are to supervise the implementation of laws, including civil, criminal and administrative proceedings, and have the same status as courts in state institutions. At the same time, the procuratorate is also one of the main participants in criminal proceedings, responsible for supervising the criminal filing and investigation work of the public security organs, prosecuting criminal cases on behalf of the state, supervising the criminal trial work of the courts, and proposing public interest litigation on behalf of the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2018 reform of state institutions, the functions of the procuratorate were somewhat weakened. After 2018, most of the investigation responsibilities for job-related crimes were transferred to the National Supervision Commission, and the procuratorate only retained the investigation duties for job-related crimes committed by judicial personnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, I feel that the procuratorate is a very serious office space, all prosecutors are very smart and intelligent, they are very rigorous and serious in their work, and they are very well managed on many details, otherwise it is difficult to win in the lawyer&amp;rsquo;s nitpicky defense. During this inspection, we saw that most of the criminal cases charged by the procuratorate, including the charges, criminal facts and sentencing recommendations, can be accepted by the court, and more than 80% of criminal suspects can actively admit guilt. The vast majority of criminal cases with unclear facts and insufficient evidence have been rejected by the procuratorate and cannot enter the court trial stage; In a small number of cases, after the prosecution is instituted and before the court begins, because the lawyer discovers that there are obvious problems in the case, the procuratorate will also withdraw the prosecution or modify the prosecution. In the end, less than 10 percent of the verdicts in cases are inconsistent with the content of the procuratorate&amp;rsquo;s prosecution, and once such a case occurs, the procuratorate has special departments and personnel to study these problems, and through repeated study and discussion, try to avoid the continuation of such problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becoming a judge or prosecutor is a dream that all of us legal professionals have, but because of the nature of my current job, this idea may never come.I have to say this is a regret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/a-wonderful-experience-working-in-the-procuratorate/images/IMG_20230909_213521.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1424&#34;
	height=&#34;2256&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/a-wonderful-experience-working-in-the-procuratorate/images/IMG_20230909_213521_hu8a964104023975830c0cb29bacc7c009_341374_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/a-wonderful-experience-working-in-the-procuratorate/images/IMG_20230909_213521_hu8a964104023975830c0cb29bacc7c009_341374_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;63&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;151px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>After 11 years, returning to work at the court again</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230904_222922-scaled.jpg" alt="Featured image of post After 11 years, returning to work at the court again" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;By chance I had an opportunity return to work at the court recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though it&amp;rsquo;s not a permanent position, but rather a temporary job lasting only a month, it&amp;rsquo;s still a valuable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my fourth time working at a court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time was during my sophomore year of college when I interned at a district court near our university for a month, primarily involved in judgment execution work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second time was during my senior year of college when I chose to intern at another district court near our university for three months, also focusing on judgment execution work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last month before graduating from college, I started working at a district court in the city where the university is located (the city has a total of five district courts), where I experienced the first part of my career, which lasted about 18 months. The first three months were the most painful period, because my salary was only 1,700 yuan, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to buy a BlackBerry phone. After that, I passed the exam to become a judicial assistant, although the salary is only about 5,000 yuan, but with other benefits, the total annual income can reach the level of 100,000 yuan.During this time, because of the nature of being an assistant, I did not need to compete with other colleagues in my work, but only needed to complete my own work tasks, so I had a very happy time for more than a year, and it also made me deeply love court work. This period of my career at the Court was also the happiest period of my work and life in all these years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230905_123058-scaled.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1809&#34;
	height=&#34;2560&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230905_123058-scaled_hu7490eb246b6dca1f991abc6f2337c350_338568_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230905_123058-scaled_hu7490eb246b6dca1f991abc6f2337c350_338568_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my work contract from 2011 when I worked at the court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it has been eleven years since I last worked at the court, returning this time felt very familiar and nostalgic. For example, due to the confidentiality requirements of many court tasks, the court utilizes a dedicated internal network. As soon as I arrived at the court this time, I immediately found the internal website I used during my previous work at the court and was pleasantly surprised to discover an electronic magazine that I had edited back then. However, this is the only trace I could find of my past work at that court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/yuedu-1024x379.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;379&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/yuedu-1024x379_hu9d8859bfe70fc64091fda2de0301579a_332508_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/yuedu-1024x379_hu9d8859bfe70fc64091fda2de0301579a_332508_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;270&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;648px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The electronic magazine that I edited while working at another court in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been quite eventful in the eleven years since I left the court in 2012. Returning to the court has allowed me to see many issues that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of before. There are significant differences between the court I had in mind and the reality I encountered, mainly in a few aspects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court work environment tends to be more isolated. Due to the relatively independent nature of court work, court personnel often have limited interactions with other government departments and members of society. Their perspectives and problem-solving approaches may differ from those of the general public, leading to a certain degree of social functioning deficit. For example, during this experience, we discovered that some judges were sued by their neighbors due to their inability to handle neighborhood disputes effectively. Others lacked social experience when dealing with simple litigation cases arising from family, school, or workplace conflicts due to their limited participation in social activities. Additionally, some young judges, who assumed judicial roles in their early twenties, lacked personal experience in relationships, marriage, and divorce but had to mediate divorce cases for others, resulting in complaints from the parties involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a higher proportion of women working in the courts. In China, due to law being categorized as a humanities discipline, there tend to be more female students studying law, while male students mostly choose science and engineering majors. As a result, there is a higher proportion of women working in the courts. In the four courts I have experienced, the proportion of female staff is generally above 60%. In the court I recently visited, among employees born after 1980, approximately 70% are women. It&amp;rsquo;s commonly believed that women are more inclined towards sensitivity in terms of personality, while men lean towards rationality. However, law itself leans towards rationality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapid growth of litigation cases in the courts is indeed a concerning trend. The current efficiency of the courts, with an average case processing time of 60 days for civil cases and 20 days for criminal cases, has contributed to this increase. Additionally, the low cost of litigation, where most cases are charged at 1% of the claim amount and many cases don&amp;rsquo;t require hiring a lawyer, has made the process more accessible to individuals. It has become as simple as submitting pre-litigation documents and evidence to the court, akin to applying for a visa.These convenient conditions have led to a significant surge in litigation cases in the past decade. In my city, for example, there has been an average of one litigation case for every 30 people annually. It seems that citizens&amp;rsquo; initial inclination when encountering disputes is to file a lawsuit in court.While the accessibility and efficiency of the court system are positive aspects, the rapid growth of litigation cases also highlights the importance of alternative dispute resolution methods. Encouraging mediation and other forms of dispute resolution can help alleviate the burden on the courts and provide more flexible and tailored solutions for the parties involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese courts have implemented numerous performance indicators. Prior to the year 2000, there were significant incidents of wrongful convictions and miscarriages of justice in Chinese courts, which had a profound negative impact. In the past decade or so, the higher courts have introduced a myriad of performance indicators to ensure the fairness of judgments and balance the judicial process. However, this has also led to a phenomenon where judges prioritize meeting these indicators above all else during case proceedings.For example, in order to curb the rapid growth of litigation cases, the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court set a target of reducing the number of cases by 5% this year. As a result, many courts have established thresholds at the filing stage, requiring most cases to undergo mediation by judges before proceeding to litigation. If successful, the cases can be resolved without going to trial. However, in reality, the workload of judges has not decreased. On the contrary, the difficulty of mediating many cases has resulted in a significant waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230904_222922-1024x576.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;576&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230904_222922-1024x576_hu65412cd9ce3469eaa70f502867ba3b96_135164_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230904_222922-1024x576_hu65412cd9ce3469eaa70f502867ba3b96_135164_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View from the court&amp;rsquo;s office&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the court is still a highly desirable place of employment. The working atmosphere is harmonious, and the infrastructure and office environment are excellent. However, all of this will come to an end as my current assignment concludes. Fortunately, I will be starting a new job at a different prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s office next month. In China, the courts and prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s offices are relatively independent departments, and they share many similarities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230904_223034-1024x576.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;576&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230904_223034-1024x576_hu8fd9f2122e6a92921b9240250b100c14_112257_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230904_223034-1024x576_hu8fd9f2122e6a92921b9240250b100c14_112257_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The library in the Court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230905_122542-1024x789.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;789&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230905_122542-1024x789_hu3e43d23b294902276bcb48972ca94cf7_162741_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/after-11-years-returning-to-work-at-the-court-again/images/IMG_20230905_122542-1024x789_hu3e43d23b294902276bcb48972ca94cf7_162741_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;129&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;311px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The identification card I used while working at the court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Rule of law and institutions</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/rule-of-law-and-institutions/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/rule-of-law-and-institutions/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/rule-of-law-and-institutions/images/146362_ec6ba4c5fe453330bdafc1bc881690ef-jpg-1.webp" alt="Featured image of post Rule of law and institutions" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having nothing to do today, I found a copy of the political gains and losses in China written by Qian Mu from the bookshelf. The content of the book was written in the 1950s. The usage of some historical terms is slightly different from that in contemporary China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It used to be regarded as feudalism, but in the modern division, the Qin Dynasty is the beginning of feudalism. For example, in the book, in order to solve the contradiction between private land ownership and taxation, the Han Dynasty mentioned that Dong Zhongshu restricted the large-scale concentration of land, and Wang Mang Then the method of equalizing the fields was directly used, which resulted in failure. Wang Mang&amp;rsquo;s land equalization was not the only one in history. The Revolution of 1911 also proposed the establishment of the Republic of China and the equalization of land rights. Of course, he did not actually do it. In the end, this great problem of thousands of years was completely realized in the Deng Xiaoping era, and the corresponding poll tax and agricultural tax were also completely ended in the Wen Jiabao era. This may also be after the founding of New China. The biggest change to our basic institutions in 2,000 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We summarize the above-mentioned economic policies of the Han Dynasty. For industry and commerce, it is close to advocating the so-called restraint of capital. In terms of land rent for farmers, it has also achieved light labor and light taxes, but it has not equalized land rights. . During the reign of Emperor Wu of the Han Dynasty, Dong Zhongshu once advocated the policy of restricting land. Even if the acres of land in the country cannot be distributed equally, there must be a maximum limit so that each landlord cannot exceed the limit of a thousand acres. Unfortunately, even this policy has not been implemented. So when Wang Mang got up, he aroused a major reform, and all the land was nationalized, called Huangtian, and redistributed. The idea at the time was to restore the well field system of the feudal era, but the result was a major disturbance. Wang Mang failed, and there has been no thorough reform of the land system in Chinese history since then. ‬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is divided into five parts: Han, Tang, Song, Ming and Qing. Due to time constraints, I only read the first part of the Han Dynasty. For the rest of the time, I watched a recent eight-episode documentary called Qiangjun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast. China&amp;rsquo;s political system for more than 2,000 years has actually been finalized very early, including many of our current systems, which were already applicable before the Qin and Han Dynasties. The biggest problem is that after the New Culture Movement and the dilapidation of the Cultural Revolution, contemporary education has an overly negative evaluation of the imperial dynasty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The political system of China&amp;rsquo;s past dynasties cannot be separated from two core issues, one is the relationship between the first and second leaders, and the other is the relationship between the central government and the local government. For example, in the Han Dynasty, the first leader was the emperor, and the second leader was the prime minister. The power of the emperor is mainly embodied by the six books in charge of food and daily life, while the power of the prime minister is embodied in various government agencies. In fact, it is very close to the state form of modern constitutional monarchy. There is a strict distinction between imperial power and government. The problem is that. This good institutional model is only continued through customary law, and has not risen to the framework of statutory law, resulting in very different effects in different emperors&amp;rsquo; reigns. Some emperors have outstanding abilities and must do everything by themselves, so the prime minister has no room to use his skills. The imperial power and the government have become one, and they have become the de facto home world. Some emperors are willing to inherit the ancient system, the imperial power and regime are highly differentiated, and professional bureaucrats can exert their maximum effectiveness. This is also a reference for observing the political situation in the past 20 years. And such a system that the main local bureaucrats cannot be held by local people was unexpectedly established in the Han Dynasty, and the original intention was to prevent problems caused by excessive local power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentary talks about the reform of the military in recent years, which is actually a process of destroying the old and establishing the new, and the system must ultimately be implemented by people. Throughout the Chinese dynasties, there has been a mass mentality of respecting the virtuous but not the public. There is no democratic soil. Only a virtuous monarch can lead the people to prosperity. The era of stagnation and retrogression must be due to the emergence of corrupt leaders. This kind of system design is estimated to continue for a long time, and the public will buy it, and they will always think that this is definitely not a problem with the system at the top, but a problem with the implementation at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qian Mu mentioned in the book that it is impossible for any system to be implemented for one or two hundred years without changing, because the people who implement the system are always changing. This point still needs to be further understood. The framework of the rule of law will not be achieved overnight, and self-healing ability is too important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added on October 10th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a deep understanding of history. Except for a certain understanding of Chinese history in middle school history books more than ten years ago, I have basically never touched it in the rest of the time. When I saw this book, I saw it by chance in a bookstore and thought it was quite thin, so I bought it. It has been placed on the bookshelf for several years, and just in time for the National Day holiday, I pulled it out and looked through it when I had time. I have also bought some other history books, almost all of which are more than hundreds of thousands of words, and I have never read them. After reading this book, there are three main impressions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answers to many years of doubts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book explains very thoroughly the relationship between imperial power and the government in Chinese history. It can be said that after so many years of socialist history education, I have always mistakenly believed that the emperor is arbitrary and has the final say. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect that there would be a practice similar to the constitutional monarchy in the Han Dynasty, and the imperial power would have so many constraints. Secondly, the book explains very clearly the origin, development and reform of many political, military, household registration and taxation systems. I have a more systematic understanding of Chinese history, and my impression of imperial dynasties has also changed a lot. I am even more amazed The ancients were able to design such a sophisticated political system more than 2,000 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new understanding of the relationship between personnel and systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my work, I often talk about the need to set up various systems to make the work more standardized, let the system restrain people, and hope that the system can solve the problem once and for all. However, in practice, there are indeed huge contrasts when different personnel operate the same system. This book lists many examples of system failure caused by changes in the times and personnel changes, highlighting the core issue of system self-healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strict distinction should be made between opinions on history and opinions on the times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we evaluate many historical events and characters, we often involuntarily apply the contemporary social environment and values, and always hope to judge from the perspective of God or from a position that we think is neutral. But in the end, the historical characters or events Whether it is good or bad, we should mainly follow the opinions of the people at that time, and it would be very immoral and meaningless to evaluate it out of that environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The spirit of the Dharma</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/the-spirit-of-the-dharma/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/the-spirit-of-the-dharma/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/the-spirit-of-the-dharma/images/img_0556-jpg-1.webp" alt="Featured image of post The spirit of the Dharma" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-spirit-of-the-dharma/images/3888670992_383f7d72c8-jpg.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;329&#34;
	height=&#34;500&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-spirit-of-the-dharma/images/3888670992_383f7d72c8-jpg_hu27f9ac97b2b01d97d05de3f9da65e0e3_26096_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/the-spirit-of-the-dharma/images/3888670992_383f7d72c8-jpg_hu27f9ac97b2b01d97d05de3f9da65e0e3_26096_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;65&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;157px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After roughly reading &amp;ldquo;The Spirit of Laws&amp;rdquo;, it is of course impossible to read the original work. This is a &amp;ldquo;miniature color print&amp;rdquo;, which is actually a &amp;ldquo;obscene color print&amp;rdquo;. (not with pictures)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The editor may have put a lot of color pictures on each page because of his good intentions, but in my eyes, these pictures did not play a big role, on the contrary they kept disturbing my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending half the night flipping through this masterpiece, I found that I was so sorry for Montesquieu. However, if many things are placed in the freshman and sophomore year, I will definitely go deeper, but now,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that I don’t have a lot of time, so I can only briefly mention many theoretical things, and try to pick out some valuable viewpoints and extract them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book has already been scratched several times with a pencil by the predecessors, but I still persisted and continued to scratch some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mainly read the two volumes &amp;ldquo;Law and Regime&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Relationship between Law and Climate and National Spirit&amp;rdquo;. Most of the other volumes were directly turned page by page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t go into details about Montesquieu and the greatness of this book. Brother Xu said that if he talked about Rousseau, he couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish it in a week. I think it would take longer if he was allowed to talk about Montesquieu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are very few perfect people through the ages, but Montesquieu is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the views on China are quite incisive, and even predicted the current problems in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t like to read books, so we didn’t pay much attention to the translation of &amp;ldquo;The Principle of Ten Thousand Laws&amp;rdquo; translated over 107 years ago and &amp;ldquo;Fa Yi&amp;rdquo; translated 96 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, it is a miracle in itself that such an insightful book could have been written in 1748.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
