<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>life on Hyruo Blog</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/categories/life/</link>
        <description>Recent content in life on Hyruo Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>by Hyruo, All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hyruo.com/en/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Listening to the teachings of a university professor again after 16 years</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/university.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Listening to the teachings of a university professor again after 16 years" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;On May 13th, the Ministry of Education issued a public notice, indicating its intention to agree to the proposal by Foshan University of Science and Technology to change its name to Foshan University. This is the fifth renaming application by Foshan University of Science and Technology, and it seems that the matter has finally been settled. Initially, at the end of 2019, during the third renaming application to “Guangdong University of Science and Technology,” it seemed almost certain, as the Guangdong Provincial Department of Education had already publicized it and submitted it to the Ministry of Education for approval. However, due to the impact of the pandemic, the renaming inspection originally planned for the spring of 2020 did not proceed as scheduled, and this delay lasted for three years. By 2023, the Ministry of Education had introduced new naming rules for universities, making it almost impossible for Foshan University of Science and Technology to be approved for renaming as Guangdong University of Science and Technology. Consequently, when resubmitting the application, the school proposed the name “Foshan University,” which was actually one of the school’s previous names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/foshanuniversity.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2507&#34;
	height=&#34;1706&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/foshanuniversity_hu5438825b9b6d1014226d20d231e650c2_651580_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/foshanuniversity_hu5438825b9b6d1014226d20d231e650c2_651580_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FoshanUniversity&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;146&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;352px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-sudden-arrangement-for-a-class-reunion&#34;&gt;A sudden arrangement for a class reunion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like a stone stirring up a thousand ripples, the familiar Foshan University was finally returning, reviving the long-silent class and alumni groups. Consequently, a classmate proposed a weekend dinner gathering to celebrate this wonderful event. Due to the sudden nature of the event, only eight classmates nearby Foshan were able to attend, and one person couldn’t make it to the dinner due to a last-minute matter. However, to everyone’s surprise, what started as a joke in the class group ended up with the classmate who organized the event actually inviting the former dean of the college. This respected dean had also taught our “Jurisprudence” course during the 2007-2008 academic year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5191.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1612&#34;
	height=&#34;1208&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5191_hu052b76b500c3b9cae2fc291af821093c_1218854_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5191_hu052b76b500c3b9cae2fc291af821093c_1218854_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;listening-to-the-teacher-lecture-again&#34;&gt;Listening to the teacher lecture again
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For almost the first three hours of the dinner, it was mostly the teacher talking, or us students asking questions and the teacher answering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-teacher-himself&#34;&gt;About the teacher himself
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher started with his experiences of traveling abroad after retiring in January this year and talked about his personal journey from starting to teach at Foshan University in 1992, through its renaming to Foshan University of Science and Technology, and the multiple attempts to revert to a university status. Especially after 2017, he shared his own health challenges and how, as a scholar, he conducted interdisciplinary research on his condition, overcame it, and took care of his health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1744&#34;
	height=&#34;892&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;195&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;469px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-childrens-education&#34;&gt;About children’s education
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the dinner, the teacher spent a long time talking about his own experiences and those of other teachers at the college in educating their children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;he-emphasized-the-current-importance-of-the-high-school-entrance-exam-zhongkao&#34;&gt;He emphasized the current importance of the high school entrance exam (Zhongkao)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which he believes is now more significant than the college entrance exam (Gaokao). Since the late 1970s, the Gaokao has been considered the most important exam in China, with countless people relying on it to change their destinies. However, in recent years, due to the saturation of college enrollment, the university admission rate has approached 90%, and for most students attending ordinary high schools, even if they “lie flat,” they basically have no worries about not being able to attend university. Overall, the importance of the Gaokao is decreasing. But at the same time, due to the “general vocational分流” policy, during the process of entering high school, more than 55% of junior high school students in many places can only attend secondary vocational technical schools after graduation, and it is basically impossible for these schools to progress to ordinary universities. In this situation, if a child’s academic performance is not ideal in primary and junior high school, they may lose the opportunity to attend an ordinary university and can only take the vocational technical university route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;he-talked-about-his-methods-of-educating-his-children&#34;&gt;He talked about his methods of educating his children
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both he and his wife are highly educated, but they also faced difficulties in educating their children. He summed it up with the phrase &lt;strong&gt;“parents are not good at teaching their children (academics).”&lt;/strong&gt; Parents can still play a decisive role in their children’s growth in life and other aspects, but their role in learning is very limited. He emphasized the importance of teachers and schools in improving children’s academic performance and cited a series of examples from his surroundings. He hoped that we would create a relaxed family atmosphere for our children, send them to the best schools within our means, and handle relationships with teachers well. He advised that we should mainly rely on schools and classrooms to enhance our children’s learning ability, rather than relying on family or off-campus tutoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;he-discussed-the-issue-of-childrens-educational-planning&#34;&gt;He discussed the issue of children’s educational planning.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a law major himself and with his wife studying medicine, he pointed out that fields like law, especially medicine, and computer science are highly competitive and require continuous learning and updating of knowledge to keep up with the times. Even in computer science, it’s quite possible to be unable to compete with younger people in their thirties and forties due to the physical and familial demands that come with age, making it easy to fall behind in the race for new technology. He stressed the importance of guiding children to develop hobbies and interests based on their personalities and interests, rather than just following trends. The teacher has only one daughter, who is almost our age. After graduating with a bachelor’s degree from a top art academy in China, she pursued a master’s degree at a well-ranked university in the United States, and later, a Ph.D. After completing her doctorate, she became a teacher at a domestic art academy and quickly grew to become one of the youngest professors there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1001914.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;2250&#34;
	height=&#34;1500&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1001914_hua8053f0bd34c4ab00b1b9d33025e98fd_197404_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1001914_hua8053f0bd34c4ab00b1b9d33025e98fd_197404_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Education&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-development-of-the-university&#34;&gt;About the development of the university
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As one of the earliest faculty members with a doctoral degree in law at our alma mater, the teacher has long served as the university’s legal advisor and is aware of many secrets behind the school’s development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-development-of-a-university-is-inseparable-from-the-help-of-influential-people&#34;&gt;The development of a university is inseparable from the help of influential people.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the course of the development of Foshan University and later Foshan University of Science and Technology, the support of key figures was indispensable. In the early stages, two mayors of Foshan City, Yu Fei and Lu Ruihua, played significant roles. Without the attention and support of these two mayors, Foshan University would not have been established in 1986. &lt;em&gt;(Yu Fei: Served as the Vice-Governor of Guangdong Province but was expelled from the Communist Party in 1998 due to his children’s seeking private interests; Lu Ruihua: Served as the Governor of Guangdong Province. )&lt;/em&gt;
In the last 10 years, Foshan University of Science and Technology has skyrocketed from outside the top 500 national university rankings to 219th nationwide, thanks in large part to the assistance of the former Secretary of the Guangdong Provincial Party Committee, Hu Chunhua. As a member of the Central Political Bureau, Hu Chunhua visited the school three times after 2015, proposed the goal of building Foshan University of Science and Technology into a high-level science and technology university in Guangdong, and the Guangdong provincial government allocated 500 million yuan specifically for support. Since then, the school’s development has entered the fast lane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5194.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2106&#34;
	height=&#34;842&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5194_hueda0fd19d53824080503c29a507fa0d3_139141_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5194_hueda0fd19d53824080503c29a507fa0d3_139141_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;250&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;600px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-development-of-a-university-cannot-be-separated-from-government-support&#34;&gt;The development of a university cannot be separated from government support.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since public universities dominate in China, the development of universities is driven by administrative resources, and the richness of these resources determines the height of university development. Decisive factors include the level of education and the allocation of funds, both of which are decided by administrative organs. As a university founded by the Foshan municipal government, Foshan University has inherent shortcomings because, compared to the financial strength of national or provincial governments, a prefecture-level city like Foshan falls far short. Moreover, although Foshan’s economic output ranks among the top 20 in the country, as an ordinary prefecture-level city in the Pearl River Delta, under the three-tier fiscal structure (about 50% of income goes to the central government, and of the remaining 50% tax, another 50% goes to the province, leaving about 25% actually retained), the financial resources that the Foshan municipal government can dispose of are far less than those of first-tier cities like Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou, and Shenzhen, as well as other sub-provincial cities and general provincial capitals. For example, the fiscal budget expenditure for Foshan University of Science and Technology in 2024 is 1.8 billion yuan, while the fiscal budget expenditure for the Foshan municipal government during the same period is 24 billion yuan, accounting for 7.5% of the total. Nearby universities such as Shenzhen University and Southern University of Science and Technology have fiscal expenditures of over 6 billion yuan, which is an amount that the Foshan city government, with a fiscal budget of 24 billion at the city level, cannot afford. Fortunately, Foshan University of Science and Technology is currently not large in scale, and if calculated by the per-student expenditure on funds, it ranks among the top in Guangdong’s higher education institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-development-of-a-university-needs-to-go-with-the-flow&#34;&gt;The development of a university needs to go with the flow.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In discussing the school’s development, the teacher specifically mentioned the construction of doctoral programs, which is one of the two biggest projects the school has undertaken in recent years, the other being the “renaming to a university” project. Currently, there are about 400 universities in China with doctoral programs. Although Foshan University of Science and Technology has seen its ranking climb continuously, the lack of a doctoral program has always been a major concern, and this has even led to the university’s president position being vacant for three years. The main reason is that the Foshan municipal government hopes to find an expert at the “Academician” level to serve as the president, and it is almost impossible to find an Academician willing to be the president of a school without a doctoral program. In this round of applying for a doctoral program, the school has put in a great deal of effort, especially the party committee secretary who has used all his skills to advance the discipline construction, focusing on mechanical engineering, a field he is highly proficient in. As of now, the application for a doctoral program has reached the most critical stage. In the list of Guangdong universities applying for doctoral program construction published by the Guangdong Provincial Department of Education, Foshan University of Science and Technology’s mechanical engineering doctoral program ranked first among 234 disciplines in 32 universities across the province, and veterinary and animal husbandry programs also ranked among the top five. It can be said that this is the closest the school has been to securing a doctoral program since it became a doctoral degree-granting institution in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5195.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1888&#34;
	height=&#34;732&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5195_hu935cfa788b6b52a3c4d88f8d40a84db9_345000_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5195_hu935cfa788b6b52a3c4d88f8d40a84db9_345000_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;257&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;619px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-personal-growth&#34;&gt;About personal growth
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With his 32 years of work experience, the teacher shared several key aspects that we should focus on during our professional development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;avoid-speaking-ill-of-others-when-they-are-not-present&#34;&gt;Avoid speaking ill of others when they are not present.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher emphasized that Chinese society is heavily influenced by personal relationships, and we should never speak ill of others, regardless of how much we may dislike them or have had conflicts with them. Even a decade ago, we might not have fully appreciated the importance of this advice, but today, we deeply agree with it. Numerous examples around us confirm this point. However, as human beings, we have our limitations, and sometimes we inadvertently express our true feelings, leading to unforeseen consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dont-be-too-rigid&#34;&gt;Don’t be too rigid.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher cited several examples from his own experience, advising us to be flexible in handling work relationships and not to be overly pedantic or inflexible. Wearing the necessary masks and disguises is essential for self-protection, which is the foundation of growth. Throughout our development, we will encounter various setbacks and unavoidable conflicts of interest, but we should still approach them with a relaxed and optimistic attitude. Harmonious workplace relationships are crucial for our own well-being. We should not view potential competitors as adversaries but rather as companions, as work is only an eight-hour-a-day matter, while life is a lifelong journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;learn-to-be-content-and-embrace-ordinariness&#34;&gt;Learn to be content and embrace ordinariness.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher used examples of students and leaders he has helped and supported over the years to advise us that as we enter middle age, we should start to learn satisfaction and contentment, and not overly concern ourselves with personal gains and losses. After all, as we reach middle age, the harmony of the family, the growth of our children, and our health are often more important than personal advancement. Especially within the system, the time most people can shine in their careers typically does not exceed 15 years. In the marathon of life, there can still be two to three decades after retirement. Even if some have held high positions and had power for a time, facing decades of retirement, if there are problems with the family, children, or their own health, it would all have been in vain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1744&#34;
	height=&#34;892&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5193_hu61b82af6b32ad0eec130834f8e34a54d_600305_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;195&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;469px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-legal-work-in-law&#34;&gt;About legal work in law
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a senior law professor, the teacher offered some sound advice and suggestions for the work and development of several of us students based on his own experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-judicial-work&#34;&gt;Regarding judicial work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Including myself, two of us present have worked in judicial authorities. Drawing on his long-term experience serving part-time in the National People’s Congress, the teacher offered two suggestions for those of us engaged in judicial work: First, the current workload in judicial authorities is generally high, with many cases and few people, a situation that is expected to persist for a long time, and the reward may not be proportional to the effort. For women, especially, who often have to invest more in family and childcare, choosing a career in the judiciary requires careful consideration. Second, within the judiciary, there is a significant level of internal competition, with a concentration of highly educated individuals, complex factions, and young and female leaders often having higher aspirations. It is important to know one’s limits, avoid confrontation, and advance steadily with modesty and caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-arbitration-work&#34;&gt;Regarding arbitration work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the students present works in an arbitration institution. Based on his experience as an arbitrator, the teacher advised that students working in arbitration institutions should strengthen communication with law firms, businesses, and other industry organizations, improve communication skills, and develop a network of contacts. Outside of work, they should continuously study relevant trade laws, international trade management, and arbitration rules to maintain advanced and in-depth professional knowledge. However, he suggested that it might not be necessary to pursue a doctoral degree, as we have all been working for over a decade and have missed the optimal time to advance our careers with a doctoral degree. Moreover, at our age, with the pressures of work and life, the benefits of obtaining a PhD may not be significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-notary-work&#34;&gt;Regarding notary work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two students present work in notary institutions. The teacher, based on his experience, put forward several points: First, the notary industry is relatively closed, with a smaller number of notaries among legal professions, and the overall development space is narrow. Second, in recent years, the notary industry has been continuously promoting restructuring, with some notary institutions transitioning from traditional public institutions to social welfare organizations similar to law firms. In this process, the personal networks and channels established become extremely important, as work income will be directly related to the volume of business. Third, the notary industry is closely related to the legal profession, and it is important to pay attention to interactions with lawyers, guiding clients to resolve many common disputes through notarization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/notary.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1200&#34;
	height=&#34;800&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/notary_hu7d6fd75e6699370713a188194a904a94_107780_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/notary_hu7d6fd75e6699370713a188194a904a94_107780_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Notary&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-lawyer-practice&#34;&gt;Regarding lawyer practice.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;One student is a practicing lawyer, and the teacher himself has also served as a part-time lawyer, and I also work part-time as a public service lawyer. Because of concerns that continuing to practice law after retirement might affect retirement benefits, the teacher canceled his part-time lawyer’s license upon retirement and did not apply to convert it to a general lawyer’s practice certificate. The teacher offered several suggestions for legal practice, including the importance of maintaining client relationships, how to expand one’s network and case sources, and the need for lifelong learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-corporate-work&#34;&gt;Regarding corporate work.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two students work in central enterprises and large private enterprises in the IT and internet industry. As they are both female and have personal or family health issues, the teacher suggested that they should pay attention to their own and their family’s health while maintaining a positive attitude towards life and a proactive learning mindset. They should keep abreast of industry trends and maintain their level of expertise in law, seeking development opportunities through their comparative advantages in non-legal work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regarding-work-within-the-system&#34;&gt;Regarding work within the system.
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Including myself, out of the 7 students present, 5 of us are effectively working in “governmental, institutional, and enterprise units” within the system. The teacher offered a lot of opinions and suggestions on working within the system, also sharing many of his observations from working in the local system in Foshan. As some of the content is sensitive, it has not been written out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5192.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1612&#34;
	height=&#34;1208&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5192_hu82f2d5ee5588d27505d5c94102ba66cc_1060195_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/5192_hu82f2d5ee5588d27505d5c94102ba66cc_1060195_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This gathering was indeed a rare opportunity. We arrived at 4 pm in the afternoon, and while waiting for the teacher and other classmates to arrive, we played the card game “Guan Dang” (Gentlemen’s Agreement) as we chatted, with one of our classmates working at a central enterprise saying, “It’s like not eating at all if you don’t play ‘Guan Dang’.” During the meal, we listened to the teacher “lecture” almost throughout, and the teacher even specifically commented on the phenomenon of “Guan Dang.” After the teacher left early due to time constraints, we chatted informally until almost 11 pm before dispersing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-is-no-template-for-choosing-the-path-of-life&#34;&gt;There is no template for choosing the path of life
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The eight classmates who attended the reunion had all graduated from the same class but later embarked on completely different paths in life. If we extend this group to the entire class of over 40 students, their paths become even more diverse and complex. In general, however, we all stood at the same starting point at the same time, seeking different lives. The vast differences that followed may have been more related to each family’s and personal choices. Even among those who pursued the same profession, different classmates took different paths. For example, in our class, four students became ordinary lawyers, one of whom has been practicing law in Foshan for 13 years and has had a smooth career development; another student who did not attend the dinner began practicing law only 10 years after graduation and is still in the early stages; one student who practices law in Shenzhen opened their own law firm early on and has recently opened branches in other places; and another student who practices law in Chengdu pursued a master’s degree after graduation and initially chose to practice in Shenzhen before moving to Chengdu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-advantage-brought-by-information-gaps-is-gradually-decreasing&#34;&gt;The advantage brought by information gaps is gradually decreasing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we graduated, information gaps were still a significant factor contributing to differences in life paths. Back then, in our class of over 40 students, only a few chose to take the civil service exam or participate in campus recruitment by enterprises and institutions, and only a few decided to become lawyers. It was only after entering the workforce that more people gradually realized the importance of their undergraduate degree in law. Including myself, many of us entered judicial and administrative organs through the civil service exam in the following years. It was not until 2017, when short video platforms began to thrive, that the advantages of employment in systems such as government agencies and state-owned enterprises were fully exposed, and this was only gradually recognized by the public. At this point, the difficulty of entering these professions compared to when we graduated from university had become unimaginable. For example, when I applied for a civil service position in the Pearl River Delta, there were only 13 applicants for the same position, with only 8 actually taking the exam. With no preparation at all, I even didn’t complete a complete practice test, and yet I managed to score 110 points (out of a total of 200 for two subjects) to become the first-ranked candidate, and was successfully employed. Every time I think back, I feel extremely lucky, with more luck than actual ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-are-no-shortcuts-in-the-marathon-of-life&#34;&gt;There are no shortcuts in the marathon of life
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teacher used his rich personal experiences and insights to illustrate how individuals navigate this era. In the 1980s, when university students were still a “rare species,” the teacher, with his strong character and self-discipline, successfully enrolled in university and pursued a master’s degree. He then went south to Foshan University to pioneer, gradually advancing from lecturer to associate professor and then to professor, and serving as the dean of the college. Along the way, he pursued a doctoral degree and engaged in postdoctoral research at top universities in the industry, providing himself and his family with ample material and spiritual wealth. In the second century of struggle, in this era widely considered highly competitive, I believe that this era still offers opportunities for many to change their destinies. However, success can only be achieved through even greater effort, a more positive attitude, and unwavering perseverance. After all, the negative emotions of this era are already enough, with voices of “lying flat” and “tittytainment” products ubiquitous. Only by adhering to one’s original aspiration can one live up to oneself, one’s family, and this era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1164572.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2250&#34;
	height=&#34;1500&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1164572_hu004c9b28559f5fa727659b387248f524_688245_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/listening-to-the-teachings-of-a-university-professor-again-after-16-years/pexels-photo-1164572_hu004c9b28559f5fa727659b387248f524_688245_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Visit a highschool female classmate</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin1.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Visit a highschool female classmate" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last night, at the invitation of a high school female classmate, my wife and I visited her company. The main purpose was to taste the cured meat, local eggs, and other delicacies she brought from her hometown. During the meal, we also took the opportunity to tour the company. Although I often visit companies in my work, most of the time it&amp;rsquo;s for serious business activities. Even when there are dining and touring components, they tend to be quite restrained, rarely allowing for a relaxed mindset like this visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a company engaged in the trade of stainless steel products, backed by Hongwang Holding Group Co., Ltd., one of the top 500 Chinese enterprises. It is a typical family-owned business. My classmate is the general manager of one of the trading companies under this enterprise, mainly responsible for domestic sales. In addition, the company&amp;rsquo;s stainless steel products, such as furniture and decorative building materials made of stainless steel materials, are also sold to countries like Japan, South Korea, and Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin5.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1636&#34;
	height=&#34;920&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin5_hub919c6f26601da0acf699e30dd4ec188_406937_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin5_hub919c6f26601da0acf699e30dd4ec188_406937_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hongwang-holding-group&#34;&gt;Hongwang Holding Group
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had heard of the Hongwang Group&amp;rsquo;s reputation many years ago. It is a successful example of Hunanese people going south to Guangdong for work and entrepreneurship after the reform and opening-up. The founder hails from Shuangfeng County, my hometown. In addition to establishing roots in Guangdong, the company has also given back to its hometown by investing in the construction of a large-scale manufacturing enterprise in the Shuangfeng County Development Zone, solving the local employment issues for many Shuangfeng residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a corporate group specializing in the production of cold-rolled stainless steel, silicon steel, and supporting fine processing products, Hongwang Group ranks 459th among the 2023 China Top 500 Enterprises and 241st among the China Top 500 Manufacturing Enterprises. It enjoys a good reputation in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meiling.png&#34;
	width=&#34;942&#34;
	height=&#34;695&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meiling_huc6fa779a5d79da6a42b887a053e7c386_751022_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meiling_huc6fa779a5d79da6a42b887a053e7c386_751022_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;135&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;325px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mellow-group&#34;&gt;Mellow Group
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This company is located on the top floor of the Foshan New City Xinbao Building, occupying two floors of office space. During the company tour, the clean, tidy, and modern atmosphere left a deep impression on me. Especially the small garden built on the rooftop of a high-rise office building, which indeed had a unique charm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin4.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1636&#34;
	height=&#34;920&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin4_hub970e22b605a2f8651b7adaff798151e_568943_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin4_hub970e22b605a2f8651b7adaff798151e_568943_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, in our conversation, I learned that although the company appears to lean towards a modern management model in many aspects, it still retains the humanized characteristics of traditional manufacturing enterprises. For example, the company provides free accommodation and meal subsidies for all employees, and the boss has specially purchased dozens of fully furnished apartments for employees to live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin7.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1287&#34;
	height=&#34;870&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin7_hu64c21e0e6f0505edfb89e971eb6047a7_1038332_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin7_hu64c21e0e6f0505edfb89e971eb6047a7_1038332_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;147&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;355px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;classmate&#34;&gt;Classmate
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This classmate is someone my wife and I both knew from high school, in the same class. Although she was a girl, during our school days, she exuded an extraordinary aura that commanded the scene, with a cheerful and outgoing personality. Her only shortcoming was her slightly weaker academic performance. After graduation, although we all worked in the same city, we only had sporadic contact with her twice. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until this visit to her company that we gained a deeper understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin3.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1612&#34;
	height=&#34;904&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin3_hu6d404f4b4399fd2bec863d4bbcbb7767_598323_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/meilin3_hu6d404f4b4399fd2bec863d4bbcbb7767_598323_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;427px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;industry-contrast&#34;&gt;Industry Contrast
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the stainless steel and metal materials industry, most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t associate it with women. Yet, this female classmate of mine happens to be in such an industry and has even become a well-known figure in the Foshan stainless steel market, which is quite impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;position-contrast&#34;&gt;Position Contrast
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last time I met this classmate at a reunion years ago, she was still an ordinary salesperson. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until this visit that I learned she had grown into a general manager managing several companies years ago, which was quite shocking to me. Most of our other classmates from the same class are still in ordinary staff positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gender-contrast&#34;&gt;Gender Contrast
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to when we were in the same classroom, this female classmate was just a naive little girl. In just over a decade, she has grown into a powerful elite in the workplace. Balancing family and children while handling the complex affairs of the company and achieving rapid promotion is indeed no easy feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/class.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3284&#34;
	height=&#34;1600&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/class_hu76eda07030458ed05572fba6005da0c3_1518683_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visit-a-highschool-classmate/class_hu76eda07030458ed05572fba6005da0c3_1518683_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;205&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;492px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hunan’s Oldest County: Which is it?</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/IMG_20240423_222634.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hunan’s Oldest County: Which is it?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I came across an article that claimed Chaling, Leiyang, and Liling as the three oldest counties in Hunan, with Chaling County established in 221 BC, Leiyang County in 202 BC, and Liling County during the Eastern Han Dynasty, which is 1900 years ago. However, I have serious doubts about this conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1chu-state-pioneer-in-establishing-counties-in-china&#34;&gt;1.Chu State: Pioneer in Establishing Counties in China
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although traditional Chinese historians believe that the system of counties in China began with Shang Yang’s reforms in the Qin state in 356 BC, according to archaeological evidence, the current consensus in the historical field is that the system of counties in China originated at least from the Spring and Autumn period (770-476 BC), and many scholars trace this origin back to the Western Zhou period (1046-771 BC). In any case, the Chu State (approximately 1042-223 BC) was the earliest to establish counties, and the Hunan region was developed and incorporated into the Chu State during the Warring States period (476-221 BC) until the Qin conquered the Chu. This raises a question: before 221 BC, was there a county-level region in Hunan that survived, whether it was a county of the Qin Dynasty (221-207 BC) or of the Chu State.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2changsha-jun-in-historical-texts&#34;&gt;2.Changsha Jun* in Historical Texts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;* &amp;#34;Jun&amp;#34; 郡 is a type of administrative division in ancient China, belonging directly to the state, with counties at the next level，similar to &amp;#34;prefecture&amp;#34;.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first saw this article, Changsha County immediately came to my mind. This is because, in my memory, the history of Qin Dynasty’s Hunan has almost been overturned since the discovery of the Liye Qin bamboo slips in Western Hunan. For a period of 2000 years, the history of Qin Dynasty’s Hunan was based on records such as “Records of the Grand Historian” and “Book of Han,” which were divided into Changsha Jun and Qianzhong Jun. The historical records used in Chaling County also have this background. However, the conclusion that Chaling County was established in 221 BC, directly drawn from the “Book of the Later Han Dynasty · Counties and States IV” about Changsha Jun, seems hasty, as the “Book of the Later Han Dynasty” does not confirm that Changsha Jun was established in 221 BC either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changsha Jun was established by the Qin. It is located 2,800 li ( ancient Chinese length unit) south of Luoyang. It consists of thirteen cities, with 255,854 households and 1,953,072 people. Including Linxiang, You, Chaling, Ancheng, Ling, Xiangnan, Liandao, Zhaoling, Yiyang, Xiajun, Luo, Liling, Rongling, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;——“Book of the Later Han Dynasty · Counties and States IV”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 26th year of Qin Ying Zheng (221 BC), Chaling County was established, governing the current Chaling and Yanling counties, belonging to Changsha Jun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;——“Annals of Chaling County”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423180307-1024x749.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;749&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423180307-1024x749_hu5c2846525eceeeed49dee85725932188_1124844_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423180307-1024x749_hu5c2846525eceeeed49dee85725932188_1124844_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;136&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;328px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Changsha Jun may be a later conjecture without solid evidence, according to Sima Qian’s “Records of the Grand Historian” (104 BC), in 202 BC, Emperor Liu Bang of the Han Dynasty enfeoffed Wu Rui, a founding general, as the King of Changsha, establishing the Changsha Kingdom, which lasted until 7 AD. This record from the dynastic history should be accurate. Then, the term “Changsha” must have a source. My conjecture is that if Changsha Jun did not exist, then Changsha County might have existed. After all, the Qin Dynasty had only fallen five years before the establishment of the Changsha Kingdom. So, I started searching for evidence with this conjecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3qin-dynastys-changsha-jun-debunked&#34;&gt;3.Qin Dynasty’s Changsha Jun Debunked
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, the record of Changsha Jun in the “Book of the Later Han Dynasty · Counties and States IV” has already been debunked in contemporary times; that is, there was no place called “Changsha Jun” in the Qin Dynasty. At the same time, there are also considerable doubts about the records of Qianzhong Jun, and it is highly likely that there was no place called “Qianzhong Jun” in the Qin Dynasty either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statement that the Qin set up Qianzhong and Changsha Juns is clearly wrong. The two prefectures that were actually set up were Dongting and Cangwu, and these two prefectures continued to exist throughout the Qin Dynasty but naturally disappeared during the Anti-Qin and Chu-Han Wars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423192420.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1371&#34;
	height=&#34;682&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423192420_hu294b28bbbb226b35ea4e952e64e59bc7_235109_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423192420_hu294b28bbbb226b35ea4e952e64e59bc7_235109_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;201&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;482px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Establishment Era and Political Region Evolution of Qin’s Dongting and Cangwu Jun” by Qin Zaiyuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4chu-state-established-changsha-county&#34;&gt;4.Chu State Established Changsha County
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although Changsha Jun did not exist in the Qin Dynasty, this does not mean that the history of Changsha can only be traced back to the Han Dynasty. For example, some scholars have found that as early as the Warring States period, the Chu State had already established Changsha County.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423193021.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1432&#34;
	height=&#34;1138&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423193021_hu7ac0992e0af535bd18c3fb733fa4e3e0_442323_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423193021_hu7ac0992e0af535bd18c3fb733fa4e3e0_442323_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;125&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;302px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5changsha-county-was-the-capital-of-cangwu-jun&#34;&gt;5.Changsha County was the Capital of Cangwu Jun
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;More recently, scholars have concluded through the study of Qin Dynasty bamboo slips such as Liye Qin Jian and other documents that Changsha County was the capital of Cangwu Jun during the Qin Dynasty, debunking the previously misunderstood two thousand years of Changsha Jun, which was actually Cangwu Jun.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liye Qin Jian, Huayuan Qin Du, and Yiyang Tuzishan Han Jian all mention the place name “Changsha,” indicating that the Qin Dynasty continued the Chu State’s establishment of Changsha County, which served as the capital of Cangwu Jun and continued until the early Han Dynasty. The ancient city of Qin Changsha County is located in the present Wuyi Square and surrounding areas in Changsha City, and the city site of Linxiang County in the early Han Dynasty may have been in Beijin City. It is suspected that the capital of the Wu’s Changsha Kingdom may have been moved from Beijin City to the “Linxiang Ancient City,” and after the move, the original Changsha County was renamed Linxiang County.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423195955.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1774&#34;
	height=&#34;1518&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423195955_hu3d876f467e2100202173b71ba03624e5_462241_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423195955_hu3d876f467e2100202173b71ba03624e5_462241_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;116&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;280px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6the-establishment-time-of-changsha-county&#34;&gt;6.The Establishment Time of Changsha County
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, according to the textual research on the establishment time of Changsha County cited in the article, it can be known that the time when the Chu State established Changsha County was roughly between 329 BC and 296 BC during the reign of King Huai of Chu.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, among the multiple place names examined in the paper, there is also the current Yiyang, which is still in use and belonged to the Chu State’s counties during the Warring States period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202953.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1020&#34;
	height=&#34;685&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202953_hu94d16647a4e43fb2ea2bda9238d53a36_143062_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202953_hu94d16647a4e43fb2ea2bda9238d53a36_143062_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;148&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;357px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7changsha-county-is-one-of-the-oldest-counties-in-hunan&#34;&gt;7.Changsha County is One of the Oldest Counties in Hunan
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion: Since both Changsha and Yiyang are located in northern Hunan, and the Chu State developed the Hunan region from north to south, during the Warring States period when the areas of YunMengZe and Dongting Lake were still vast&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, these two places adjacent to Dongting Lake should be the earliest counties established by the Chu State in the Hunan region.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423204539.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1237&#34;
	height=&#34;1278&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423204539_hu177b796cb6958ef5b9a7b8ba8fd3ecba_276946_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423204539_hu177b796cb6958ef5b9a7b8ba8fd3ecba_276946_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;96&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;232px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8other&#34;&gt;8.Other
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Counties Established by Chu State Regarding this, I also looked into the list of counties established by the Chu State during the Spring and Autumn period and the Warring States period that have been verified by current historical research. From the counties established by the Chu State in the Spring and Autumn period verified by scholars in the 1980s, it can be seen that the sphere of influence of the Chu State had not reached the Hunan region at that time&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and the same is true for the more than forty counties established by the Chu State in the Spring and Autumn period that have been verified in recent years.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423201354.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1122&#34;
	height=&#34;571&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423201354_hue325b079a4b9869b34e77833898f27c5_303956_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423201354_hue325b079a4b9869b34e77833898f27c5_303956_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;196&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;471px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, from the counties established by the Chu State in the Warring States period that have been verified by scholars, no place names that correspond to the current cities and counties in various parts of Hunan have been found either.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202824.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1363&#34;
	height=&#34;768&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202824_hucc6992c8235bb784a84b919926488efb_179358_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/hunans-oldest-county-which-is-it/images/20240423202824_hucc6992c8235bb784a84b919926488efb_179358_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;425px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li Fengxian: “Research on the Year, Boundary, and County Establishment of Qin Dynasty’s prefectures during the Warring States Period.” Ph.D. dissertation, Qinghai Normal University, 2023. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhao Yuxuan: “Examination of ‘Changsha’ County in Qin and Han Dynasty Bamboo and Silk Documents.” “Documents Unearthed.” First issue, 2024. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xu Shaohua: “Eight Comments on the Places Mentioned in the Baoshan Chu Slips.” “Journal of Chinese Historical Geography.” Vol. 4, 1996. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhou Hongwei: “Another Discussion on the Historical Process of Dongting Lake’s Changes.” “Journal of Chinese Historical Geography.” Vol. 20, No. 2, 2005. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang Kuan: “On the Nature of the County System of the Chu State during the Spring and Autumn Period.” “Research on Chinese History.” No. 4, 1981. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chen Jian: “The Origin and Transformation of the County System in the Pre-Qin Period.” Ph.D. dissertation, Jilin University, 2019. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zheng Yifan: “A Preliminary Study on the Counties of the Chu State during the Warring States Period.” Master’s thesis, Wuhan University, 2017. &amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Chinese Earth Burial I Know</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/12.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Chinese Earth Burial I Know" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Funerals have always been an important ritual in human civilization. In terms of traditional Chinese culture, earth burial has been a significant part of Han culture. Besides the Han, there are other burial practices such as cremation, water burial, and sky burial. As China&amp;rsquo;s urbanization movement accelerates, the traditional cultural practice of earth burial has become increasingly rare. Now, in most parts of China, cremation has replaced earth burial. My hometown, Hunan, may be one of the few provinces in China where Han people are the majority and still retain a significant amount of earth burial traditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-naive-understanding&#34;&gt;I. Naive Understanding
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout my childhood, I rarely encountered funerals. The only vivid memory I have was in early 1995 when one of my grandfather&amp;rsquo;s younger brothers returned to our hometown in Hunan from Jiujiang, Jiangxi Province, where he had lived and worked for several decades. He was already over 60 years old at that time. Shortly after returning, he passed away due to an illness, and the funeral was held at our house. This was the first funeral I had ever experienced, leaving an indelible impression on my childhood. Several scenes often appear in my dreams to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_2024033125.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1636&#34;
	height=&#34;1228&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_2024033125_hubf4691c7881ee5f52def693c6488f60a_406856_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_2024033125_hubf4691c7881ee5f52def693c6488f60a_406856_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;319px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funeral procession&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scene One: It was the first time I saw adults crying so heart-wrenchingly. After my great-uncle passed away, his daughter couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop wailing at the funeral, muttering incoherently about regret, sorrow, and exhaustion. Several relatives and friends couldn&amp;rsquo;t console her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scene Two: It was my first time seeing a Buddhist monk in person, a profession I had only seen on television before. However, due to our earth burial customs, we needed to invite monks to perform rituals according to Buddhist traditions for the deceased. They chanted Buddhist scriptures for several days for my departed great-uncle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scene Three: When it was time to bury my great-uncle, I realized for the first time how arduous the process was. The coffin containing the body weighed at least 600 kilograms. To lift it, we needed a massive wooden frame and round poles, adding up to over 750 kilograms in total. It took 16 strong adults to carry it, and each person lifting the coffin needed a backup to alternate, otherwise, it would be difficult for one person to carry it for such a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scene Four: Since my hometown is located in the central mountains of Hunan, it was nearly two kilometers from our house to the burial site, and the mountain paths were usually narrow. Therefore, at the front of such a large group, a strong man had to carry a machete to clear the way. If any trees or shrubs along the road might block the procession, they had to be cut down immediately. Even so, there was still an accident on the way to the burial site. Due to the uneven primitive mountain path, the coffin tilted sideways while being carried. In the end, someone had to jump on top of the coffin to sway it back into balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-full-experience&#34;&gt;II. Full Experience
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a long time after 1995, I rarely attended any funerals until 15 years later. From 2010 to 2024, I experienced five funerals from start to finish, which were for my father, father-in-law, grandfather, grandmother, and maternal grandmother, all of whom were buried in the earth burial tradition. Additionally, I attended over ten funerals for other relatives. The shortest funeral was for my father-in-law, which took only four days from the time of death to the burial. The longest was for my grandmother, which spanned thirteen days. Despite the significant difference in time, the processes were largely similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2047541253180289618131116.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2000&#34;
	height=&#34;1923&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2047541253180289618131116_hudf922dda8e0a6e0d6d366f01b0e4f8bf_442204_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2047541253180289618131116_hudf922dda8e0a6e0d6d366f01b0e4f8bf_442204_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;104&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;249px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sacrificial rituals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Placing in the Coffin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is a crucial step that usually takes several hours to a day from the time of death to the placement in the coffin. In rural Hunan, households with elderly members often have a coffin ready, typically made from solid wood and polished with a large amount of tung oil before being painted to ensure tight sealing. Such a coffin usually weighs over 250 kilograms.&lt;br&gt;
Before the deceased is placed in the coffin, it is customary to wait until all family members have arrived, which sometimes requires a longer wait if the children of the deceased are not present. For instance, my father-in-law passed away in a hospital in Guangdong, and at that time, apart from my wife, his other daughters were not in Guangdong. So, I drove my own car and transported his body overnight from Guangdong back to our hometown in Hunan, which was over 650 kilometers away, by which time my wife&amp;rsquo;s sisters had already been waiting at their father&amp;rsquo;s house.&lt;br&gt;
When the deceased is to be placed in the coffin, the family hires a local embalmer to help with makeup and dressing. Then, an elderly person knowledgeable in the theories of Yin and Yang and the Eight Trigrams selects an appropriate time to place the body into the coffin. The coffin is typically filled with a large amount of quicklime for preservation. After the coffin lid is closed, it is sealed with wood glue, and long iron nails are hammered in to prevent any movement. During the summer when temperatures are high, it is usually necessary to rent a large refrigerator to cover the coffin and prevent the body from oxidizing too quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeking Guidance from the Deities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In rural Hunan, every village has a Earth God Temple. On the evening of the day the deceased is placed in the coffin, the family usually takes the portrait of the deceased to the Earth God Temple for a sacrifice led by a monk or a Taoist priest. This is done to inform the Earth God that someone in their jurisdiction has passed away, providing personal information such as the name and date of birth of the deceased. It also serves to guide the soul of the deceased, with continuous sounds of gongs, firecrackers, and the burning of spirit money to show the deceased the way home.&lt;br&gt;
The Water God is one of the most important deities in Han culture. After the death, the family, led by a monk or Taoist priest, goes to the river near the home to sacrifice to the Water God, which is similar in form to the sacrifice to the Earth God. Additionally, personal items such as clothes, shoes, and socks worn by the deceased are usually taken to the water&amp;rsquo;s edge to be burned as part of the sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous Light and Incense&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
From the time the deceased is placed in the coffin until the burial, a continuous light (changmingdeng) is lit beneath the coffin and before the portrait of the deceased. The light must never be extinguished, no matter how long it takes, and the same applies to the incense before the portrait, symbolizing the unbroken tradition in Chinese culture. Previously, we generally used rapeseed oil to light the lamps, but now special candles are available for purchase. The most challenging part is the incense, as traditional incense sticks usually burn for only about 30 minutes before needing to be replaced. Ensuring that incense is burning continuously for 24 hours is a very demanding task and usually requires several people to take turns watching over it. Nowadays, we can buy incense sticks over a meter long that can burn for seven to eight hours, greatly reducing the labor intensity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Chanting Scriptures for the Deceased&lt;br&gt;
**After the death, it is customary to spend three to seven days inviting monks and Taoist priests to the home to chant scriptures for the deceased, including well-known Buddhist texts like the &amp;ldquo;Vajra Sutra&amp;rdquo; and Taoist texts like the &amp;ldquo;Rebirth Incantation.&amp;rdquo; The children of the deceased are expected to accompany the chanting throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/11.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1000&#34;
	height=&#34;666&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/11_hu13288e1c15abe991f05966ef46812215_105740_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/11_hu13288e1c15abe991f05966ef46812215_105740_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Ritual for Guiding the Deceased&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
During the process of guiding the deceased, there is an important ritual called crossing the &amp;ldquo;Bridge of Helplessness.&amp;rdquo; The Bridge of Helplessness is a necessary passage in Chinese folklore for reincarnation. This process involves sacrificing to many deities of the underworld, with family members usually following the monk and Taoist priest outdoors while barefoot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual Sacrificial for the Deceased&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Throughout the funeral process, various relatives of the deceased offer a large amount of paper spirit money, mountains of gold and silver, clothes, houses, and other sacrificial items to the deceased. At my grandmother&amp;rsquo;s funeral last month, we burned nearly 500 kilograms of spirit money and various sacrificial items. Traditionally, we believe that the best spirit money is made from bamboo paper, which is produced from bamboo that has been growing for no more than a year, and is stamped with copper coin patterns. However, spirit money that is printed in colorful designs resembling contemporary currencies is considered worthless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family Sacrifice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Family sacrifice is a very important step in the funeral process, usually conducted on the evening before the deceased is buried. The participants are all the relatives of the deceased. For example, nearly a hundred people participated in the family sacrifice at my grandfather&amp;rsquo;s funeral. This includes children, daughters-in-law, sons-in-law, nieces, nephews, grandchildren, great-grandchildren, and other extended family members. Each category of relatives arranges a separate sacrificial activity, typically led by one person who reads the eulogy they have co-written, followed by a series of sacrificial rituals. This family sacrifice activity can sometimes take up to six or seven hours to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selection of Burial Site and Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In rural Hunan, it is common for the deceased to be buried in the family ancestral graveyard or on the family&amp;rsquo;s own mountainous land. However, the specific location and orientation are usually determined only after a local expert has assessed the feng shui (geomancy). The timing of the burial is also very auspicious, generally chosen according to the traditional Chinese calendar, in alignment with the deceased&amp;rsquo;s and the family members&amp;rsquo; birth dates based on the theories of Yin and Yang and the Eight Trigrams. Sometimes, if the timing is not convenient, I have even seen cases where the burial had to be delayed for over 30 days.&lt;br&gt;
Since the burials are all conducted on the mountains, the graves are still dug manually. In our hometown, the graves are usually excavated to a depth of 2.5 meters, with dimensions of 2.2 meters in length and 1 meter in width. For those who have never dug such a pit, it may take three people digging continuously for three days to complete it. However, there are also some professionals who can finish the job in just one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funeral Procession&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The funeral procession is similar to what I described in the first part. Currently, we still use the method of 16 people carrying the coffin. Along the way, spirit money is scattered, and firecrackers are set off. The descendants of the deceased, dressed in mourning attire, accompany the body to the burial site on the mountain. In addition to this, there are other procession members, including monks, Taoist priests, bands that have been hired to perform, dragon and lion dance troupes, as well as friends, relatives, and local villagers. This is known as a grand funeral in Chinese traditional culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Announcing the Death and Begging for Rice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This practice is now rare, but I personally experienced it once over a decade ago. At that time, communication was not very convenient, so it was customary for the children of the deceased to personally visit the homes of friends and relatives to announce the death by kneeling and kowtowing. Nowadays, this is mostly replaced by communication tools such as mobile phones or WeChat. The practice of begging for rice from a hundred households still occurs occasionally. It mainly refers to a situation where the time of death, according to the theories of Yin and Yang and the Eight Trigrams, is considered very unfavorable. In order to avoid negative occurrences, the deceased’s family goes to nearby households to beg for a small amount of rice from each, which is then cooked together into a pot of rice and consumed by the family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2048471261402053493075528.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1636&#34;
	height=&#34;920&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2048471261402053493075528_huee81bbe7807082ae7d2b84a3312d02f3_353211_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2048471261402053493075528_huee81bbe7807082ae7d2b84a3312d02f3_353211_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The burial is a long way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-my-personal-thoughts&#34;&gt;III. My Personal Thoughts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Funerals are solemn and serious events in any culture around the world, and this is especially true in China, with its 5000-year-old civilization. From the grandiose funerals of ancient emperors and modern national leaders to the modest ones held by every household for their departed loved ones, they are all treated with the same gravity. In traditional Chinese culture, weddings and funerals are considered the two most significant events in one&amp;rsquo;s life. Even though funerals are considered &amp;ldquo;sad events,&amp;rdquo; many still refer to them as &amp;ldquo;joyous occasions&amp;rdquo; alongside weddings, referring to them as &amp;ldquo;red and white joyous occasions.&amp;rdquo; The &amp;ldquo;red&amp;rdquo; refers to weddings, and the &amp;ldquo;white&amp;rdquo; to funerals, both considered joyous events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent decades, with the comprehensive advancement of Chinese modernization, the daily lives of most people have undergone drastic changes. In the fast-paced modern lifestyle, traditional funerals are often seen as outdated and superstitious. Some believe that funerals are entirely unnecessary, arguing that once a person dies, they know nothing more, and thus the practice of holding a funeral is futile. In urban high-rise apartments, for instance, when a family member passes away, they are immediately taken to the crematorium, the ashes placed in an urn, and then buried in a cemetery, all within just a couple of hours. Such a practice is considered unlucky if extended for even a second longer, and the idea of earth burial is even more opposed. As someone born and raised in a traditional Chinese rural area and who has worked and lived in cities, I also have a very contradictory mindset. Here, I will try to analyze the pros and cons and express my personal preference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2046566880512721931207683.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1636&#34;
	height=&#34;920&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2046566880512721931207683_hu2e3f36cea2a94c9b426ae0d4b03ce4bf_400409_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2046566880512721931207683_hu2e3f36cea2a94c9b426ae0d4b03ce4bf_400409_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burn the Stygian coin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A. Disadvantages of Traditional Earth Burial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-consuming and Labor-intensive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As mentioned earlier, traditional earth burials can take anywhere from four to twenty days, which is too long for modern society. Even in government or state-owned enterprises, employees can only take up to five days of leave for their immediate family members. If the funeral lasts longer, it will undoubtedly affect their work and income stability. In some private enterprises, taking leave for a funeral can result in the deduction of wages, and the randomness of the time of death can even lead to job loss.The earth burial ceremony is an extremely physically demanding activity, especially for the direct descendants of the deceased, such as sons and grandsons. The numerous kneeling and bowing rituals are particularly unpleasant, and sometimes, when accompanying monks in chanting scriptures, one has to kneel for several hours. For some older individuals, this can be quite a burden. It is not uncommon to hear about instances in rural areas where family members, due to the prolonged funeral rituals, have suffered sudden illnesses as a result of consecutive nights of intense efforts to cope with the ceremonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expensive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In my hometown, the average cost of a funeral is over 80,000 yuan, which is high considering the generally low income in mountainous regions. In 2019, my wife&amp;rsquo;s father&amp;rsquo;s funeral cost nearly 150,000 yuan, which is the average cost in her hometown. According to local government statistics, the per capita annual net income in our county was only 20,700 yuan in 2022, meaning that a funeral can consume a family&amp;rsquo;s income for over a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disturbing the peace.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In rural Hunan, two things are indispensable for a funeral: firecrackers and loud speakers or loudspeakers. The average funeral involves over 1,000 kilograms of firecrackers, with explosions every few minutes. Even on the funeral procession route, large fireworks are set off every few meters, causing significant noise pollution. Loud speakers or loudspeakers play dirges throughout the day, which also affects nearby residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some practices have a negative impact.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It is not uncommon to see some funerals incorporating inappropriate activities, such as striptease or love song performances, which are considered lowbrow or inappropriate and generally cause psychological resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obvious urban-rural differences.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In the process of urbanization, ordinary people in cities do not have their own land, and commercial cemeteries are only large enough for urns, making earth burial impossible. Additionally, the residential properties in cities are generally commercial, leaving no space for large-scale funeral arrangements as in rural areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2057097192002619408076662.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1336&#34;
	height=&#34;1200&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2057097192002619408076662_hu6b75a9da9af8478553b15c01fa6dc7d4_224355_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2057097192002619408076662_hu6b75a9da9af8478553b15c01fa6dc7d4_224355_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;111&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;267px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B. Advantages of Traditional Earth Burial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Final Review of the Deceased&amp;rsquo;s Life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Traditional funerals provide a systematic and comprehensive review and evaluation of the deceased&amp;rsquo;s life or the relationship with the deceased from different perspectives of the participants. This is solidified through eulogies and collective sacrificial rituals, which is known as &amp;ldquo;final judgment.&amp;rdquo; More than 2,000 years ago, Confucius said, &amp;ldquo;A person&amp;rsquo;s words are kind when they are about to die.&amp;rdquo; In Chinese culture, each person in the latter half of their life thinks about being as positive as possible and attaches great importance to their reputation after death, which is commonly referred to as the historical evaluation. Even if this history is limited to a small circle of friends and relatives, it is of great importance to the deceased&amp;rsquo;s family and descendants. A traditional funeral allows everyone to reflect on the deceased&amp;rsquo;s life, which is undoubtedly an invisible moral constraint for each living person, as death is inevitable for everyone. Of course, regardless of the deceased&amp;rsquo;s life, people will respect them and give them a final, objective, and positive evaluation, creating a harmonious and positive atmosphere and eliminating hatred and negative emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Physical and Mental Baptism.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I believe there is no other moment that can compare to a traditional funeral in making people reflect on the meaning of life and existence. Faced with one ritual after another, it is difficult not to deeply contemplate the true meaning of life. Reflecting on the experiences of kinship, love, and friendship with the deceased, one can consider if they have done anything wrong or right. It is also an opportunity to think about what needs to be improved or enhanced in the future. For instance, during my father&amp;rsquo;s funeral, I contemplated how to handle relationships with my children, even though I was not married at that time. Similarly, the names of my son and daughter were thought of during my grandfather&amp;rsquo;s funeral, even though they were not born yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Closer Family Ties.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced society, it is difficult to maintain close contact with relatives with blood ties, and gatherings like traditional funerals that last more than five days are unlikely to happen again in the future. For instance, relationships with cousins and other elders. As we share 1/2 of our genes with our cousins and siblings, these connections are significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obtaining Spiritual Comfort.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
There are many instances where children have not treated their parents well during their lifetime, especially in families with strained mother-in-law and daughter-in-law relationships. In Chinese culture, filial piety is paramount, and if children are not filial, they not only face criticism from others but also suffer from inner turmoil. However, it is not always easy to improve these relationships, as many people say, &amp;ldquo;Why do such complex funerals? If you treat them well while they are alive, that&amp;rsquo;s enough.&amp;rdquo; In fact, because filial piety is difficult to fulfill, many families cannot express their gratitude to their elders when they are alive. Therefore, they rely on a grand funeral to seek spiritual comfort. Although it may seem like hindsight, it is a common sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debts Cleared with Death.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In Chinese culture, it is believed that once a person is buried, their soul finds peace, regardless of the conflicts or hatred they had with others in life. Even if there is a tradition of &amp;ldquo;debts passed on to the children,&amp;rdquo; it is now limited to the inheritance of assets. Any debts beyond the inheritance are considered cleared. In traditional culture, this settlement often takes place during the funeral, often symbolized by a bow before the deceased&amp;rsquo;s portrait in front of everyone. After the deceased is buried, these matters are no longer mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_210430684995989784853900.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1536&#34;
	height=&#34;1036&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_210430684995989784853900_hu5ea9985f4052b77e8da8e24c472e50c7_328444_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_210430684995989784853900_hu5ea9985f4052b77e8da8e24c472e50c7_328444_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;148&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;355px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scene of the funeral&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, I believe that providing a decent funeral for the deceased is necessary, whether it is earth burial or cremation, traditional or modern. However, there are also a few suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The length of the funeral should not be too short or too long.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If it is only a short memorial service lasting a few minutes or tens of minutes, it might as well not be held, as it would not achieve any effect. However, in modern urban funeral homes, there is often a queue for memorial services, which objectively does not allow for a very long duration. Additionally, even traditional funerals should not be too long. The practice of extending for more than ten days is indeed divorced from reality and unnecessary. In fact, during my grandmother&amp;rsquo;s recent funeral, I once argued with professionals that it would be best to complete it within seven days. However, due to other special reasons, I eventually had to comply with their opinion and it lasted 13 days. I believe that in urban areas, if the main procedures of the funeral can be extended to one or one and a half days, it would be more appropriate. By adding some necessary ritual elements, we can create a more profound historical and cultural atmosphere, which is very meaningful for life and death education. Traditional rural funerals should be controlled to three to four days at most. If they are too long, there is no real significance. In fact, I have attended several funerals and there have always been some long &amp;ldquo;vacuum periods&amp;rdquo; that could easily be compressed to complete the funeral within the scheduled time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some unnecessary earth burial customs can be combined or simplified.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It is not to say that all traditional earth burial customs in rural areas are feudal superstitions, but there are indeed many meaningless rituals that can be simplified or combined. Some kneeling and bowing customs can be appropriately retained, but there is no need to kneel and kowtow to everyone. Some mythical and religious customs do not need to be carried out in every detail, and some practices that disturb the peace can be simplified or canceled. However, we should not be like the government of Nantong City, Jiangsu Province, which recently issued a document banning the burning of spirit money and sacrificial items across the city, citing the need to eliminate feudal superstition. This move has been widely criticized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show more tolerance and understanding for traditional customs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After the founding of the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China in 1949, a massive campaign against feudal superstition was launched nationwide. In an era when over 90% of the population was illiterate, with feudal superstition ubiquitous and the general populace being generally ignorant, such a movement was indeed necessary. However, after decades of reform and opening up, it is now difficult for people to truly believe in feudal superstition. Instead, there is a greater emphasis on the inheritance of some traditional customs and culture, which is adapted to showcase contemporary people&amp;rsquo;s thoughts and demeanor. It is unnecessary to completely eliminate them. I sincerely hope that the earth burial customs in Hunan can continue to be practiced in rural areas. Looking around, this custom has almost disappeared in all traditional Han areas across China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2102547023760605009745235.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1224&#34;
	height=&#34;1036&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2102547023760605009745235_hu1756e2825e494f074d63466efdc25e22_195241_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/the-chinese-earth-burial-i-know/images/img_20240331_2102547023760605009745235_hu1756e2825e494f074d63466efdc25e22_195241_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;118&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;283px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funerals are held at home&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What does being 35 years old actually mean?</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/IMG_20231024_220627.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What does being 35 years old actually mean?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is my wife CC&amp;rsquo;s 35th birthday, and in a few months, I will also turn 35. In recent years, the &amp;ldquo;phenomenon of being 35&amp;rdquo; has undoubtedly been a very popular topic in China. Taking this opportunity, I would like to briefly share my views on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first heard about the &amp;ldquo;phenomenon of being 35&amp;rdquo; around 2009. It was during the summer vacation of my college years when I stayed at my cousin&amp;rsquo;s house in Changsha, Hunan. He told me that he was preparing to apply for the Hunan Provincial Civil Service Exam. However, being born in 1980, he was already approaching 30 years old, and if he couldn&amp;rsquo;t pass the exam, he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have many opportunities to apply because the age limit for the civil service exam was 35 years old and below. I was quite surprised to hear about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cousin had always been a role model for me in terms of academics. Throughout his educational journey, he always excelled. He successfully enrolled at Xiangtan University in 2000 and earned a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Control Engineering from Wuhan University of Science and Technology in 2004. After graduating in 2007, he joined Sany Heavy Industry, which was the best private company in Hunan Province at that time and also one of the largest construction machinery manufacturing companies globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/R-C.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;840&#34;
	height=&#34;480&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/R-C_hu103ce4a308f06d585b251adf18c347c2_282248_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/R-C_hu103ce4a308f06d585b251adf18c347c2_282248_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;175&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;420px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sany machine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The income my cousin earned at Sany Heavy Industry astonished me. However, he told me that he would rather find a government position with a much lower income than continue working at the company. The reason was that the work pressure at the company was too high, and internal competition was extremely intense. If he couldn&amp;rsquo;t transition from a technical position to a managerial position before the age of 35, there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be many good career prospects for him. So, he preferred to take a government position as early as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During his application for the government exam, an absurd incident occurred. The online registration system required applicants to submit a personal photo, which had to be one inch in size and with a maximum file size of 30KB. This meant compressing the photo to the extreme, leading to frequent failures in photo submission. The photo would either become too blurry due to excessive compression or fail to meet the size requirements. It took many attempts before he finally succeeded in uploading an appropriate photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, my cousin successfully passed the professional technical recruitment exam organized by the Hunan Provincial Bureau of Quality and Technical Supervision in 2009. He was assigned to the Quality and Technical Supervision Bureau in Zhuzhou City. Later on, he also secured a permanent position in this unit and gradually grew into a senior engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/R-C28129-1024x768.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;768&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/R-C28129-1024x768_huf9ad96ae54c1042141e1416b3a922789_143222_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/R-C28129-1024x768_huf9ad96ae54c1042141e1416b3a922789_143222_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bureau of Quality and Technical Supervision&amp;rsquo;s Work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my cousin&amp;rsquo;s situation gave me a preliminary understanding of the &amp;ldquo;phenomenon of being 35,&amp;rdquo; the following case left a deep impression on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2014, after I started working, there has been a female colleague in the same office. She was born in 1985 but wasn&amp;rsquo;t good at exams, so she worked in our unit as a temporary employee. (Although she was considered a temporary employee, I have never seen any government department actively dismiss anyone unless they voluntarily resigned.) This female colleague, through arduous efforts, finally passed the civil service exam at the end of 2018 after years of trying. However, to reduce the difficulty, the job she obtained was located in a relatively remote area about 120 kilometers away from our place. By the time she passed the probationary period, she was almost 35 years old, as she had turned 34 when she became a civil servant. According to the government department&amp;rsquo;s internal transfer rules, which also have an age limit of 35 and below, she had almost no chance of returning to work in her hometown. Unless she gave up her civil servant status and resigned to seek another career, but this would be an unwise decision in China, especially for older women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth mentioning the rules regarding internal job transfers within Chinese government agencies. Before 2021, it was relatively easy for employees in my city to transfer to different positions. Any civil servant within the territory of China, as long as they were below the age of 35 and met the basic requirements in terms of terms of education and specialization for the desired position, theoretically had the opportunity to transfer. Since my city is located in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, with relatively high salaries and good working environments, many local residents who wanted to work in the government sector would usually choose to pass the civil service exam in a less competitive area, such as remote mountainous regions, and then transfer back to the major cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this indirect approach has become increasingly difficult to achieve since 2021, as the Organization Department of the Communist Party of China Central Committee issued new regulations that have largely closed this loophole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/Screenshot_20231024_224243-1024x906.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;906&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/Screenshot_20231024_224243-1024x906_hu33ee72f1102a42e1e6d87e485f06c89e_143514_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/Screenshot_20231024_224243-1024x906_hu33ee72f1102a42e1e6d87e485f06c89e_143514_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;113&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;271px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new regulations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the &amp;ldquo;phenomenon of being 35&amp;rdquo; has shifted from an internal government regulation to a misconception that has spread to the societal level, particularly in large IT and internet companies. Many people believe that they may face unemployment once they reach the age of 35. Of course, this may also be related to China&amp;rsquo;s demographic dividend. Some major corporations believe that individuals who have been with the company for a long time are more likely to become complacent and fail to keep up with market changes and technological advancements. On the other hand, young people who continuously flock to major cities in search of job opportunities are seen as more dynamic and driven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Middle-aged individuals often face challenges in the job market and find it difficult to secure new positions that match their previous jobs in terms of status and benefits. They often have to settle for lower-quality jobs to meet their basic living needs. Many of them experience a strong sense of crisis in their careers and fear unemployment. As a result, they become extremely competitive internally, extending their working hours without limits to demonstrate their loyalty to their work and the value they bring to the company. Even when faced with demanding requirements or tendencies towards abusive behavior from the company or management, they are willing to endure it, as the pressures of life and family force them to compromise their dignity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/OIP-C.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;474&#34;
	height=&#34;425&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/OIP-C_hu738cfe7530506a53db24e0133139b51c_48952_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/OIP-C_hu738cfe7530506a53db24e0133139b51c_48952_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;111&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;267px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;extremely competitive internally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, for the majority of society, the age of 35 is considered the golden age for work. People in this age group have matured mentally and have accumulated a great deal of work experience. They possess a strong sense of social responsibility and family responsibility. I also hope that our society can have less age discrimination, so that everyone has a fair opportunity for growth and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our generation has experienced tremendous social changes and carries immense social pressure. When I was a child, my family was very poor. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until 1998 that we bought our first black and white television. Throughout the 1990s, my parents&amp;rsquo; annual income was probably less than $300, and we lived in extreme poverty. This was the living situation for the majority of people in my hometown at that time. So personally, I care a lot about the certainty of life. I believe that maintaining a stable job is of utmost importance. The pressures of family and life leave me with limited choices to make mistakes, because one wrong step could lead to continuous and permanent losses for my family and myself. Even though the combined annual income of my wife and me is more than 200 times what my parents used to earn, I still worry about this issue. Of course, this way of thinking may also be a shared sentiment among many Chinese people, otherwise the civil service examination in China would not be so popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/IMG_20231024_214438-1024x767.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;767&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/IMG_20231024_214438-1024x767_hu3f795be08472a600710401ad5384cb8d_109014_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/IMG_20231024_214438-1024x767_hu3f795be08472a600710401ad5384cb8d_109014_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the topography and geomorphology of my hometown village.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often imagine what kind of life I would have if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t studied hard when I was young and didn&amp;rsquo;t get into university. Or if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t chosen to work in the court and instead continued to seek employment in society, what kind of job status would I be in now? Perhaps I would be running a small company like some of my cousins of the same age, working as a laborer in the manufacturing industry, or doing small business in Southeast Asia or even Africa. Maybe I would be like some of my classmates from college, already a successful lawyer or working as a legal or HR manager in a small or medium-sized enterprise. I might even continue to work in advertising companies or telecommunication enterprises in the field of marketing. But in the end, life has no &amp;ldquo;what ifs.&amp;rdquo; Since I have chosen the current career path, I can only resolutely continue on this path. This is also the helpless choice of our generation&amp;rsquo;s fate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/IMG_358320180418-194726-jpg-1.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1000&#34;
	height=&#34;739&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/IMG_358320180418-194726-jpg-1_hudc931503273cfa7a90e47d94a0e77893_185876_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/IMG_358320180418-194726-jpg-1_hudc931503273cfa7a90e47d94a0e77893_185876_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;135&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;324px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the lawyer&amp;rsquo;s certificate I obtained after passing the judicial examination in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/IMG_20231024_215621.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;720&#34;
	height=&#34;408&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/IMG_20231024_215621_hue8819d565f47e890fffaf29f6fc592d8_150770_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/what-does-being-35-years-old-actually-mean/images/IMG_20231024_215621_hue8819d565f47e890fffaf29f6fc592d8_150770_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;176&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;423px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the class photo of my middle school graduation in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How many holidays do I have each year?</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/how-many-holidays-do-i-have-each-year/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/how-many-holidays-do-i-have-each-year/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/how-many-holidays-do-i-have-each-year/images/E5889BE5AEA2E8B4B4E8AEBEE8AEA1_1695734327328_20230926.png" alt="Featured image of post How many holidays do I have each year?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In two days, we will soon have the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, which totals 8 days. Today, I heard in an internal meeting that government departments predict that this holiday will be much livelier than previous years, and the number of people traveling may increase by more than 20% compared to 2019 before the COVID-19 pandemic. So, I want to take this opportunity to assess how many holidays I currently have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    1.Annual Leave: 10 days&lt;br&gt;
    I have been working for over 12 years now, and according to the regulations, after working for 10 years, I am entitled to 10 days of annual leave, and after 20 years, it increases to 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    2.Home Leave: 5 days&lt;br&gt;
    Since my mother lives in the countryside, which is over 800 kilometers away from my current workplace, I can have a home leave every four years to visit her, and the duration is 20 days. On average, it&amp;rsquo;s five days per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   3. Care Leave: 5 days&lt;br&gt;
    As an only child, I have five days of care leave each year to take care of the elderly at home. If my parents are hospitalized, this leave can be extended to 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    4.Statutory Holidays: 11 days&lt;br&gt;
    Currently, China has 11 statutory holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    5.Weekends: 104 days off&lt;br&gt;
    Saturdays and Sundays make up 104 days off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, I have 135 days of leave, which accounts for 37% of the year, and the number of working days per year is 230.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-many-holidays-do-i-have-each-year/images/E5889BE5AEA2E8B4B4E8AEBEE8AEA1_1695734787511_20230926.png&#34;
	width=&#34;800&#34;
	height=&#34;800&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-many-holidays-do-i-have-each-year/images/E5889BE5AEA2E8B4B4E8AEBEE8AEA1_1695734787511_20230926_hu71bc5194777ae35364707a10416f7d22_475194_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-many-holidays-do-i-have-each-year/images/E5889BE5AEA2E8B4B4E8AEBEE8AEA1_1695734787511_20230926_hu71bc5194777ae35364707a10416f7d22_475194_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also other types of leave, such as maternity leave, marriage leave, childcare leave, bereavement leave, sick leave, personal leave, and so on, but currently, I am unable to enjoy most of these leaves. For example, parents are entitled to an additional ten days of childcare leave each year until their child turns three, but my child is already five years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that many of these leaves are only available to those working in government departments or state-owned enterprises. Employees in private or foreign-owned enterprises may have different vacation policies. Especially in some small private companies, it&amp;rsquo;s difficult for employees to have their leave effectively guaranteed. For instance, many small companies adopt a working pattern of 12 hours a day and six days a week. Apart from the eleven statutory holidays mandated by the government, it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to enjoy other personal leaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, as China is still the world&amp;rsquo;s largest developing country, there is still a significant gap in terms of workers&amp;rsquo; holiday protection compared to developed countries in Europe and America. However, this issue has gained widespread attention from the government and society, and I believe there should be significant improvements in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-many-holidays-do-i-have-each-year/images/E5889BE5AEA2E8B4B4E8AEBEE8AEA1_1695735353952_20230926-576x1024.png&#34;
	width=&#34;576&#34;
	height=&#34;1024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/how-many-holidays-do-i-have-each-year/images/_hu1432abcc5820e17d145998f153375571_496459_fc929d32a316e765165622ed149c476c.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/how-many-holidays-do-i-have-each-year/images/_hu1432abcc5820e17d145998f153375571_496459_70ab861e6ef1b771b9d7df7e9871cd14.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;56&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;135px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Visited two college classmates who are lawyers</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_220820.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Visited two college classmates who are lawyers" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much contact with many friends from out of town in recent years. Taking advantage of the weekend, I visited two college classmates who are lawyers in Shenzhen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204849-1024x767.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;767&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204849-1024x767_hu196bde671f564b6f8b6a444bc567a7eb_136394_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204849-1024x767_hu196bde671f564b6f8b6a444bc567a7eb_136394_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of lawyer&amp;rsquo;s office&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In China, graduates with a major in law have several main employment channels, including courts, procuratorates, administrative law enforcement agencies, and law firms. Among them, law firms are usually the most popular choice of employment because they do not require participation in the highly challenging civil service examination. In our class, out of 40 classmates, seven of them joined law firms after graduation. However, two of them later switched to government legal departments, and now there are five remaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_205050-767x1024.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;767&#34;
	height=&#34;1024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_205050-767x1024_hu8c88828db650cf97c213f9b3e56112fe_98327_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_205050-767x1024_hu8c88828db650cf97c213f9b3e56112fe_98327_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;74&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;179px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a lawyer is a rapidly growing profession that demands high individual capabilities. Of my two classmates who are lawyers in Shenzhen, one became a partner in a small law firm due to obtaining the lawyer&amp;rsquo;s practicing certificate early. Currently, the law firm has around ten lawyers. The other classmate joined a very large law firm, which was recognized as an excellent law firm nationwide in 2021. It has approximately 100 lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204939-702x1024.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;702&#34;
	height=&#34;1024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204939-702x1024_hub60023c9ac623c56f9e5ebbefe5a33fb_86549_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/visited-two-college-classmates-who-are-lawyers/images/IMG_20230924_204939-702x1024_hub60023c9ac623c56f9e5ebbefe5a33fb_86549_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;68&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;164px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a larger firm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the communication with my two classmates, I had three main thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the current year of 2023, the legal profession still generally relies on personal family background. If individuals have good social connections and a certain amount of capital accumulation, pursuing a career in law can be relatively smooth. However, if personal family conditions are difficult, it is very challenging to establish oneself as a lawyer in a major city. It requires several times more effort than others to have a chance of achieving some degree of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legal industry in China is undergoing a significant transformation. The traditional model where individual lawyers take on cases as independent agents (essentially being their own bosses) is being squeezed by the &amp;ldquo;salary system&amp;rdquo; employed by large law firms. In this model, lawyers work as employees of the law firm and receive relatively fixed compensation. Currently, the largest law firm in China has 15,000 lawyers, and even smaller law firms are actively expanding and moving towards corporate operation models. Most young lawyers work for senior lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legal profession in large cities has become highly competitive. For example, in the city of Shenzhen where these two classmates are located, there are already over 20,000 lawyers, with a ratio of 1 lawyer per 1,000 residents, similar to the situation in the UK. Due to the relatively low litigation costs in China, a large portion of civil litigation cases do not require the involvement of lawyers. In criminal cases, if the defendant cannot afford a lawyer, the government will provide a designated lawyer for free defense. This significantly suppresses the demand for legal services. As a result, the income of lawyers in China cannot be compared to countries like the UK and the US. With more people in the profession, the share of the income pie for each individual becomes smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Don&#39;t forget your original intention, regain simplicity</title>
        <link>https://hyruo.com/en/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hyruo.com/en/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/OIP-C-jpg-1.webp" alt="Featured image of post Don&#39;t forget your original intention, regain simplicity" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the summer when I was 14 years old, I saw a Lenovo mobile phone advertisement on the middle page advertisement of a &amp;ldquo;Reader&amp;rdquo;. At that time, Lenovo had not yet acquired the PC business of Big Blue, but it was already booming in China, with computers, mobile phones, printers, cameras, and many 3C fields having its presence. At the time, I didn’t remember much about the content of the advertisement, but the 999 yuan color-screen mobile phone left a deep impression on me, so I encouraged my mother, without telling my father, to use the mobile phone’s built-in electronic dictionary function, and successfully defrauded me of financial support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(The following content is nonsense, watch carefully)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was young, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the heights of the heavens and the depths of the earth. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how deep the sewage was in the mobile phone industry in a small county. With 1,500 yuan in cash (at that time, the tuition fee for a semester of high school was 1,500 yuan), I walked onto the chopping block of profiteers.&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/5-Lenove-G620C-300x300.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;300&#34;
	height=&#34;300&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/5-Lenove-G620C-300x300_hudb65aa0421e8b67d37056a9ef4cfcdb9_10742_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/5-Lenove-G620C-300x300_hudb65aa0421e8b67d37056a9ef4cfcdb9_10742_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, this mobile phone is the first real electronic device in my life. Before that, the tape machines and radios I had come into contact with were only played occasionally in the hands of older friends. Even in the second year of junior high school, in order to listen to the Korea-Japan World Cup in class, I cheated my parents 15 yuan in the name of buying an electronic alarm clock, and privately bought the simplest black FM radio. But these are unimportant. In the situation of scarcity of various resources in the big countryside, any novelty can inspire endless interests and hobbies. Internet cafes with dial-up Internet access, 10 yuan an hour Internet fee, make parents panic. And the first time I saw at my cousin&amp;rsquo;s house that it was no longer running the school&amp;rsquo;s MSDOS system, but could play extremely cheating games such as CS, and it left an indelible mark in my heart all year round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my first mobile phone, Lenovo&amp;rsquo;s G620C did not disappoint me. The only regret is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support java, so I can&amp;rsquo;t run QQ or something. Other 32-polyphonic ringtones, 1.5-inch 64k color flip screen, English-Chinese Chinese-English dictionary, etc., a bunch of functions that looked tall at the time really added a lot of fun to life.&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/eebbk162416830-jpg.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;360&#34;
	height=&#34;360&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/eebbk162416830-jpg_huff022731b92f507170aed3dd2dfa19b4_18016_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/eebbk162416830-jpg_huff022731b92f507170aed3dd2dfa19b4_18016_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, with the gradual understanding of electronic products, mobile phones are no longer the only source of fun. Especially in the era when functional machines dominated, a large-screen backgammon electronic dictionary that can run rpg games, a screenless patriot mp3 with a 64MB capacity that can store nearly 100 low-bit-rate wma songs, and an entry-level Aihua cassette player The happiness it brings is far better than that of mobile phones. Especially when PHS became popular in 2005 and 2006, under the crazy pressure of getting a PHS mobile phone for 100 yuan of phone bill, the mobile phone did not seem to be as important as it was later thought. Until after college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the start of university, TV shopping 999 bought Changhong Xiaozhiling. But after using it for one semester, at the beginning of the second semester, I lost it on the bus, so that I spent 120 yuan on the Internet in desperation, and bought a second (&amp;gt; 2) hands on Baidu Youah (which has closed down). BlackBerry 7290, this is the beginning of a new era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BlackBerry 7290 is an extremely classic product. The amazing side scroll wheel design, the clearer screen under sunlight, 16M large storage space, various available software, and the invincible full keyboard on the earth, make this old machine, which is several years behind Europe and the United States, come back to life in my mobile phone. After quickly falling into the quagmire of BlackBerry design, it has successively upgraded and replaced BlackBerry 8700, 7130, 8820, 8310, 8900, 9780 and other models, just like a BlackBerry lover. During this period, other brands of mobile phones also showed their splendor, but I always stick to the BlackBerry line and despise other brands. Since the BlackBerry 9700, the mobile phone platform competition has been rapidly accelerating, and the disadvantages of BlackBerry have also begun to be infinitely magnified, and the situation has been declining and leaking thousands of miles. The 9900, z10, etc. that were released later, after I have already started with Samsung galaxy note and galaxy s3, I already feel that I am not interested.&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/rimblackberry7290-1356315219-3-jpg.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;379&#34;
	height=&#34;548&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/rimblackberry7290-1356315219-3-jpg_hu786d450033e42a89c71a0561c3092ef5_27988_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/rimblackberry7290-1356315219-3-jpg_hu786d450033e42a89c71a0561c3092ef5_27988_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;69&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;165px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two Samsung mobile phones do not seem to bring a better experience now. It can only be said to be an ordinary Android phone, where the stuck place is unambiguous, and there is also a flaw in the font door. The cost of the hardware and maintenance of the two mobile phones before and after is over ten thousand. This cost is already very high for the Android system. Especially after domestic brands such as Xiaomi, Meizu, and vivo have shined, the cost performance of Samsung&amp;rsquo;s flagship phones is very low.&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/samsung-galaxy-note-featured-jpg.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;360&#34;
	height=&#34;240&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/samsung-galaxy-note-featured-jpg_hubc42836e22821000e67eb66f1943e1d7_10500_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/samsung-galaxy-note-featured-jpg_hubc42836e22821000e67eb66f1943e1d7_10500_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the Android platform is very open and various applications and functions emerge in an endless stream, after two years of experience, some deep-seated problems have been discovered. A summary of what I can&amp;rsquo;t bear is probably as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROM and power consumption issues. While smartphones are generally fast drainers, Android is the winner. The power consumption of the official ROM is slightly better controlled when there are fewer applications installed. This is why many mobile phones consume less power during evaluation, but the power consumption is very fast when they are actually used. The official ROM is not well-beautified and ugly. Without ROOT, a large number of system built-in junk applications and a large number of rogue apps are running in the background, resulting in a sharp increase in power consumption; the official ROM may be unstable after rooting, especially after flashing the Internet. In some modified versions of the system, the power consumption problem is difficult to control. Many modified ROMs on the Internet will claim to improve the power consumption problem, but in fact they have not solved it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROM as a whole is a very serious problem. A large number of third-party ROMs or modified official ROMs appear on the Internet, resulting in a substantial increase in built-in rogue software, backdoors and hacking programs. It is very important to find a safe and secure ROM. difficult. Although there are products like MIUI that seem more reliable, power consumption is also a very big problem when running on non-Xiaomi mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to fight against the background startup and permission tentacles of countless rogue software on Android, software such as autostarts or lbe optimization master was used to control it before, but the problem is that although these control software can better control the background application, they can be used in routine operations. Especially troublesome, from time to time you have to clean up memory and modify permissions. The control software itself is also very power-hungry. miui comes with an lbe control module, which is more convenient and simple, but there are still problems in supporting non-Xiaomi phones.&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/screenshot1.png&#34;
	width=&#34;320&#34;
	height=&#34;480&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/screenshot1_hu2bb6913743a293b897510d20a1ad6829_34242_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/screenshot1_hu2bb6913743a293b897510d20a1ad6829_34242_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;66&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;160px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brutal development of Android has led to the fact that there are almost only three roads for the development of mobile phones: the screen specifications are constantly increasing, the hardware parameters are constantly being refreshed, and the thickness of the body is constantly shrinking. None of these three have much guiding significance for me. False propaganda emerges endlessly, and all kinds of marketing that destroys the three views abound, but the product itself has no substantial development. CPU, screen, circuit, camera, the production of these main components, there are only a few companies on the market that can do it, so the components used in most mobile phones are almost the same, and the same system is used, the actual difference is only Unscrupulous marketing and after-sales behind the price and price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the components of an Android phone are highly standardized, it is not difficult to assemble a mobile phone, but few manufacturers on the market can really understand these components and the connections between them. Most manufacturers only pursue the products they want to make now. According to this demand, they can make a list of purchases, assembly and marketing. There is no unified and reasonable hardware development plan. The upstream suppliers can do whatever they can provide. As for the products provided by the upstream No one cares about how effective it can be and where future products will go. Of course, consumers don’t need to know what mobile phone manufacturers have done. Consumers only need to know whether the product is good or not, and the information they get is just a series of parameters listed by the manufacturer: the parameters are not very meaningful. . The same audio decoding chip, some companies feel that the effect is not good after using it on a mobile phone once, and then replace it with another one next time. In their eyes, only the latest and highest parameter chips can bring more gimmicks; and there are also companies that, after using this chip for the first time, gradually became familiar with the functions of this chip. After several years of continuous research and software optimization on this chip, they finally formed a set that can last for a long time The scheme used. This is the true portrayal of the entire industry at present. The former is a company other than Apple, and the latter is only Apple.&lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/pi15726-jpg.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;300&#34;
	height=&#34;378&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/pi15726-jpg_hu215c3b414dfcec99beb42d923d7a7331_10396_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/pi15726-jpg_hu215c3b414dfcec99beb42d923d7a7331_10396_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;79&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;190px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same hardware, in the hands of different manufacturers, has completely different effects. An obvious example is the 13-megapixel camera made by Sony. Most of the 13-megapixel cameras on the market use the Sony imx135 photoreceptor, but the photo effects of different mobile phones vary widely, and even Sony’s own photo effects are in the middle and low list, because the use of hardware requires algorithms Cooperating with software, excellent algorithms and software optimization cannot be reflected in hardware parameter lists and marketing advertisements. Consumers cannot feel these background virtual services before purchasing, which is not very useful for product sales. In order to save software and optimize costs, most manufacturers have led to mobile phones with exactly the same hardware parameters on the market, and the realization and effect of various functions vary greatly. &lt;img src=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/Sony-IMX135-stacked-image-sensor2-jpg.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;356&#34;
	height=&#34;353&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/Sony-IMX135-stacked-image-sensor2-jpg_hu625320025d9bf4b9297048e603418ab7_16018_480x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 480w, https://hyruo.com/article/dont-forget-your-original-intention-regain-simplicity/images/Sony-IMX135-stacked-image-sensor2-jpg_hu625320025d9bf4b9297048e603418ab7_16018_1024x0_resize_q75_h2_box_2.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;242px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, at the end of the day, there seems to be no other choice but Nokia and Apple. Since Nokia&amp;rsquo;s new flagship has obvious shortcomings in camera speed and software richness, only Apple can choose. This is indeed a joke. There are so many mobile phones of all kinds on the market, but in the end, I have no choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IOS system experience time is also very long, the earliest itouch started, and then ipad and iadmini, the overall impression is very good, the quality of hardware and software is very high, although there are many obvious deficiencies, but in the end, this is a For products that don’t bother, you don’t need to worry too much about system problems, power consumption problems, mobile phone hardware performance problems, software application problems, and various multimedia tool usage problems such as taking pictures and playing music. And the current model, after throwing away the low portability of the 5-inch and 6-inch large screens, is particularly valuable. In fact, in addition to viewing pictures and videos, even if the screen is large, the visual range of the eyes to read text is also limited. It is very narrow, and even when you only look at two or three lines at a time, you will pull down the screen. This is because the convenience of touching the screen with your fingers is much easier than floating up and down with your head and eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone is a simple but not mediocre product. The simple performance of the front desk represents countless optimization efforts in the background, so that the hardware parameters that are not outstanding have made the most excellent product. And this concept is also what I have been pursuing in recent years: no matter what, treatment cannot be given up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
